この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
U-Umm...
I don't play Go on the internet, but...
I have a friend that does.
He wants to play you, Master Touya, very badly.
His nick on the internet is...
Sai.
Fine.
It'll provide a nice distraction during the Jyudan match games.
Umm... please play seriously.
Fine. If I lose to that friend of yours, I will retire.
We will play in one week. The match will start at ten, with three hours time.
I thank you.
Fifty-fourth match
Excited Spirits
I don't see Touya Kouyou there.
He's probably busy with matches.
After all, he is Touya Meijin.
Are you sure that it really was Touya Kouyou on the net?
Yeah! He beat Ichiryuu! Ichiryuu from Japan!
It's well known that Ichiryuu is the pro player Ichiryuu.
If he did beat Ichiryuu, then he has to be Touya Meijin.
Things sure are getting exciting on the net.
Though Sai did disappear.
Sai...
I remember him.
Everyone was raising a fuss over Sai when I went to Japan two years ago as the US representative.
Though we never did find out who he was.
Oh, Frank!
You haven't been here in awhile.
Meneer Ooijer!
Yes, I was busy at work.
I felt empty inside, not being able to play against the number one player of the Netherlands.
Would you play a game against me?
Sure thing.
Oh yes, I saw Touya Kouyou.
Touya Meijin from Japan!? He's here in the Netherlands!?
On the net. 'Toya Koyo'.
Oh, on the net.
Are you sure he's the real thing?
I'm not sure.
The person he was playing wasn't very good, and Toya Koyo left immediately after that match.
Sounds like a fake.
A fake Sai appeared six months ago, though he stopped showing up right away.
Sai!?
Meneer Ooijer you don't know about him? He's a really good player who was on the net a while back.
As strong as Touya Meijin.
As strong as Touya Meijin? Who is Sai?
I don't know.
He claimed to be from JPN.
JPN...
So he's Japanese...
One of my goals when I went to Japan for the international amateur tournament
was to find out who Sai is.
Many people knew of Sai, but no one knew who Sai was,
and then he disappeared from the net.
Will he ever return?
Fourth Game of the Jyudan Match
This is the end. Ogata-kun fails to come back!
It's almost over.
The Meijin is too strong!
Ogata-san must be really angry, especially since he had the advantage for most of the game.
If he had won, it would have been the birth of Ogata Jyudan.
But Ogata-san has been doing well lately,
I wouldn't be surprised if he got a title soon.
I'm sure he feels the same way.
Even if he is competing against his Master, Touya Meijin.
Ogata-kun's interesting because you can see his anger easily.
He said that he'd be 'keeping the seat warm' for his master,
but he had all intentions of keeping the title of Jyudan.
But Touya Meijin is a hard obstacle to get past.
Speaking of which, didn't Master Touya just collapse last week? He seems much better now.
Isn't he still in hospital?
His wife was here with him, too.
Don't worry about it. A heart attack or to isn't going to kill you.
It's over.
Hmm... six and a half moku probably. Let's go to the discussion now.
This is where Ogata-kun lost the pace.
Touya-san's decision here was great. That's when he gained the advantage.
I didn't want white to come in from here.
I thought he would play a Tsugi here.
Yeah.
Is that the losing move?
Yup. There were no other mistakes though, it was a good game.
Or for Ogata-kun it's a pity.
Master Touya, how is your health?
Perfectly fine. I can play the fifth game right now if you'd like.
But aren't you still in hospital?
He's freeloading there because it's relaxing there!
Touya-san's messing around with Internet Go right now!
Internet Go?
I met a 'Toya Koyo' on the net the other day.
I didn't think it would actually be him.
I mean, who would think that Touya-san would play on the internet?
So I challenged him to a match thinking 'How dare
he use the name Touya Kouyou. Doesn't he know his place?' and...
Wow,
Ichiryuu Kisei and Touya Meijin played a match on the net!?
He took advantage of any little mistake I made.
'Oh, it is Touya-san! What's he doing here!?'
'Oh wait, he's playing Go with me.'
Just a little toy for me to occupy myself with until I leave the hospital.
I much prefer holding stones in my hand.
Oh, it's just for these few days?
Excuse me, I'll be leaving now.
Oh, Ogata-san, if you're going out to drink, I'll come with you!
Ogata-san!
He must be really angry.
It is getting late, Master.
I'm sure your wife is worried at the hotel.
You're right, let's stop here then.
The Jyudan match is now 2-2. The fate of the match rests on the last game.
You seem much better now, it might have been nice to stay here for a little longer.
There's no need to rush back to the hospital.
Sorry, I don't want to take the time to relax right now,
I need to prepare for my next game.
Your next game? The fifth game of the Jyudan match isn't until next week.
Hello.
Oh, playing Go again?
Aren't you tired from spending all of yesterday playing a match?
Maybe it's because he won yesterday. He doesn't seem very tired.
How nice.
But, you did collapse because of mental exhaustion due to playing too many games.
Why don't you rest for just today?
Or is internet Go mere fun and games for Touya-san?
Yes it is.
But there are games in it that I can't lose.
Concerning tomorrow, Doctor.
Could you turn away any visitors I have?
Touya-san?
I would like to play without intrusion.
Seems like you never have time to rest.
I feel sorry for you, ma'am.
Sorry, could you stop for a second?
I doubt there are many problems, but I should check.
You seem very well.
I won't tell a Go player not to play Go, but please think about your body.
Okay, he can leave the hospital the day after tomorrow, just as scheduled.
And I'll put up a no visitor tag tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
You don't have to come tomorrow either. Tell Akira so, too.
Akira has a study session with other young players tomorrow.
So I don't think he will come anyway.
Good.
This 'Toya Koyo' that I'm playing right now.
He's just as good as Touya Meijin from Japan.
He is probably Touya Meijin himself.
What quick and efficient moves.
He...
He's the real thing.
LL... that Li Lixin can't do anything against him.
Hello?
It's me! It's Ooijer!
Turn your computer on. 'Toya Koyo' is there!
I've been watching it! Since about half an hour ago.
He has to be the real Touya Kouyou!
Yes!
No, there's no doubt.
For his opponent, LL, to lose this badly...
Good morning.
Do you know LL?
He's the top amateur player from China.
He won the International amateur championship last year.
Yes.
Oh! He resigned!
Yes!
This is so exciting.
What's going on?
Yes!
I don't know.
Good bye then.
Master, what's going on?
Touya Kouyou from Japan is playing on the internet!
You guys know about him, right?
Touya Meijin!
Pros have been playing on the net with increasing frequency the past two years.
Now he's finally appeared!
It's so incredible!
I'd like to challenge him, too, but is someone like me allowed to?
Oh man, what will I do!?
The Meijin match from earlier.
The move that Touya's dad made here, it's paralyzing!
I wouldn't see a move like that!
They wrote about it in the paper, too. None of the pros watching the game saw it, either.
There are moves that only the one playing can see.
It is very different to be playing a game, and to be watching a game.
Those watching are calmer than the players, so they can't see as deeply.
Only those playing can see it...
The depth of the universe on the board...
The deepest depths...
And... you can't truly tell the strength of someone, until you play him.
Hikaru!
It's Akari-chan!
Really?
Yes.
What is it, Akari?
What about the Go club? Did you ditch it?
I didn't ditch it.
Everyone had other things to do today,
so I came to ask you to teach me, Hikaru.
Me!?
Are you busy?
Yes! Very busy!
We have an important match tomorrow, too.
Let's play her, Hikaru.
Sai?
I'll play.
I want to play!
Oh, really?
Hikaru, how dare you say that! Akari-chan came all this way...
Umm... ahh... fine, I'll play you.
Really!? Thanks!
I'll bring up some tea and cake later.
Thank you!
Were you studying Go? Sorry.
It's no big deal.
Have you gotten any stronger?
Yup!
Kaneko-san's taught me a lot.
Everyone else is working hard, too.
Though Mitani-kun doesn't come very regularly.
The tournament in June will be the last one for us,
so I was hoping Mitani-kun would come.
Can I place... nine stones?
Nine stones is nowhere near enough.
Place more.
Hikaru, nine is fine.
I'll make sure the game goes okay.
Oh, fine. Nine stones is fine. Just place nine.
Yup.
Are you really going to play her? It's Akari, Akari!
You're playing Touya's dad tomorrow, can you afford to be playing a stupid game like this?
There's nothing wrong with playing Akari-chan to calm my nerves.
Well, if you say so.
Good luck.
Good luck!
17-6
16-13
15-6
Hikaru was like her once.
It's already been two years since I came back to the world.
I learned of him immediately after I came back.
I knew that he would walk the same path as I, ever since I first met him.
The same path to master the divine move.
Next time, let us play an even match.
Yes, let us.
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow! My wish is granted!
How much closer can I get...
to the divine move!?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Right now Fuda Norimoto Meijin and Cho Ch'i-hun Ouza are
playing the 27th annual Igo Meijin Match.
Today I am doing the big board explanation
of the third match with Suzuki Isao 7-dan.
One thing that's different from the usual is
that everyone in the audience is from grade school and junior high school.
Other than the Meijin and Honinbou, there are titles like Kisei and Ouza, for a total of 17 titles.
Combined with the women's titles, there are a total of 22.
Getting a title is a major goal of any pro player.
I hope one of the kids watching today will one day become good enough to take a title.
To be continued...
I don't care if he has to retire or anything!
I get to watch this match today, from here!
I have no intentions of taking back my promise of retiring if I were to lose.
But in exchange, if I win...
I'll ask you to tell me who you are!