この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
I resign.
Hikaru has completely surpassed Waya with this match.
Sai...
We... talked about a good player on the net called Sai once, remember?
Yeah... I remember.
You played... as well as Sai today.
Shindou isn't...
You'll lose if you under estimate him!
Then, if I win the last match,
will you recognize me as your rival?
Ochi...
Shindou... I'm not going to lose today.
I've played against Touya every night.
Just to beat you.
Forty-fifth match
Hikaru vs Ochi
Touya...
You played Touya?
I've played him every day.
Why?
Touya trained me, far more zealously than he was obligated to.
Why would Touya...
Why would Touya play against you!?
Let go of me!
It's because I hire pros to come tutor me at home.
You said that you trained with Touya just to beat me!
What about it?
Why Touya!?
Why him?
There's no particular reason for it. I had a lot to learn from Touya.
Ochi!
He...
Did Touya...
Did he say anything...
say anything about me?
I resigned here.
It can't be! This is impossible! Two years ago!?
It was a total loss...
Don't underestimate Shindou!
Did he!?
He didn't say anything about you!
Get off your high horse!
We talked about the pro exam, too,
but he doesn't care about you at all.
He doesn't think anything of you.
Hikaru...
Besides, do you know how strong Touya really is?
He hasn't lost a match yet after becoming pro!
No losses to this day, since April!
I hate to admit it, but he's a level higher than us!
Why would someone like that care about you?
It's not that I... under estimate him.
But Touya's recognized my strength.
Touya says he's going to recognize me as a rival if I beat you in the pro exam.
If you beat me?
Yup, that's right.
Except it's not if I beat you, it's when I beat you.
Beat me?
Yeah.
If you... beat me...
What... do you mean by that?
N-No, it's just that...
If I win the rest... and stay at one loss...
That's what it means...
That's all.
Ochi is lying?
Touya is... actually...
Anyway, if I beat you today on the last match...
Touya will acknowledge me!
Then if I beat you, Touya's going to recognize me as a rival, right?
Is that right, Touya!?
Ochi!
What's with him?
I heard Shindou's voice too.
I wonder what they were arguing about.
What was that? A warmup match?
I wonder if Ochi's okay.
He's just really in the spirit. How strange, he's already passed.
Though, I expected as much.
I'm starting to think that Ochi's going to win.
Shindou's in a pinch!
Maybe he'll go into the playoffs with Waya!
Why are you talking about me?
Waya...
Sup.
Hey, how do you feel right now?
How do I feel? Normal.
Your opponent for the last round is Fuku, who you're weak against.
If you lose, you enter a playoff with Isumi-san, a powerful opponent.
Why you... you're enjoying this aren't you?
If Isumi-san were to lose today,
you and Shindou would pass automatically, but...
Judging from his opponent...
Yeah. I doubt Isumi-san will lose.
He'll be waiting for Shindou's and my results.
Well then, I guess I should stop worrying about others and play my own match.
And hope that my game will lead me to my future.
What kind of future?
Even if it does lead to the future...
Exactly what kind of a future is it?
What kind of future do we have?
It's finally time!
Yeah!
I will win!
Touya is behind Ochi.
Touya is looking at me through Ochi.
I have a feeling that he is.
Almost there...
I'm almost there, Touya!
I've almost caught up to you!
Shindou doesn't know how strong Touya is.
He wouldn't be calling Touya a rival so casually if he did.
The more I play him, the more I learn about how strong he is!
I played someone like that every day!
Just to beat you!
I won't lose!
Touya is standing behind me!
Is there anyone standing behind you, Shindou?
Today marks three months... 27 matches.
They all fought well.
Those who have become pro.
Those whose futures will be decided today.
And... those who can't become pro this time, but still have to keep playing.
All I can say is, I'd like you to keep playing with pride until the end.
These three months weren't a waste.
It is time.
Please begin!
Two years ago...
Sai appeared before me and...
Just like you started chasing after Sai,
I... started chasing you!
Stop fooling around!
T-Touya...
I won't forget the look on your face then.
Wait! Touya!
If you keep chasing after my illusion,
you'll get surpassed by the real me someday.
You?
Would you like to play now? Instead of just 'someday'?
Touya...
Touya!
If I win this match today, I'll become a pro!
I'm going to stand before you...
Touya...
Stand before you...
I see.
Ochi's game play is interesting.
I can tell that he's quite a good player just from the opening.
Touya is hiding behind this match.
It looks like this obstacle you've prepared for us won't be easy to surpass.
You're confident that you can survive on the top side?
Now is the perfect chance to disrupt his shape.
He should use a Nozoki here!
It's an even game.
Ochi maybe stronger, but...
Hikaru is playing well.
Hikaru, that is...
Not good enough, Shindou.
The weather isn't looking to good.
No, it was sunny this morning too.
Let's see... Your lunch, and my lunch.
These are it. Please take care of them.
Okay.
I hope it doesn't rain before we leave.
I'm sure a lot of them didn't bring umbrellas today.
It's time for lunch, so please halt your clocks.
I can win if I keep up like this.
Hikaru, you should eat lunch.
Yeah... I know.
Contemplating? You don't do that too often.
I guess it shows how desperate your situation is.
I guess Touya's training wasn't for nothing.
Ochi has complete control of the game now,
just because of that one bad move I made.
I'm clearly losing this game.
Damn it...
I won't let it end like this!
A little to eager, Shindou.
You think that's going to reduce my territory? Attacking that stone is going to be easy.
No.
That's not it.
He's not just reducing my territory.
He has another goal. There's another meaning behind it.
I've read through it!
Nozoki?
He played somewhere unexpected.
I see.
This is the result of your training, Touya.
Now Hikaru has to rebuild his plan from scratch.
Hong Su-Youn, a Korean Kenkyuusei is black.
Shindou Hikaru... is white.
This.. this white is Shindou?
That move that I thought was a bad move, was to prepare for the fight here.
If this is Shindou's strength right now...
Three weeks... isn't enough!
Don't under estimate Shindou!
I haven't underestimated him, Touya.
If Shindou reads a hundred moves ahead, I'll read a hundred and one.
If he reads a thousand moves ahead, I'll just read a thousand and one moves.
He's seen through my plan.
White will be at even more of a disadvantage if I don't play it right.
Is this the end?
I have to hang in there...
I can't let him get more of a lead!
Calm down.
Calm down!
I still... I still have a chance!
I can come back!
If I don't miss it.
I refuse to miss it.
No matter how small the chance is, any weakness at all.
Fighting back, Shindou?
He's fighting back... did Shindou get an advantage because I responded to that move of his?
Damn! Then...
I'm going to keep attacking until I crush you!
There!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
I have a problem for today. Everyone in the audience should think along.
There's something you can still do to white.
Where should Black play?
Try it, Yuuki-kun.
Here.
That's Atari, so I'll run.
Atari!
Here!
Thanks for the meal!
Try it, Mai-chan.
Here!
I'll capture it.
I can't get away from this.
Thanks for the meal.
Yup, that's right!
I want to try out more problems!
We will next time.
To be continued...
There are still two matches going on...
and what important matches they are.
If Shindou loses, we'll be tied at four losses and we'll have a playoff.
The game is completely even now.
Who is it!?