この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Touya...
Finally...
I'm finally here.
We're both pros, Touya. What do you think of me now?
Touya, I'm..
Finally...
What's up with him? He didn't have to ignore you.
Man, he pisses me off. Just because he's doing well...
I guess he's not just doing 'well'...
I won't just catch up to him...
I'll pass him.
That bastard...
Oh, these are the pairings for the Ooteai matches.
Shindou Hikaru... there it is.
My first opponent is...
Tou...ya...
My first opponent is... Touya!
Touya-kun isn't coming.
He called,
it's big news.
Touya Meijin collapsed,
and he's in an ambulance, on the way to the hospital, right now.
Fifty-third match
The Confession of Sai
Yes...
The man closest to the divine move...
Next time, let us play an even match.
Yes, let us.
Will I really get a chance to play him in an even match?
And, where's the hospital?
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Hikaru! Hikaru!
And... and...
He's all right, right?
Yeah. He's still at the hospital though.
Let's go! Let's go check up on him!
Yeah.
AISHINDOU HOSPITAL
This must be it.
Let's see...
Hurry up, Hikaru!
Where am I supposed to go?
Aren't we there? They told you to go here, right?
The Go institute told me that it was here, but...
It's here, right? Right?
Excuse me,
could you tell me where the inpatients are?
Where is he!?
What department is he in?
Department?
Sai, what department?
How am I supposed to know?
What is the name of the patient?
Touya Meijin! The Go player.
He was brought here three days ago.
I was scared to death when I heard that you were hospitalized because of a heart attack.
I'm glad that your alright.
I agree.
You've been working too hard, Master.
I apologize for worrying you, Hirose-san.
It's not just me. Everyone at the Go salon was worried.
The entire store was in a panic when your wife told us what happened.
This is a bigger issue than a Go salon panicking, Ichikawa-san.
Tension ran through the Go world that day.
It happened the day before the third game of the Jyudan match, right?
Mr. Ogata, what did you do as the challenger, when you heard that Master Touya collapsed?
All affiliates and I headed to Ehime, where the match was supposed to take place...
With the understanding that they would notify us of his condition.
We were worried about him, but still there was a chance that we would still play.
I waited for Master Touya in front of the board,
until his loss by default was decided on the next day.
I could have been there if it was closer, around Shizuoka...
I thought to myself, when I woke up and looked at the clock.
Master, please don't be so reckless with your health.
The fourth game is in five days.
Master, will you be all right?
Of course, though the doctors do not seem to approve.
Come in.
Hello.
Wow, what an incredible room.
Hi.
Shindou-kun!?
Shall we be going, Ichikawa-san?
Oh, I'm not staying long. I just came to see how Master Touya was doing...
I didn't expect you to come visit.
Well...
I can't tell them that Sai kept bugging me to come check up on him.
Mr. Ogata, there's no need to say that. He came all this way.
Oh, I'll go get something.
That's okay.
You're a pro as well, right?
Don't you remember?
I work the counter at the Go salon you played Akira-kun at.
Is this your first time here?
It's my first time at any Go salon.
Can anyone play?
Yup.  Write your name here.
Oh, there's another kid here. Can I play him?
Yeah, but he's...
You beat Akira-kun back then. It's no wonder that you became a pro.
I would like to have seen that match.
Akira-kun refuses to show it to me, and none of the customers remembers it clearly.
Neither Master Touya nor Mr. Ogata know about that match.
I played that match.
Yeah, we'd be in trouble if they knew about it.
Hikaru, hurry!
Umm... I heard that you collapsed from a heart attack at the Go Institute.
Umm...
I'm alright now.
Though they want me to stay here for another ten days or so.
Master, why don't you relax here for a month or so, instead of only ten days?
Yes. You can go to matches directly from here.
You can play as much Go as you'd like even here. Right, Master?
Ehh?
From here?
Using this.
I set it up yesterday, with permission from the head of the hospital.
A notebook?
If he learns how to play Go over the Internet, the master won't be bored.
I suggested it.
Oh wow, Master Touya is going to learn about computers?
Not at all, he only taught me how to play Go on it.
Oh, so even Master Touya is going to play Go over the internet now.
Maybe I should try it, too.
You're playing internet Go?
It wasn't hard to learn how to play Go on it.
Playing Go is what I do.
Internet Go...
Ichikawa-san, maybe we should get going soon?
Yeah, you're right.
I'll get going, too.
Master, shall I take these gifts to your house?
I drove.
Yes, please.
I'll help.
Oh, thanks.
Well, goodbye then.
If Ichikawa-san is going to Master Touya's house, I'll drive you back, Hirose-san.
Oh, thank you.
Seems like Shindou-kun plays Go on the internet, after all.
Internet Go?
He sounded interested, but what do you mean by 'after all'?
Hirose-san saw him at an internet cafe along time ago.
Oh yes, I remember.
I just saw him from outside.
He came to the Go salon afterwards and told us about it.
Akira-kun was there, too, and stormed out as soon as he found out where it was.
Yes, yes.
He certainly was running quickly.
First I've heard of it.
And did Akira-kun meet Shindou?
Who knows?
Akira-kun didn't say anything about it when he got back.
When did this happen?
It was summer two years ago...
Akira-kun was in the store during the day, so it had to be during summer vacation.
Oh yes, it was around the end of summer vacation two years ago.
Summer two years ago... Internet Go...
That's around the time when Akira-kun played Sai.
Akira-kun stormed out of the store when he learned that Shindou was playing at an internet cafe...
Did he think that Shindou was Sai?
Or did he think there was some connection between Sai and Shindou?
Thank you for coming. Please, sit.
Didn't I collapse on the day you were supposed to play Akira?
Sorry for getting in the way.
Not at all.
I'm sure Akira didn't go to the match because he didn't think he could play calmly.
I probably worried him quite a bit.
You play Go on the internet?
I probably wouldn't have had to learn it if I weren't in here.
I just started yesterday, but I played Akira this morning.
It's great that I can play even while I'm in the hospital,
but I miss the feel of the Go stones.
It's not for me.
It's just a stopgap while I'm here.
It's only while you're here?
Yes.
Umm...
I don't play Go on the internet, but I have a friend who does.
He wants to play you, Master Touya, very badly.
His nick on the internet is...
Sai.
His name is Sai!
Hikaru...
I know.
Ogata-kun showed me the match Akira played against Sai.
There's no way for black to live in the center...
He's a friend of yours?
Yes...
Hikaru.
Please don't tell anyone!
About Sai and I...
Sai has... he has always wanted to play you, Master Touya.
But he only plays Go on the internet, so...
Why?
Why is he hiding behind the internet?
What is his name?
His name...
You don't plan on telling me his name?
He's not a pro, is he?
He's a friend.
It's common for a good player to wish that he could play a pro.
But it displeases me that he wants to keep his identity a secret.
Bring him here. I'll play him any time.
But not on the internet.
I messed up... sorry, Sai.
I'm right here!
Get us a board and stones!
I am right here!
Sai...
You've seen the match Sai played against Touya, right?
You know how strong Sai is, right?
He is very strong.
But Akira lost that game because he could not read deeply enough.
I would have won.
But I won't know exactly how strong he is until I play him myself.
Then play him!
Even if its just once, please!
On the internet...
I mean... he...
He can only play on the internet...
Fine.
It will provide a nice distraction during the Jyudan match games.
Sai...
The Sai that everyone was excited over on the internet two years ago...
Is something the matter?
Yes. Something about someone really strong being on the internet.
Strong?
His nick is Sai.
His Tesuji and stuff...
I thought he played like Shuusaku, back then.
Shuusaku?
Honinbou Shuusaku!?
I replay Shuusaku's matches all the time, and I thought they were similar.
He seemed that strong.
And I watched him play a few more times after that.
He became stronger with every game. His game is changing.
As if... Shuusaku learned modern Joseki.
It is true that I thought of Shindou, when I heard that he might be a child.
But...
The game that Shindou played during the Wakajishisen, wasn't one of Sai's games.
Shindou is not Sai.
Then who is Sai?
A fake one showed up quite a while ago, but he quickly disappeared.
The real Sai is still missing.
I'm not interested in anyone who refuses to reveal himself, but...
Where is he right now? Is he no longer on the net?
A distraction, you say?
Sai, it is a chance to play.
Thank you very much.
But please keep it a secret that I know Sai.
I won't tell others about it.
But, no matter what his circumstances are for hiding his identity...
It doesn't change the fact that he's of a suspicious lot.
I only accepted the match because you're so intent on it.
When would you like to play?
Whenever.
Whenever you can play, Master.
What about tomorrow?
Please wait until I get used to this.
Using this is quite different from holding the stones.
Then, next week?
Yes. The fourth game of the Jyudan Match is next Thursday.
I'll rest for a day after that. What about the following Saturday?
It won't affect my important fifth game of the Jyudan Match, either.
I didn't...
I didn't wish for a nonchalant game like this.
Sai...
Umm... please play seriously.
Of course.
I wouldn't want you to say that you weren't playing seriously, when you lose, Master.
I? Lose?
IF! If!
If...
I won't lose.
I don't mind quitting the pros if I lose.
You've got to be kidding!
Please don't, everyone in the Go world would be shocked if you did.
You seem to seriously think...
that I might lose.
Not at all... I...
Fine. If I lose to that friend of yours, I will retire.
Retire...
I never asked you to do that!
We will play in one week.
The match will start at ten, with three hours time.
I will refuse any visitors on that day.
How does that sound?
Master! I wasn't...
I said that I will play the match you want me to.
Now be quiet, you're in a hospital.
Master...
Hikaru!
Sai...
I thank you.
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Today, we will continue the problem from last week.
Have you figured out the answer to the problem?
The correct answer is B, here.
Even if white makes an eye here,
you can play here.
White will capture three stones,
but you can play a snap-back.
Even if white comes here,
black can connect.
This becomes a deficient eye, so white only has this one eye now.
In this case white dies.
If you were able to solve this problem without a hint,
you're probably a higher-kyu player.
To be continued...
Turn your computer on.
Touya Kouyou is playing!
I've been watching! Since about half an hour ago!
This is the real Touya Kouyou!
What flawless and efficient play.
Only the one playing can see these possibilities.