Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Shindou!
I'll make you wait... until I catch up with you.
There's no reason for you to fear me.
I should be the one fearing you.
Shindou Hikaru... if that's what you intend to do... I will...
Eighth match
The Scheme in the Rain
Igo made Fun
Key to Solving Tsumego 3
Key to Solving Tsumego 2
Key to Solving Tsumego 1
Entrance into Knowledge of Go
Collection of Tsumego Chosen by Touya Meijin
A Hundred Selected Tsumego
Learning Joseki: A Hundred Tesuji
Starting Go
Tesuji from Real Matches
New Opening Methods
Immediately Useful Joseki
Igo Cultural Magazine
The World of Igo
Igo Encyclopedia Second Volume
Silver Matches of Go
Oh, there it is. Is this it?
Yes Hikaru, that's it.
Welcome.
This... and this.
That will be 1630 yen.
You wanted this right?
But Kaga ripped it up last time.
I'm sure you'll be able to understand it too now, Hikaru.
Why don't you buy Akari-chan some beginners books as well?
Beginners books for Akari? That's a waste.
Why?
She can't even tell the difference between Go and Othello.
Othello? What's that?
It's just another game.
Oh man, it's getting dark. If I don't get home soon I'll get in trouble.
I wonder what time it is. Is there a clock somewhere?
Oh there's one, oh no! It's this late already!?
Huh?
Touya Meijin wins Jyudan Title, now holds 4 titles...
It was explained earlier that Meijin is a title, Jyudan is yet another title. There are a total of 8 titles. Meijin, Kisei, Honinbou, Jyudan, Gosei, Tengen, Ouza, and NHK World Tournament Qualifier.
Oh wow, Touya's dad took another title.
He has risen higher... and higher...
I wonder what Touya's doing...
Private Kaiou
Jr. High School
That guy's replaying games alone.
I guess it's a waste of his time to play against us.
After all he is the son of Touya Meijin, the holder of 4 titles.
Yeah, I saw on the news... 4 titles...
It's hard enough to get one, but to have four!
He's a being higher than the clouds to us.
Yeah, and he's his son.
Future Meijin I hear.
Hey, why don't you ask for a game?
No way!
Touya-kun, congratulations about your father.
Didn't he win the Jyudan match?
It's his fourth title isn't it?
Oh yes, thank you very much.
Oh? What an uncaring son.
I want to fight you!
I'm in this club simply for that reason.
How much do I have to improve before the next time we play?
Shindou Hikaru... The hand of god that I aim for is on the other side of the obstacle that is you.
I've totally lost. I resign.
What's going on? You're in the zone today.
Wanna play another game?
Nah.
Thanks for the game.
Can I ask you for a game?
Aoki...
Yes. Please.
Good luck.
Aoki-san...
Aoki-senpai is...
Sorry, I'm a freshman, and still don't know all the senpais...
Who is he? Is he strong?
Aoki-senpai from the 3rd year. He's the third strongest after the president and vice president.
To make it short, he's the guy that might not get to go on team tournaments thanks to Touya.
Three people per team.
He's a very kind and caring person.
He went to take care of it on his own... just like Aoki.
If he plays and loses then no one can complain...
He hasn't lost yet!
I resign.
That quickly!?
I learned a lot.
Thanks for the game.
That damned Touya...
What is it with this atmosphere?
This is the Kaiou Go club I looked up to?
Look at what Touya's done to it.
The entire Kaiou Go club can't do anything? How pitiful.
It's your turn.
Wait... oh yeah!
I just had an idea...
I'll play against Touya.
I can't win, but I can't lose... just watch.
Touya, wanna play a game?
Sure.
Who is it?
Freshman?
Could he be someone really strong?
How many stones do you want?
I don't need any handicap, so long as you let me play first.
Go ahead.
Then, good luck.
Good luck.
Oh he's just an idiot.
No hope, he's an idiot.
He'll lose in an instant.
Does he even know how to play?
Tengen on the first move?
Tengen is the center spot on the Go Board. Each of the 9 marks on the board are "Stars", but the one on the center is also called "Tengen", and its literal meaning is "Source of the Sky". There is also a title called "Tengen".
So long as I control the tengen, then it's my game.
What?
I guess you noticed.
But it doesn't matter. So long as I control the tengen, I can just repeat your moves.
Your strength is reflected right back at you!
Touya paused!
If that's the way you want to play it.
He did tsuke on the tengen!
Don't hesitate, just repeat his move.
H-Huh.
It's your turn!
I-I resign...
It was like magic...
Idiot, even I can crush someone who's simply repeating my moves.
Don't pick on him so much.
You can count on a damezumari by playing around the tengen, or you could use ladders to trap him.
Damezumari was explained in a previous episode, it's when excess breaths of air are removed and new possibilities form because of it. Ladders, called Shichou in Japanese are an important formation. It was shown and explained in Episode 2 when Hikaru was at the Go Class.
Either way, you get crushed.
Wait for me!
Don't do anything too stupid, new guy.
'Cause you'll embarrass the Kaiou Go club.
Then why don't you guys try defeating Touya?
This next tournament, is Touya going to be the captain?
Why not? I hear he's going to become a Meijin in the future.
Are you telling me to get his autograph now while I still can?
I don't know about an autograph, but I should play a game against him.
If he does become Meijin in the future, I'd be able to brag about it.
Claim that "I played the Meijin once."
You're aiming too low there.
Akira-kun!
Ichikawa-san, what's going on?
Hehe...
I came to pick you up!
All this way? You didn't have to.
What are you talking about? Get in.
Look you're getting wet.
You did say that you were going to tutor me in Go today.
I haven't forgotten.
I'll serve you coffee and cake.
Serve you... cake... and coffee?
I can't stand it anymore!
Well I do want to humble him at least once...
Senpai...
I feel the same way but... beating him without a handicap?
Seems easier to become valedictorian of the class...
I know... but isn't there anything we can do?
You can't do it under any NORMAL circumstances... but...
What are you plotting?
A way to win against Touya Akira.
Is there? There is, isn't there Senpai?
Public Haze Jr. High School
It's really raining hard now.
Let's go home Tsutsui-san.
Fujisaki-san didn't come today.
Doesn't matter whether Akari comes or not.
It's all because you yelled at her the other day.
Something like that won't discourage her at all. I know these things, we're neighbors.
Why don't you ask her to come?
No way! Besides, it doesn't make any sense for a girl to play Go!
What are you talking about Hikaru.
Even in the capital of the Heian period, many women played Go.
Everyone, look, Master Sai is here.
Sheishou Naban-dono and Murasaki Shikinu-dono played Go as well.
Historical figures from Japan
Didn't you learn about it the other day?
Did I?
Sai...
Yes?
Isn't it cool?
Just kidding,
Oh...
I've seen it many times already.
The first time you saw it, you made such a fuss.
Did you say something?
No, nothing.
Then Shindou-kun, see you tomorrow.
Yeah, see you tomorrow.
Hamburger Shop
Food Place
From the ancient times... Go and Go stones haven't changed but...
Hikaru, this umbrella hasn't changed either in the last thousand years.
Yeah... it hasn't changed at all...
It can't block all the rain... and your feet get wet...
and it's inconvenient holding it in your hand...
Yes...
In the age where man has gone to the moon, we're still using umbrellas!
Man on the moon?
Making stuff up again Hikaru? There's no way men can go to the moon.
But we can. Man's already walking on the moon.
You're lying Hikaru. You're lying right?
It's the moon! The moon! Going to a place like that!
Stop kidding around. Even I know that it's impossible...
Hikaru...
Have we really gone to the moon?
That moon in the sky?
Yes really! That moon!
If we can go to the moon, then why are umbrellas still umbrellas?
Doesn't matter what the situation is. If we can beat Touya in an even match, we'll be able to humiliate him.
Yeah but...
Of course.
We just don't need to tell anyone what situation it was in...
What if we demand a match when he's got a 40 degree fever!
He wouldn't come to school on a day like that.
What if we play him in a karaoke room? Make a lot of noise around him so that he can't concentrate.
That's not enough to beat him. We have to get more of a handicap.
Why don't we tie his arms and legs behind his back and make him play?
That's good...
Here.
Anyways... no matter what we do... we'll win against Touya Akira...
We'll shatter his pride...
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Let's see who has the larger territory.
Black counts White's territory, White counts Black's territory.
Rearrange the pieces to make it easier to count.
How many do you have?
1..2..3..4..5..6!
It's 6 versus 6.
But Black has one prisoner.
We use it to fill White's territory. White's territory becomes 5.
In Go, we call territory moku, or "points".
White has 5 points, and Black has 6 points.
6 minus 5 equals?
One!
Black wins by one point.
Now let's play Go!
Okay.
Onegaishimasu!
To be continued
You're telling me to play blind folded?
You can do it right?
You are the future Meijin after all.
If I'm the best...
You're saying I should be able to play blind Go easily?
Please make your first move.
Touya's going to lose without holding out even 5 minutes...