この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
But anyways, pros have to play games, right!? Games!
When do I get to play Touya!?
Do you know, Waya?
Of course not!
But I am connected!
To Touya, and to Touya's dad.
We're in the same world already!
I'll be playing them someday!
Yes...
I'm not the one that's connected...
Hikaru...
It's just Hikaru.
Ochi Kouske (13)
Shindou Hikaru (14)
Waya Yoshitaka (15)
That boy passed...
I see, his name is Shindou.
He may be apart of the new wave that Ogata was speaking of.
Did you hear that, Sai!?
I'm going to be playing Touya Meijin!
Remember the new first dan series!?
Let me...
Let me play, please!
Forty-seventh match
Sai vs Meijin
S... Sai?
Let me...
Please let me play, Hikaru!
You've got to be kidding?
Touya's going to be watching.
It won't be just Touya either, Waya and Ochi will be there.
And it will be on Weekly Go, too!
And... there is a reverse komi of 5.5 in the new first dan series.
The new first dan is at an advantage.
You're going to win for sure if I let you play it.
I know how strong you are.
I'm... going to be hidden in your shadow again!
Then hide in it!
Don't be so selfish!
You think it won't matter to me!?
Then, when exactly are you going to let me play!?
What's wrong, Sai? You said so yourself...
That you have an Infinite amount of time...
So you're not in a hurry...
That even if I died, you'd just wait for the next person to possess.
Isn't that right?
Right?
I... think so...
See!? If I'm the second, then there is going to be a third and a fourth!
You don't understand, Hikaru!
I've been worried lately...
About how long I can remain in the present.
Oh, you're just worrying about nothing.
Anyways, I'm tired of getting in trouble every time I let you play.
Ask the third guy you possess to let you play.
Hikaru!
Is Hikaru...
Not going to let me play anymore?
Today's Events
Public Match Room
2nd Floor
Mid-Kyu Class
New First Dan Series
5th Floor
Master Kuwabara.
My, my, if it isn't Ogata. It has been awhile.
We haven't met face to face since the Honinbou Match, right?
Wasn't that seven game match fun?
I learned a lot during that match.
I hear you've been doing well lately.
Didn't you completely defeat Kurata-kun just the other day?
And you, master, seem to be doing poorly as of late.
I'm too old, I don't want much.
Though I won't give the title of Honinbou to anyone.
And, why is Kuwabara Honinbou here?
Try these, Ogata-kun, instead of sucking on that candy of yours.
No thanks.
Why am I here, you ask?
I'll turn that question right back to you.
It's only a new first dan playing today.
Even if the Meijin is playing, it's not something that someone like you would come watch.
Which means that this boy is part of the new wave that is coming to the Go world.
You know Shindou?
You saw him play somewhere?
I see, I was right!
I knew he was exceptional when I saw him. My sixth sense is still sharp.
Sixth sense?
The sixth sense.
I merely passed by Shindou once before.
You just passed him by?
Ridiculous.
Shindou is going first, and Ochi you're playing next week. That's great.
Waya, have they notified you yet?
Not yet.
Oh man, I want to play already.
O-Ogata 9-dan and Kuwabara Honinbou!?
H-Hello.
Hey, let's sit over here.
Hey, why are two top pros here to watch a new first dan match?
Probably because they are interested in Shindou.
Ogata-san was watching Shindou during the Wakajishisen, too.
He even invited Shindou to the Meijin's study sessions!
To the Meijin's study sessions!?
Though, he did refuse the invitation.
He was on his way to my master's study session.
I don't know about Master Kuwabara though.
I wonder if Master Kuwabara has his eye on Shindou, too.
Hey.
Ogata-san... and Master Kuwabara?
He's here after all.
Good afternoon.
Ochi-kun, good afternoon.
Huh? You know Touya?
You're the Meijin's son, right?
Yes. Nice to meet you, I'm Touya Akira.
You're someone else that's interested in Shindou?
I-I...
I see, I see. Then the Meijin must be, too.
Even the Meijin, who has five titles, is interested in that boy. How interesting.
Master Kuwabara...
Just who is Shindou?
He passed with us, he's our rival... and our friend.
Okay, say cheese.
Akira is here to watch today.
I knew that Akira was concerned about you.
But, Akira wasn't the only one, Ogata-kun and I felt the same way.
I requested to play you for this match today.
Show me your strength.
Okay.
Room of Deep Contemplation... I'm going to be playing in this room, that Waya and I looked at last year.
Sai!?
Sai...
Shindou-kun?
Sai! Get off!
Say... Ogata-kun.
This match...
Want to bet on who wins?
Bet? Interesting...
Wouldn't it be?
Bet!?
There is a reverse Komi of 5.5.
But it will still be difficult against Touya Kouyou.
I agree.
But not if the Meijin lets the boy win.
He wouldn't do that.
No, that man wouldn't do it.
And? Who are you going to bet on?
The boy!
Going against the odds?
Not at all. I don't intend to lose.
I don't. Or what is it? Did you want to bet on the boy, too?
Having studied under the Meijin, I have faith that he will win.
Just who is Shindou?
He passed with us... he's our rival... and our friend.
Shindou!
Shindou is going to play my father under the scrutiny of Ogata-san and Master Kuwabara.
He has finally come this far.
I've been waiting.. for this.
What kind of game is he going to play?
What kind of game is he going to show me?
You.
Sit down.
Sai...
What's wrong, Shindou-kun?
Sorry, Hikaru... I just wanted to sit here for a moment.
Sai...
Shindou-kun.
Idiot. You didn't need to sulk now.
I'm about to play a game.
I understand how you feel, but...
Well...
But...
There aren't going to be many chances like this.
No! No! If I let Sai play with the advantage of a 5.5 reverse komi...
He's going to win for sure.
And I'll become the center of attention...
Wait...
But...
A handicap...
He'll play differently with a handicap...
Touya Meijin is giving a handicap of the first move and 5.5 moku.
If Sai were to take on more than that... like...
If Sai were to play with a handicap of 15 moku, he wouldn't be able to play normally...
Then they might not find out about Sai's strength.
I'll do it!
I'll pretend that there's a 15 moku gap to begin with!
Sai!
Do you really get it?
Even if you do have the first move, you're going to play a lot of unreasonable moves,
If there's a 15 moku gap on the board.
You're going to play against Touya's dad!
He'll crush you, and that'll be the end of it.
Do you really want to play a game like that?
It is time.
The new first dan will play first. Komi is a reverse komi of 5.5 moku.
You have two hours each.
After you use all of your time you will have one minute per move.
Sai...
Then, please begin.
Good luck.
Okay. If you're okay with that...
Good luck!
What kind of a game are you going to play, Sai?
It has been twenty minutes since the game started.
It has started... right?
He's really into it.
Into it, you say?
If he isn't, then what is it? Do you think he's nervous to pick up the stones?
I wonder what Shindou is thinking.
He knew who his opponent was.
One would usually decide his first move ahead of time.
They only have two hours each for this match.
It's ridiculous to use twenty minutes of it here.
No. I'd never use it.
Never.
He's planning something out.
He is exceptional, after all.
Shindou...
Shindou-kun..
To win by more than 15 moku...
I know how impossible that is.
My opponent isn't merely someone from a Go salon.
He is probably someone who would fight me to the last half moku in a real match.
Yes...
The atmosphere before the board is the same as last time.
No matter what the circumstances are, you're finally...
going to respond to each of my moves.
To head for a win of more than 15 moku...
I'll have to start a fight where one of us dies...
Either he will get wiped out, or I will.
How far will I be able to go?
Upper right corner, hoshi!
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
We're going to be looking at the final tournament for the Go Go Igo cup this week.
I can go home happy now.
Playing with my child, I really thought pair-go is great.
I'm really happy that we won. Thank you very much.
Congratulations.
Everyone was playing so intently.
There were lots of different pairs, and I really enjoyed watching them.
Wasn't it fun!?
I can't win unless I start a fight early on.
What is Shindou-kun thinking!?
The fight that started in a corner... has spread across the board.
This match looks poorly played, but there is a lot behind it.