胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
wth my wings spread out.
A hundred forty years ago...
Torajirou lent his body to me
If Torajirou existed for my sake...
Then I existed for Hikaru's sake
Then...
Hikaru exists for someone else as well
And that someone will, too...
Be there for another person
A millennium
Becomes two
Built up slowly person by person
The long path leading to the divine move...
My part in it... Is over...
The Sixty-First Match:
Sai Is Gone?
Sai?
Hey!
Why are you hiding?
We're playing because you wanted to
Man, you're pissing me off
Sai!
Fine then!
I'm going to bed!
Hey! Cut it out already!
What are you doing?
That's strange...
You just got back
why are you acting so strange?
Did I leave it at the hotel?
No, that's impossible
Hhuhh
No
It can't be We were playing Go until just now
Hey, What's wrong?
The window was open...
Maybe he got carried off by the wind?
I'm going out for a bit
W-Wait, where are you going?
Where?
I wonder where...
The Go institute maybe?
You wonder?
Maybe he went somewhere fun after getting carried off by the wind
But... It's never happened before in the two years we've been together
He's not here
Sai!?
Sai!
Are you here?
So he's not here
Where the hell did you go?
Why did you disappear all of a sudden?
Maybe...
What is it Hikaru?
Going into the shed all of a sudden?
Nothing?
Did you forget something here?
The stain...
It's gone...
Why!?
What's going on!?
We were playing Go together
In my room!
That was it... We do that all the time...
Oh yeah...
The stain had faded a little the last time we were here...
He said back then that he was going to disappear soon!
What did he mean by that?
He couldn't...
He couldn't have... Really disappeared?
That's impossible!
He wouldn't disappear without saying a word to me!
Sai and I were always together!
Hikaru, what are you up to?
A ghost's going to haunt you if you stay in there to long
I want one to haunt me!
Huh?
Grandpa?
What do you think makes ghosts disappear?
What? Are you talking about making peace with their life?
That's when they've accomplished everything they want to
Yeah!
Hey! Hikaru!
Going home already!
He hasn't mastered the divine move!
He would still want to stay in this world for millennium after millennium
It has to be my room!
He has to be hiding somewhere in my room!
He was in my room just this morning!
I'm home
Sai!
Sai...
He just went somewhere!
It's never happened before
But he must have figured out how to go off on his own!
He was in a bad mood lately, too
He probably flew off somewhere for a change of pace...
Did he...
Know how to fly?
He must have learned how to!
He just went somewhere for fun!
Man, where did he go?
Hello?
Oh, Hikaru?
What's wrong with you?
Why did you go home?
You came all the way, you should have played a game!
Huh? What?
What kind of places do ghosts like?
How am I supposed to know!?
Come on, tell me!
Why do you want to know?
Like his own grave?
Or places he has fond memories of?
He doesn't have a grave... Does he?
A place he has fond memories of...
Okay, I think I figured it out
thanks a lot
Oh, hey! Hikaru!
He wasn't in the shed where we first met...
I guess it's not somewhere he has memories with me
Torajirou!
Sai said that he met Torajirou on Innoshima...
There it is...
Let's see... Innoshima... Innoshima...
Hiroshima!?
That's fricken far away!
Here it is...
He... Complained constantly about me
But he liked Torajirou...
Man, so what!?
I spent time together with Sai, too!
I'll find you no matter what
I won't let you just disappear all of a sudden!
I won't let you!
I won't, you hear me Sai!?
But.. Innoshima...
Can I make it back today?
Well... But... Where Sai might go?
I may find some leads as to where Sai went
Hey! Where are you going?
Want a ride?
Kawai-san!
Tokyo station?
You're taking a trip somewhere?
And, isn't Innoshima where
Honinbou Shuusaku was born?
That would be fun... I wish I could go, too
I was really busy during Golden week this year...
Okay! That's it!
I'm gonna drop this car off at the office
W-What?
I said, I'll go with you
Mount Fuji looks so beautiful today
Kawai-san could you keep your voice down?
You idiot! You have to make the most out of vacation trips
But you're just tagging along...
We have to get on a bus to Innoshima from here
Oh! That bus!
It says it's to Innoshima!
It's the bus! Hurry!
Let's go!
H-hey! Man... Why do kids always have to run?
We're crossing the sea?
Of course!
It's the ISLAND Innoshima, ISLAND
What, Don't worry, it's not supposed to be that long of a trip
It says the Shuusaku Memorial Museum is a 15 minute walk away after we get off the bus
Shuusaku Memorial Museum?
Yup, yup. It's the remains of the house Shuusaku was born in
Isn't that the kind of place you wanted to go to?
A memorial Museum...
Would Sai go to a place like that?
I have a feeling that he wouldn't be very comfortable there...
This is it! This is it!
Are you as excited as I am?
Sai! Are you here?
They said the memorial museum is towards the back
Sai!
Stop hiding!
He's not here?
Sai?
I guess he isn't here...
Hey! What are you doing over there?
It's this way!
Were you praying or something?
Sai...
He's not coming here after all...
Wow! They have Go boards, too!
Is this... A Go board Torajirou used to play on?
Torajirou?
It's Master Shuusaku's childhood name
Yes, this is the board he used when he played with his mother
Sai!
Can you hear me?
Master Shuusaku's grave is over there
Oh! Hey! You!
Quit running already!
Ahh... This is why I hate kids
You see, he's a pro player who just became first dan this year
Wow, that's incredible
And he said he wanted to go to where Master Shuusaku was born. So here we are
I brought him here
Sai!
I'm sure Master Shuusaku would be happy to hear that
Sai?
This is it?
Sai...
Where did you go...
I... Have no idea what's going on anymore...
There's no use in getting dejected...
I've got to look for him
I guess he's not here after all...
Where did you go?
I came all this way looking for you...
Hey, Sai!
Please! Say something!
You can hear me, right?
You sure took a long time visiting the graves
I had no idea you looked up to Shuusaku so much
It's not like that
Don't deny it
I've already decided on where to go next for you
Housenji temple in Takehara
The lady at the memorial museum told me about it
She said Shuusaku played Go there
That was the Go board they used at the time
And these are the stones
I can't believe we actually get to see them like this
He came here with Torajirou a long time ago...
It is important to preserve them
But I think it's also important to let the people who want to see it, see it
Excuse me for a second
Ahhh! The guys at the Go salon are going to be so jealous!
Sai...
Sai!
He isn't here...
Why, Sai?
Didn't you want to come to where Torajirou was?
Go home!? You've got to be kidding!
Going to and back from Hiroshima to Tokyo in a day!?
And this late at night!?
I'm going home! I told my mom that I'm only going out for a bit
And I have school tomorrow...
Go home alone then!
I'm going to sight see tomorrow, too!
What!? There's more!?
The guy at the last site told me about two more places
I'll go!
But... I don't have the money to stay overnight...
Aw man... I'll lend it to you
Wait! I've got to call home!
Hey! The phones over here
What's wrong? Eat up already
We visited both places this morning
You can't not be hungry
Fine, take your time eating lunch
Where are you going?
Didn't you see the Go salon?
I'll go play the guys over there for a bit
I'll pay for the bill here
Come pick me up when you're done
Sai...
He was nowhere to be found, after all...
I haven't seen him today or yesterday
I guess I'll go back to Tokyo already
If he's not over here
Yeah!
He just might be back in my room when I get back!
If I see Sai at home
Then, someday. We'll come back here again
I'm sure he'd be ecstatic
If I took him around here
I feel bad for Kawai-san
But I'll drag him back to Tokyo
Kawai-san!
What!?
Cut the crap already!
You're the one that suggested it
What!?
You're the one that lost
Kawai-san!
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?