Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Touya has already passed the pro examinations.
Pro? You've gotta be kidding? He's only in the 7th grade.
Most pros become pro in their teens.
April next year, Touya will start his race.
And he will move forward faster than anyone else.
You can't possibly catch up to him unless you desperately run after him starting now.
Hey!
How do you take the pro examination?
The Insei examination for December?
Yeah, we're holding it this Sunday, but we're past the deadline for the applications already.
What? But! I want to take it now!
Insei...
Examination!?
I thought Inseis weren't allowed to go to amateur tournaments.
Twenty-first match
The Haze Jr. High Go Club
Quit the Go club?
Hikaru, you're going to quit the Go club?
I don't intend to quit the Go club...
Even if you don't quit, once you become an Insei, you can't go to the tournaments anymore.
Insei?
What's an Insei?
There's no way Hikaru would quit the Go club!
He was just talking about how great the tournament's going to be! Right, Hikaru?
I...
I... just...Touya...
Shindou! You made me join the Go club to make me a member for the tournament, right!
And now you're backing out of that!?
Mitani!
Sup, Tsutsui?
Sorry for disturbing your fun, but hide me for a bit.
Hide?
Tsutsui! Have you seen Kaga?
No, I haven't.
That brat, where did he go?
Is... he gone?
Sorry! Sorry!
Kaga, what did you do?
Well, well...
Tsutsui-san, who is he?
He's Kaga a third year student, he's the president of the Shougi club and...
And I'm better at Go than he is, Although he's in the Go club.
In the Shougi club and is good at Go?
He's lying.
What'd you say!? You little brat!
Kaga!
I'm gonna crush you!
Oh, there are new members in the Go club.
Last year, you were the only one!
Kaga, Shindou-kun says he wants to take the Insei exams.
Oh? Insei! Do it! Do it! Just do it!
Huh? What's with the sad face?
Well... I...
Forgot that I can't go to the tournaments if I become an Insei.
Tournaments? Those don't matter.
Those don't matter!? Who are you to say that!
Shut up already!
Insei, huh?
Monthly Go World
If you want to become an Insei, you must have a higher goal than the tournaments.
Shindou-kun's goal is Touya Akira.
This book says he passed this years pro exams.
Touya...
If you're going to go after Touya, you can't muddle around in the Go club.
You've got to go all out at him as soon as possible.
I see...
You chase Touya...
But Touya won't be an easy goal. Do you understand?
I understand.
Shindou-kun...
You're right. You can't muddle with tournaments.
Tsutsui-san!
Shindou-kun says he's going to aim higher than Kaiou.
He hasn't said it! He hasn't mouthed those words at all yet!
He just forgot that he can't go to the tournaments!
Right?
Shindou!
I...
Doesn't this kid know how to shut up?
It's his choice to participate in the club or not.
You don't know! He forcefully dragged me into the Go club for the tournaments!
It's my choice whether to participate or not?
Fine I understand! Then I'll quit the Go club too!
Mitani-kun!
Do what you want. Quit if you want to. You're free to do as you wish.
Kaga!
Tsutsui, how many Go boards do you have?
Three.
Get them all.
Shindou! Play three games at once!
What!? Three games at once!?
Hey you, loud and annoying kid!
You're playing too.
Shindou's going to quit after showing you, Tsutsui and I exactly how strong he is.
Kaga is pushing Shindou-kun from behind.
He's right, we can't give Shindou-kun more doubt than he already has.
Okay, Kaga. We'll have Shindou-kun play three games against us.
Fujisaki-san can you help me get the boards?
Sure.
Mitani, you're playing too. It's the last match!
King
Haven't played Go in awhile.
Mitani! Play!
This is it!
Chemistry Lab
Mitani... if I fail the Insei exam.
Then let's go to the tournament...
You've gotta be kidding! I'm quitting no matter what you do!
Shindou, you're the one that's quitting, you can't have everything you want.
Well let's start!
Umm...
Hurry up and play!
But I have to think...
You don't have time to think when playing multiple games!
Play with your instincts! Instincts!
Sense! Flashes!
Over there, now!?
And here too?
I really am not a match for him at all...
Tsutsui hang in there. Don't let Shindou take it easy.
Shindou-kun and Mitani-kun are quitting the Go club?
Tsutsui-san will be graduating...
Akari, what will we do?
I...
I won't quit!
Because...
Because Hikaru isn't quitting Go!
Chemistry Lab
He's moving to all the critical spots with no thinking time!
This is it...
I resign.
Shindou-kun's incredible.
Mitani's done with his game too.
No...
I'm short.
I lose by six and a half moku including Komi...
I resign...
No one heard but...
I was here so I heard you.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Hikaru, Mitani spent everything he had playing you.
Can you tell who's winning, Shindou?
Kaga.
You can learn to count points already.
Well, we don't need seichi, right? I win by six and a half moku.
He...
I can't win.
Like I said! I'm really good!
Well, if you do this well playing three games, it's probably enough.
Huh? Really?
I told you, playing multiple games is different.
Will I pass the Insei exam!?
I don't know, I'm not an exam official.
If it's one on one, I can beat Kaga as well!
No one said that!
Yeah, Tsutsui-san, do you know how to write Kifu?
Um, yes.
I have to bring in Kifu's for three games I played.
Perfect, I'll write the three matches I just played. Can you teach me how?
H-Hey... The matches you just played... Do you remember all three games?
Yeah, of course.
Do you have a red and black pen? A red pencil will also work.
Red is white, and just put numbers in the same orders as the moves.
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
I look forward to his future.
What about Ko?
Put the numbers here and write "Taking Ko" here.
I hope he fails the exam.
How childish are you!? How long are you going to whine about this?
Hey, what's all the ruckus...
Kaga!
So it's basically a school for Go, right?
Japanese Institute of Go
← ahead 40m
But to pay an expensive fee to take the test to go in there...
Like I said, it's filled with skilled players, so it's hard to get in too.
What's wrong with the Go class you went to before?
That place was close to where we live.
That place is where a bunch of old ladies who don't improve go to play for fun.
Well, you've never focused on something like this before, so it's okay but...
only if you cared about your studies as much as this...
Oh, Shindou-kun, right?
I'll show you the way.
Please take off your shoes here.
Hikaru.
Yeah.
They must be Insei.
That's it, right?
Yeah, that's where it begins.
The first step to defeating Touya Akira!
Please come back after getting a little stronger.
Thank you very much.
Teacher, the last student is here.
Oh yes, please this way.
Please sit there.
What!? Seiza!?
Seiza is the Japanese term for sitting properly, with your calves under your thighs.
Please show me your application form and Kifus.
Let's see the Kifu...
You're white for all three, right?
What careless play?
This kids taking the exam at this level!?
His opponents are really weak too and...
Who is this Tsutsui?
A senpai from the Go club.
Mitani?
A friend in the Go club.
This Kaga. What about him?
Kaga is the head of the Shougi club.
Shougi!?
He plays the best out of all of them.
But, he is sponsored by Ogata-san.
Then let's play.
Any handicap?
Place three stones.
Umm...
How long will the exam take?
It will take at least an hour, feel free to wait outside.
Oh, is that the case? Then...
Hikaru, I'll be drinking tea in the coffee shop on the first floor, come get me when you're done.
It's unfortunate, but he'll fail.
He can't hold Seiza for even five minutes.
Oh, the Insei exams are going on today?
Yeah, a girl just failed it.
Who's taking it right now?
A guy, probably a little younger than me.
He'll...
probably pass.
Good luck.
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Today, you two will play a game.
Onegaishimasu!
This is a real battle to the end.
Done?
Yes.
When further play is meaningless, confirm the end with your opponent.
Adding the komi, it's a win by... 23 points!
Mai wins!
That was a great game!
I have a prize for Mai, the winner.
To be continued
He forced the teacher to make him third board because he wanted to play against me.
The reason he joined the Go club was just to play against me...
Hikaru!
Really!
I'm his, and he's my rival!
I'll catch up eventually!
Hikaru! You will lose at this rate.
If you wish, once again I will...