Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Twenty-seventh match
A Place to Go Back To
Shindou
Winning every game is hard.
Of course it is.
You are playing against those who are well aware of their goals and walking towards it.
Shindou!
Waya!
The next study session with my master is on Tuesday.
Shindou, you went to Mr. Morishita's study session?
What was it like?
Of course it helped him a lot, right?
K-Kinda.
Maybe I should join a study session too.
But playing Go all day long and all night long?
You're right, we need to let lose sometimes.
Hey! Wanna, go do karaoke on our way home tonight?
Yeah! Let's! Wanna go bowling afterwards too?
Okay. Let's ask Isumi-kun too!
Okay I'll call home then.
Okay, then I'll...
Haze Public Junior High School
I... don't want to do Karaoke or go bowling.
I just want to play at the Go club sometimes...
What will you do after I go here?
Here?
Yup, that's right.
Yes!
Hikaru!?
What's up?
You always go home right after class.
You study Go at home everyday, right?
Yup! I teach him!
What are you talking about? You don't teach me anything.
Don't worry about me. What about the tournament?
You girls are going, right? It's almost time, right?
Yeah.
What's wrong with that response?
What about Mitani? Did he quit?
I tried calling him a few times...
I barely even talk to him now because I'm in a separate class.
I can't bring up the Go club anymore...
I hope he comes back someday too...
Seems like it's become lonely here at the Go club.
Hey! Want me to play you guys for a bit?
He's gotta be bored playing you two crappy girls all the time.
I'll play all three of you at the same time! Okay? Okay?
Hikaru...
Please don't come anymore.
Ouch...
Natsume-kun and I were just talking about it... Mitani-kun might come back eventually...
And when he comes to take a look... if Hikaru was having fun here...
Mitani-kun wouldn't like it... He wouldn't come anymore...
Hikaru...
Then just this once!
Just once won't matter!
Get another Go board, I'll play you guys.
Hikaru!
Really...
You two place all the stones you want!
You think that little of us? I'm really going to place all the stones I want!
Okay!
How's this!
Just that? Are you sure it's enough?
Just this!? But there's so many.
Heh, just you wait.
Ahh! I'm getting nervous!
Good luck.
Chemistry Lab
Ahhh... Hikaru wins...
Ahh! I'm so angry! I placed so many stones too!
He just keeps taking them!
Hikaru, you're not holding back at all.
You're always doing that to me. I've got to let the stress out somehow.
Mitani-kun!
Mi-Mitani!?
Mitani-kun.
Hikaru just dropped by today.
I don't care whether Shindou's here or not.
I forgot my chemistry book, so I came to get it, that's all.
I'll just get it tomorrow.
You must be happy, getting lessons from the spectacular Insei.
About you forgetting your chemistry book... is that true?
The rearmost desk by the windows.
Akari...
Chemistry
Mitany Yuuki
It's here...
Akari... I...
It was nothing. Mitani-kun just forgot his chemistry book, so he came to get it, that's all.
I don't think he had chemistry today.
Oh no.
Tamako-sensei wasn't here today.
Hikaru, you Idiot!
Stop it Akari!
Now Mitani-kun's never going to come back!
Clean up the stones already and go home!
I'm sorry! I won't come anymore!
I get it! Stop it!
Come on to the
Basketball club!!
We teach you how to play
Members
Go club recruiting
Beginners are welcome
We're at the Chemistry Lab after school
It was exactly a year ago wasn't it?
When Shindou pulled me into the Go club.
We put up a poster...
But no one's coming... Not even one.
Mitani-kun won't come back either...
This sucks.
Let's make another poster!
Mitani-kun came last year when we made a new poster!
Anyways, you girls have to practice for the tournament next month.
What!? Are we really going?
We're going. I already asked the girl from the volleyball club.
So we have three including you, Kumiko.
Good luck!
I wish I could go too, but I'm the only guy.
There's nothing I can do.
Umm... ahh... I came to join the Go club... may I?
I heard we're having a quiz today.
Oh no!
Umm... is Mitani-kun here?
Hey! Mitani!
Mitani-kun.
Oh, it's you Natsume. What is it?
It's about the Go club...
Go club?
You're still in that?
Against those two girls that don't know how to play.
They know how to play now! They're starting to learn how to play a good game.
But that's not what I'm here for. We got a new member.
And?
That seventh grader isn't strong or anything, but he's about as good as I am.
Well, we have two male members now!
So?
So if you come back we can go to the tournament!
This again?
Mitani-kun...
Won't you play first board, Mitani-kun!?
You there. The bell's rung. Go back to your own class.
Wait for me after school. I'll come again.
Natsume!
Don't bother.
I'm not going back.
You there!
Well, to begin with, in yesterday's homework...
Okay! We're doing the lab on page 47 of your textbook,
so each group is to get whatever you need for it.
Be careful.
It wasn't me! He was...
I'll clean that up so.
Fujisaki Akari
What is this?
Match records?
They keep this crap?
Man they play a lot...
Five books in total?
Oh so they have five whole members.
The girls don't know how to play and Natsume and...
Koike Hitoshi?
And?
Mitani Yuuki
Mitani!
Hey, Mitani!
What are you doing! Help out!
What!? Natsume-kun you gave up after that!?
But...
Fine, I'll try asking him again tomorrow.
I'll go again too.
I'm sure something good'll happen if we just keep on trying, Senpai.
Yup, Koike-kun's in the Go club now too so...
Oh! Is that the new poster?
Your done already?
Is this okay?
I thought about putting a Tsumego in but...
Nah, it's great! It's very well done.
Thanks.
Ah! Mitani-kun!
You're going with us to the tournament!? You're going to play first board for us?
No!
Why!? Why not?
If you're not going to the tournament...
then, you came here...
to play us every now and then?
That's all.
Ahhh! That's fine!
We've got to get another board!
Umm, can you play both Natsume-kun and Koishi-kun to begin with?
I'm Koike from the seventh grade. Nice to meet you.
Play us after that!
We have to show him how much better we are now.
Waaasssuuuppp?
Kaneko-san!
I came to get some practice and drink some buds. We are going to a tournament after all.
I thought I should come here as much as possible and get some practice.
And? Who's the best player here?
I see.
Let's play then.
I'm going to Nigiri.
You're really confident. You're going to play me evenly?
It's our first match, We have to play evenly to see how relatively strong we are to each other.
But go ahead and put some stones down if you want.
What? Me? Play with a handicap?
Oh so you are confident. Then let's play.
Come on.
Oh, I'm first, You're at a disadvantage, so wanna tack on 10.5 moku komi!?
Komi is usually 5.5, she's making fun of Mitani here.
Why you!
Oh god please! Don't let Mitani-kun leave!
It's been awhile, I'm a little rusty.
I'm not trying either.
Oh! Kaneko-san's stones connected.
No. Mitani-kun knows that he's at an advantage, so he didn't try to forcefully kill them, and let them connect, that's all.
But Kaneko-san is a lot stronger than either I or Koike-kun. No wonder she was so confident.
About time you resigned, isn't it?
Yeah... You're rather strong.
What about the "I resign?" the "I resign".
Well, there are opponents that you really don't want to resign to.
But that won't work. "I resign"
How about a three stone handicap from now on?
If you think you can win at three stones, just try it.
Oh, those words are going to hurt when you lose.
Oh yeah! We've got to record this!
We're finally starting to fill in Mitani-kun's book.
It was always blank.
Don't record a game like this.
Why not?
We've got to make a book for Kaneko-san too.
Make it! Make it! Please!
I have to record my increasing wins and decreasing handicap against this guy.
Thanks Kaneko-san! It was fun today.
Hey Kaneko-san, you're in the same class as Hikaru, right?
Shindou?
Yup. Could you tell him?
That Mitani-kun's started to show up at the Go club?
To stop worrying?
Okay. But Shindou's going to be absent tomorrow, so I'll tell him on Monday.
Absent?
Yeah, he told the teacher something about going to a Wakajishisen or something.
Wakajishisen?
I'm sure he has his own tournaments. Leave him alone.
Cya.
Good bye.
G..Good bye.
Mitani.
We're playing three stones tomorrow too!
Who said I was coming tomorrow?
Then I'll make sure to mark down your loss by default.
But why is it three stones!?
You lost every game today at three stones!
I'll make it four stones if I lose every game tomorrow too.
Like I said! Who said I was coming tomorrow!
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Today's topic is "Fuseki."
Fuseki is the first stage in a game of Go.
Both players declare which area is their territory.
In this situation this area might become Black's territory.
And this area might become White's territory.
Black's territory looks bigger, so let's suppose White moves in.
When this happens, the fuseki is over, and the battle begins.
It is important to keep a balance with your opponent.
Right!
To be continued
9th Wakajishisen
I thought Mashiba-san would put up more of a fight.
You can't tell who's the pro.
Huh! It's meaningless to beat me at a place like this!
It's all meaningless unless you pass the pro exams.
Mashiba! You bastard!