この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
If you calm your emotions and play normally, you win.
If you play with stirred emotions, you lose.
I calmed down with those 30 minutes.
While you became upset.
He's completely been overwhelmed. There's no way he can win like this.
I win by four and a half moku!
Thanks for the game...
Thirty-second match
The Last Day of the Preliminaries
Second day of the Pro Exam Preliminaries
Please begin.
Good luck.
Hikaru... you're still not relaxed today...
If you lose control of your mind, the thought behind each of your moves begin the break apart.
Now that I think about it, you were like this during the Insei examination too.
You couldn't play the way you usually do.
An your moves become rushed, you went in too deep.
It's time for lunch,
so please halt your clocks.
Hey!
Let's go eat lunch! Lunch!
I bought lunch this morning!
What for!?
You're not going to finish it, Shindou-kun?
Just as I thought, Shindou isn't doing well.
If he loses today, he'll be at the end of the ropes with two losses.
Mind my own business.
Hikaru, umm, umm...
Shut up! I'm trying to think right now.
I resign...
How did you do!? I got my second win!
What? Looks like you got your second loss. You're at the end of your rope!
Hikaru, is this okay?
What?
I mean, it's almost time for the pro exam.
You already have two losses.
Are you sure you should be here?
It's okay.
I'll go in as late as possible.
So that I don't meet Tsubaki.
In order to get a win!
My opponent today is Fuku.
I've only lost to Fuku twice out of all the games we played for fun,
and all the games during the study sessions.
I should be able to beat Fuku if I play normally.
Fuku is probably desperate being one and one.
But if I play normally I won't lose!
Play normally... that becomes harder the more desperate you become.
Okay!
Please begin.
Shindou-kun! What's wrong!?
That doesn't matter, go sit down already.
Okay.
You came in at the last minute.
Mmm, sorry.
The clock's already started.
Okay.
Good luck.
Don't let your feelings take control, Hikaru.
I don't understand it at all.
That's like speaking to someone who's asleep!
But, didn't he say something earlier about giving him money so that he can take the pro exam?
The Inseis take it for free.
Ahh, I see.
He asked to take a day off of school awhile ago too.
He said he told his teacher already.
I thought he was too into it back then.
I thought I'd ask you dad, about what it's like to be a pro player.
No, I don't know anything either, though I do like Go.
What did Masao say?
He said, "It's hard to become a pro no matter who it is. He'll probably drop the exam."
"Let him do what he wants."
I agree with him. Just let Hikaru do what he wants for now.
It feels like Hikaru's changing... I feel uncertain.
Why does Hikaru want to become a pro all of a sudden?
He lost to a boy his age by a lot at Go, and he was given up on.
He looked disappointed, and became pro. So I want to make him look back at me.
Yeah! The eyes he had when he first came to me.
I'll make him turn those eyes to me!
How fortunate that the opponent is someone you're used to playing.
You're back to you're normal self.
It's time for lunch, so please halt your game.
You're already in the end game?
Do you want to play to the end?
Yes.
Ah, okay.
I was worried for Shindou-kun because he got two straight losses, but he's playing the way he usually does.
I have 50 moku.
I have 59 moku.
I won...
Thanks for the game.
Yes! One win!
One win? Shindou-kun you lost twice!?
Oh you didn't know? I would've been out if I lost.
I'm so glad I won. Oh yeah... now Fuku you're one and two just like me.
Yeah.
Sorry. I'm going to go home. I don't want to bump into that hairy godzilla.
Is that why you came at the last minute this morning?
Yeah.
Are you going to come at the last minute tomorrow too?
We're going to have drawings again tomorrow.
I know!
It makes sense for the winner to record the game. I'd hate to mark down my own losses.
Fukui... Fukui... and then my win...
Three and a half moku...
And one more!
I'll grab a win again tomorrow!
Tomorrow... you have two losses still tomorrow. That won't change.
I resign. This is it.
Jinryuji-san lost!
Who is that kid?
You're not going to tell me that you're a pro right?
No, I'm an Insei.
Playing at a Go salon like this occasionally is good practice.
Oh, an Insei, here to practice...
I have a friend who's a pro.
According to him, if the age limit for the exam wasn't 30, I could take it too.
"You're strong enough!" He told me, but seems like he was just being polite.
Sorry I didn't put up much of a fight.
No, thank you very much.
Over here mister, you played here.
If you had kosumi'd here, I would have been in trouble.
I see...
Waya, are you done? Want to go?
Yeah.
Hold on a second.
Try going to this Go salon. You want to play good people right?
Thank you very much.
Playing at a Go salon is fun, but the smoke is...
Want to play at my house, Waya?
Hey Isumi-san, let's stop by the Institute.
To see the pro exam preliminaries?
Today's the third day.
Let's go see if Shindou's risen up with three straight wins.
What!? Waya and Isumi-san dropped by afterwards yesterday?
Yup. In the afternoon, to check the match records.
When I told them that Fuku and Shindou finished in the morning and went home.
Waya said "Those two always play so quickly."
We used a lot of time that game for Fuku and I.
The people with three wins and three losses are gone.
And all the people left are people who are 1-2 and 2-1.
Waya said "Shindou that idiot, what is he doing?"
It's not just you Shindou, I have two losses Fuku has two losses... it's really bad.
Morning!
To think, Iijima-kun got three wins.
Oh yeah! Where's Tsubaki!?
The beard guy got three wins and moved on.
Oh, so he's not here.
Well then, we'll begin the drawings.
Please come forward to draw a number when your name is called.
If you've already played your opponent, please say so, we'll redo it.
If two people with two losses play each other, one of them will fail.
Let's begin now.
That move he played now, it seems like a good move, but it's a failure.
If Hikaru responds correctly...
It ends here.
I resign.
Yes!
Like I said! If you had only played like that on the first day!
But nooo you were afraid of the bearded guy and you lost. I'm so angry!
Shut up already.
Fuku won too. Now Fuku and I are both 2-2.
Will you mark me down too?
Oh you won?
Yeah, by resignation. I'm so glad.
Nase is 2-2 too.
We might play each other tomorrow.
There will be less people too.
I'll go watch the other games.
It's finally the last day of the preliminaries...
I'll take... a win tomorrow too!
Pro Exam Preliminaries Day 5
Two boards... this decides everything...
Umm...
Morning.
Looks like everyone's here.
There are five people with 2-2. Two of us will...
We'll begin drawing the pairings.
Fuku and Shindou-kun have played each other on the third day.
Anyone else played someone here? No right!
Then if Fuku-kun is playing Shindou-kun, we'll redo it.
Everyone please come forward and draw a number.
I'm B.
I'm B too.
Your name?
Hirabayashi.
Let's see, Hirabayashi and Fuku-kun.
I'm A.
Nase-kun and Matsui-kun.
Shindou-kun you don't have an opponent and you win by default.
Win by... default...
YAHOO! I won without playing.
I'm so lucky!
It's the opposite! You're unlucky!
Hikaru, you need to play as many games as you can!
Really?
You're going to play that bearded guy again!
I still have a month till the exam!
I'll train! I'll train!
Train? How?
Umm... I'll think about it when I get home.
Think about it now! Now!
Ahh you're so annoying.
Oh yeah, Morishita 9-dan's study session is this afternoon...
I don't want to go home only to come back again.
Wanna play on a magnet Go board to kill time?
~Wai~ I'll play! I'll play!
Shindou and the other guys with two losses... if they won yesterday, they should still be there.
If they have three losses, they would've failed yesterday, and they wouldn't be here today.
If he failed... Shindou might not come to the study session today.
Fuku and Nase and the outsiders are the only ones playing. Did Shindou fail?
Sh-Shindou!
Hairy Godzilla!? You lost because of that?
Y-Yeah.
Even if it was by default, you made it to the exam, that's good.
But really, I thought you'd come up with three straight wins.
I didn't think you'd get defeated by a hairy godzilla.
But... I just kind of got angry and...
Okay! You'd come with us, the next time Isumi-san and I go to a Go salon.
Go salon?
You're going to play against people like that hairy godzilla.
You've got to get used to it by the exams.
They should be done by now. Let's go check.
Yeah.
Hey mom? It's me. Yeah, it just ended.
Yeah, I won.
Thanks.
Sure.
Waya-kun...
Fuku, how was it?
I won!
Yes!
Yes! All three of you made it to the exam!
Man, you really had me worried.
Who cares! We won!
What are you talking about? Just yesterday you were going,
"Where's the hairy godzilla? Where's the hairy godzilla?" in fear.
You didn't have to say that!
Oh well, I'm just glad you won.
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Today, let's continue with tesuji.
It's White's turn.
These three white stones are in jeopardy,
but there is a way to save them by capturing these black stones.
What should you do?
You're almost there... Go for it!
So, in the end, you can capture these black stones.
Now, how about this example?
That's right, you can turn the tables and capture black.
If you play tesuji this way in an actual game,
Go becomes even more fun.
To be continued
Just think of it as a team match!
Team match?
We have to be able to beat the old men at a Go salon with three stones at least.
Why you bastard! How dare you look down on me like that you brat.
I can't just play like I normally do. I have to find a key to the game.