Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
I want to go to the Wakajishisen!
No, I have to go!
Otherwise, I can't say "To defeat Touya Akira" anymore!
I have to go to the Wakajishisen and show him!
That I'm right behind him!
Twenty-sixth match
Welcome to the A League
Waya!
Shindou... what is it?
Hehe, look!
I'm in first class! I'm in first class starting today! First class!
The bottom of first class.
Hey, why don't you congratulate him?
When he passes me I will.
Waya-kun you're so strict!
But! But! I'm closer to the Wakajishisen now that I'm in first class!
Closer to Touya?
You see, with the Wakajishisen...
I have to be in the top 16 right?
First I've got to rise up to first class, getting to the top 16 comes after that.
It's nice to be excited but... Shindou, do you understand?
What?
Your opponents from today, are us, the first class.
But, I guess you rose up pretty quickly.
Come on everyone, stop pressuring him.
It's not pressure, I'm encouraging him.
Well, good luck.
Good luck.
Good luck!
Welcome to first class!
Hikaru, hold yourself together.
Nice to meet all of you!
It's time, please begin.
Good luck.
We have more time in first class than in second class?
I can't be afraid just because my opponent is in first class.
I'm in first class too.
Hikaru, took his first step in first class.
Thinking again?
That move has a lot of thought put into it. No wonder he's in the first class.
It is strong... but!
I can't cower away from my opponent!
I have to return an even stronger move!
I'm climbing much higher!
Looks like you've really taken a step up Hikaru.
Though you have a lot of rather worrisome parts.
I resign.
One win!
This is my first time playing Fuku but...
He doesn't think at all...
The guy from the morning thought so much it threw me off but,
Fuku is faster than the guys in second class.
The stones flow lightly. The teacher complimented me on my three board play...
Maybe I'm better at fast games.
Oh! I won by half a moku.
Yes! Two wins in a row!
I lost!
Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Things got a little hard from here, but we kept on playing.
Shindou-kun you took that part and it got close and I lost track.
Fuku, you play really fast.
Yup, everyone says so.
Hey, let's play another one.
Sure! We've got plenty of time.
Go's so much fun.
Yup, Waya-kun says that a lot too.
Is Waya good?
He's good. But I win against Waya-kun for some reason.
Maybe it's incredible that I, who defeated Fuku, who can win against Waya!?
Hikaru, it's your turn.
I know.
Wow, you came really far out here.
This is my field. My territory!
Okay!
I come down upon the territory of white and build a tower of black!
AHH! Right in the middle!?
Be quit over there! Some people are still playing!
Okay...
I'm sorry.
What about your match? Who won?
Shindou!? That's two straight wins.
Waya you lose to Fuku?
Fuku, why you!
But it's the truth!
I'll tell you this because you're getting cocky, but I'm your next match. So you won't have a third straight win.
We'll see!
Why you...
Two straight wins! Two straight wins!
I'll tell you this because you're getting cocky,
but according to Waya, he's your next match.
So you won't have a third straight win.
We won't know till we play.
Yes but...
Speaking of, we've never seen Waya play.
Yeah.
I wonder how he'll play against me.
Hey, it's your turn Sai.
Well then.
It's going to be fun!
Yeah...
Good morning.
Is Waya here.
He is, look.
Internet Go is easy.
But I know nothing about computers.
My cousin said he's giving me his old computer.
What's the model?
How am I supposed to know?
Anyways, teach me internet Go for when my cousin teaches me how to use it.
Yeah, okay.
Talking about Internet Go?
Oh! That's when we used that box to play right?
Shindou, you play Internet Go too?
So you know how to use computers? You don't look it.
Umm... I saw someone play it in a store before.
Though I'm the one that played.
I don't even have a computer.
Oh.
Does anyone good play Go on the Internet?
There's quite a few. You'll learn plenty.
Pros play on it sometimes too.
Amongst the commoners?
They play as a joke sometimes.
But they don't use their real name, so you won't know.
But this one time, they used their real name.
Of course you wouldn't expect him to be the real thing.
Did you play?
Yeah.
I thought it was just an amateur using a pro's name.
I got creamed.
Who?
Mr. Ichiryu, When I checked, it turned out to be him.
Wow... the pros...
It's not just pros.
There was one guy I thought was stronger than the pros.
Though he stopped showing up after a little more than a month.
Stronger than a pro?
A little more than a month?
Internet Go sounds fun. Let's play it sometime.
Yeah.
Waya, what's the name of this guy who's stronger than a pro?
Name?
Sai.
Oh wow.
Just as I thought.
It was summer last year that Sai was on the net.
I only played him once but, I watched him a lot.
Seems like I played Waya before.
So he must have been one of the guys in your massacre.
He was really strong.
Not a loss to the best of my knowledge.
Not a loss to the best of my knowledge too.
It wasn't just amateurs either.
A pro in the Korean Institute lost too.
Hmm... there are pros in Korea too?
Even Touya Akira ditches the exam to play against Sai.
I know about that.
But anyways, he was an incredible player.
Once summer break ended, he disappeared though.
I check for his name whenever I play Go on the net every time still...
in hopes of playing Sai again.
There were many people who played against Sai.
But Sai never spoke to any of his opponents.
So his identity is still unknown.
But, Sai for some reason messaged me.
After he beat me, he typed in...
"I'm strong aren't I?"
Doesn't he sound childish?
Zelda...
Yeah... you said "I'm an Insei"
Waya, you're Zelda!?
Hikaru!
Y-You...
How do you know about my conversation with Sai?
It's time, so please begin your games.
Good luck.
Could it be... he's... Shindou is...
Sai?
Can't be...
Impossible!
I said too much again.
Hikaru, worry about that later.
Hikaru! Concentrate on the board right now!
Hikaru! Can you hear me!?
It's no good if you can't hear me!
Wait... what am I saying?
I saw Sai's matches many times.
He's not Sai.
Sai is much stronger than this.
But...
How should I put it...
I feel Sai within his moves.
No! No! Don't think about that crap!
But...
Shindou knew about my match against Sai.
Is he Sai after all?
No! It can't be!
It can't be!
IT CAN'T BE!
I resign.
We won....
I have... three straight wins...
That's it...
I figured it out...
Shindou!
You're Sai's student aren't you!?
You were watching my match against Sai from behind him weren't you!
Close! He wasn't behind me, he was in front of me!
If you're learning Go from Sai...
Touya Akira said he was chasing after you right?
Yeah. That's because he saw some of Sai inside of you right?
It sounds kinda right and kinda wrong...
Waya is really sharp.
Shindou! Answer me!
How do you know about my match against Sai?
Waya...
It was only coincidence that I saw the match between Sai and Zelda.
Remember? I told you that I went to an internet cafe?
There was someone playing Go on the internet there.
When I turned to look, the match was already over.
And the conversation between Sai and Zelda from then was interesting.
So I remember it. That's all.
What about him?
He went home right away. I didn't even see his face.
Hikaru...
You're getting better at lying.
It's all thanks to you.
So he doesn't know him...
It was a good game Shindou.
The moves, they were interesting.
Maybe you will become strong!
Like Sai someday.
Three straight wins!? Against Waya!?
My opponent for the afternoon seemed scared of me.
I moved in too far sometimes, and...
I resign.
I got my fourth straight win.
Just when I thought "I'm gonna have all wins from now on!"
I got straight losses from the next match,
and I started to doubt whether I'm getting stronger.
NcDonald's Hamburgers
Well, I guess you did well.
You managed to make it all the way to 16th after all.
Now you qualify for the Wakajishisen. Congratulations.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
And he was getting ten straight losses in second class recently.
But he's still not a rival.
He did get over the hurdle in front of him,
so congratulations it is.
Doesn't matter to me.
And? When is the Wakajishisen?
Touya will be there right?
Is Touya Akira the only thing in your head?
Next month and the month after.
On Saturdays we won't have Insei matches.
It takes more than a day.
It's a tournament between 16 Insei and 16 new pros.
It takes three days.
The first match is all between Insei and pro.
It's an even game of course.
How was it last year?
The Insei that went past the first round...
There were five of them.
Isumi-san and I were the only ones that won the second round. But that was it.
But you won against pros! Wow!
What are you talking about?
You won't pass the pro exams unless you can win against pros.
Wakajishisen is a good testing ground.
Will Kurata 5-dan be there?
He won't. I think he's over the age limit.
I'd rather not go up against Saeki-san.
A match within your class?
More importantly. We have to get past the first match first.
Oh yeah, Nakayama-san will be there too, I heard.
Touya...
I couldn't even respond to you back then...
Want to play now instead of someday?
Now I can.
"Yeah, let's play."
Mashiba Mitsuru, 17 year old, from the Chiba prefecture.
Studied under Mizokuchi Hiroshi 9-dan.
Touya Akira, 13 year old from the city of Tokyo.
Studied under Touya Kouyou Meijin.
Ogata-san! Ogata-san!
Oga...
Welcome...
To the world of the pros.
Thank you.
Haze Jr. High School Graduation Ceremony
Tsutsui-san.
Umm... Thank you very much!
Stop it, I'm the one that should be thanking you.
It's thanks to you guys that the Go club was able to continue.
Thank you. It was fun.
Tsutsui-san...
Take care.
Yeah, you guys take care.
Yes.
Kaga...
Kaga!
Oh! Shindou!
Umm... I...
The three board match from then... umm...
Don't worry about it. Take care man.
Yeah! I'll be working hard!
I'll be looking forward to the news that Shindou-kun's become a pro!
Good bye! Tsutsui-san!
Watch me Tsutsui-san!
Please write.
I... really will be working hard!
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
This is Yuta Iyama, who turned pro this year.
He's still just a 7th grader.
Do you have time to play with your friends?
I play games with my friends on Mondays and Wednesdays after school.
Which do you enjoy more, schoolwork or study Go?
Studying Go is harder work.
Please tell us what kind of girl you like.
I like kind-hearted girls.
Please tell us your goals for the future.
I'd like to become a player capable of winning titles,
and able to compete on a worldwide level.
To be continued
Thank you very much!
Seems like it's become lonely here at the Go club.
Mitani-kun!
Hikaru just dropped by today.
I don't care whether Shindou's here or not.
Hikaru...
Please don't come anymore.