Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
But...
what if he cheats during the tournament?
He has the nerves to do it at a Go salon against adults.
He probably won't hesitate to against a kids tournament.
His opponent won't notice, we won't notice...
But, can you form a team with a guy like that!?
Make him stop, Sai, how!?
I don't know.
But I'm sure we can do something...
We have to make him stop!
Eleventh match
The Most Inconsiderate Act
Mitani!
Huh? Another kid?
This kids not gonna come bet 10,000 yen again is he?
10-10,000 yen!?
Oh, the boy from yesterday. Are you going to play?
No I'll just watch.
Then, could you shut that door?
It's too loud outside.
Oh, sorry.
The match is still in the middle game.
Hey if you're a friend, could you tell this kid to take it a little easy on us old folks?
Really, this boy doesn't know how to hold back.
What did you come here for?
What? Umm... well.
Sai, Mitani is winning this right?
He won't cheat if he's winning right?
You look as if your disappointed.
No I don't.
What are you talking about?
Chemistry Lab
Hey, Tsutsui-san...
How did Mitani cheat at seichi?
You decide win-loss in Go, by the size of your territory.
For example, this black formation.
Count the number of intersections inside.
1... 2... 3... 4... 5... 6... 7... 8... 9... 10... 11... 12
That means this territory is worth 12 moku.
After you finish a game, they usually look like this,
but it's hard to count this right?
So you make the territories square to make it easier to count.
All your doing is moving stones around inside the territory,
so it doesn't increase or decrease the number of territories you have.
See? With this, 3 times 4 gives 12.
Yeah it's easier to count!
So this is what seichi is... and he cheated at this?
Yup.
Is that easy to do?
It's not a matter of easy or not...
Even if I did it awkwardly, the opponent probably won't notice.
Because, when your doing seichi,
you usually don't pay attention to how your opponent is doing it.
After all it's taken for given that neither side would do something dishonest.
The game of Go is based upon the foundation of trust.
Cheating at seichi is the most inconsiderate act that takes advantage of that trust.
And Hikaru is trying to let a kid like that in?
How can this guy bet 10,000 yen with his skill?
There are a lot of old men who try to look cool with no real skills.
Hey boy...
You think you've already won right?
Have you heard of the phrase "You don't know the outcome of the match until it's over"?
They also call it "Don't count your skins until you've gotten it".
Oh, you laughed?
You can't laugh until it's over, during a match...
That's nice.
Right?
You seem to understand what I'm saying.
You might make something out of yourself later.
Hey kid, can you grab that ash tray there for me?
Thanks.
Are you left handed?
You've got good eyes too, nice.
Left handed?
Fine, it's still a little early...
But I'll teach you what an adult's Go is. At the price of 10,000 yen!
You think there's no way I can catch up after this right?
But just you watch!
The game's only just starting...
Sai...
Damn him...
There!
His hold on the stone's is so much better than earlier.
I'm catching up now.
Look, look, 5 moku there!
10 moku!
15 moku!
He moved a stone!
You have got to be kidding, where!?
The game's turning around quickly.
That stone wasn't there!? When?
What is it boy?
Did you miss something?
We're betting on the game you should pay more attention.
Mitani...
Yup that's right, you don't know till it's over.
I can't do it... He's much better than I am...
and if he moves the stones around too...
Okay, the game's over, you know who's winning?
You can't win unless you tweak the seichi.
You're slow, you're slow!
This guy's doing the same thing I've been doing!
12 and a half moku difference with komi... I won.
Hey boy, take out 10,000 yen.
Mitani...
Damn!
Is that all?
5, 6, 7... 8... and...
You're short 20 yen.
Mitani, I'll lend it to you.
Hey, Shuu-san do you think you can lend me 20 yen?
Mitani...
Thanks.
Hey boy.
When you've cheated too much, people like me get called in.
Dake-san!
Will you lend me 20 yen?
Thanks much.
Mitani!
What is it with him?
Wait up!
When did this place become an arcade?
Mitani!
In result... he learned his lesson.
This may have been unavoidable...
...people only learn from mistakes when they're hurt by them.
But!
Sai! It was a trap!
That guy played badly at the beginning to trick Mitani!
But...
...that was too cruel.
Can't we get it back for him!? The 10,000 yen!
Mitani's learned his lesson already, but that guy's...
Sai!
I can't stay quiet anymore either...
We have to deal with people like that with a cold heart.
Who do you think is the strongest player in Go history?
Well, the top right now is Touya-Meijin with four titles..
The strongest young player would be either Kurata 4-dan or Ogata 9-dan.
I heard this one reporter asked a pro that question.
And the pro that was asked replied without hesitation: "It's Honinbou Shuusaku from the Edo period".
The Go from that period's stupid. It won't work at all these days.
We'll give Mitani back the 10,000 yen tomorrow and ask him to come to the Go club again!
But Sai, can you win? That guy looked really strong.
I saw him play earlier, it's fine. We can win.
What if he moves a stone?
I will catch it.
You can tell him that you saw it, or to do a better job.
What if he cheats at seichi?
It won't go to seichi, he will resign.
It was just recently that he started cheating.
When he was just making a bit by betting, all the customers loved him.
They gave him the money happily, as if they were giving it to their grandson.
But you can't cheat... that's why I asked you to come.
It's an adults duty to teach kids a lesson.
Shuu-san, with the 10,000 I gave you, and the 20,000 yen fee, gimme 30,000.
He probably won't come...
Mitani-kun...
he probably can't come...
How sad.
Call me when ever you need me.
Well, I guess I'll wait for some prey now.
What are you talking about, I don't need you anymore, go home already.
That's mean Shuu-san.
Ojisan!
I'm a friend of his.
If I win will you give me that 10,000 yen back?
Then if you lose, you'll give me 10,000 yen right?
Hikaru, it'll be fine.
Then I can't do it, that's what a bet is after all.
Dake-san, stop picking on kids already.
Boy, you should go home already too.
Hikaru, I won't lose.
Hikaru!
Fine! I'll pay 10,000 yen if I lose.
Then I can play ya. Take a seat.
Dake-san!
I'm not giving you a handicap.
I don't need one.
You don't need it huh?
Kids these days...
You've seen my strength already.
How strong are you?
How strong? Umm...
About as strong as Honinbou Shuusaku.
Honinbou Shuusaku is a historically famous Go player from the Edo period in Japan. Sai lived in Shuusaku's consciousness before he met Hikaru.
That's a laugh! Of all the people Shuusaku huh?
If Shuusaku came out,
the only person who could play him would be Touya-Meijin.
I'm black.
With respects to Shuusaku, I'll start with my left hand.
Lower-right corner, komoku.
17-5
6-17
What will they do now?
Is everyone watching?
Strike three!
Even with two straight balls, you really can't hit it...
Oh he got one up!
The attack was a little too simple,
they had their way.
Wow, that ended quickly.
Really, please stop doing things like this.
It can't feel good to steal money from kids.
That boy was stupid too for trying to play Dake-san.
Okay Dake-san, please leave after drinking this.
Dake-san!
D-Dake-san this is!
H-Ho-Honinbou...
Shuusaku!
Oh, there it goes!
A home run! What a great hit!
I'll give this to Mitani tomorrow, and ask him to come.
That'll make three, we can go to the tournament!
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Christmas is right around the corner.
So today, we made a Go board that looks like this.
I'm going to give you a problem. Try to solve it.
Here is the problem.
It's Red's turn.
Where can Red play to capture Gold's stones?
He's placed his stone.
Thank you! That was a nice try.
Now you try, Mai.
Mai gets it right.
To be continued
Teacher, please make me our third board!
Come on, my target is Kaiou.
I can't afford to lose the first round.
Shindou... soon...
I'll soon... catch you!
Weren't you going to make me third board!?