この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
I resign.
I have 50 moku.
I have 59 moku.
I won!
Thanks for the game!
I resign.
Yes!
Shindou and the other guys with two losses... if they won yesterday, they should still be there.
Win... by default...
Thirty-third match
Team Formed!
Shindou, you've really never played adults at a Go salon before?
Go salon?
I haven't played but I've watched before.
Sai was the one that played.
Huh?
This place looks good, it looks big.
Heart of Stone
Brace yourself for the cigarette smoke.
Okay.
Hey Isumi-san, what about your Go class today?
About the Kyuseikai?
We have the day off today.
We do have three people here, just playing isn't very interesting...
Isn't interesting?
Three people?
Yes.
Ma'am, we'd like to play the strongest players you've got here.
I hate brats who are full of themselves.
Let's see if they have the skills...
to back those words up.
I'll play, I'm probably strong enough.
Okay, but could you wait a bit until we have three people?
What are you going to do with three people?
Think of a team match!
Team match?
Yeah! I'm sure it'll be a lot more fun that way than just playing.
Isumi-san, you're first board.
I'm second board.
Shindou is third board.
Wow! It sounds like a lot of fun!
See?
Don't lose Shindou!
Yeah.
What are they getting hyped about.
Team match? Sounds interesting.
I'll play too.
Owner!
There's two!
If you kids win, I won't charge you the admission fee.
What!?
Score!
But if you lose, you're going to wash all the stones in the store!
AND pay the fee of course!
Okay.
I'll play too. I'll make these kids wash the stones.
Okay! There's three!
Is this spot okay with you?
Saga-san, want to play first board?
No, I'll let you have it.
Huh? What's going on?
I'm going to Nigiri now.
Okay.
I'm going first.
Yes.
Saga-san you're white, Doumoto-san, you're black.
Oh, everyone's turns are decided by the first boards nigiri? I didn't know that.
I've only entered tournaments as individuals...
It's been awhile since I've played a team match...
I've always been third board. I was in the Go club, and I am today too...
Good luck.
Probably some Go club at a Jr. High.
Or actually there's one older child, so they're probably kids from a Go class somewhere.
They'll be taught a lesson.
It's okay. If I play calmly, I won't lose to him.
I'll get the first win on the third board.
I resign.
I resign...
Even the owner...
But the owner had won against a pro at two stones before...
Who are you kids...
That was just a warm-up!
Now it's time for the real thing!
Real thing?
He said it's his first time playing adults in a Go salon, so I let him get some practice with an even match.
Okay, now let's play the real thing, at two stones handicap!
Two stones!?
If we win, we don't pay the admission fee, and if we lose, we'll wash all the Go stones.
You intend to play them at two stones all along?
Of course! We're Insei!
Insei!?
What!? Did he say Insei!?
W-Wait, this is out of my league. Is Kawai-san here?
No, he's not here.
Good luck.
Good luck...
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Wait up!
Phew, it sure is hot today.
Do taxi drivers really have that much free time?
Weren't you here yesterday too Kawai-san?
I'm a slacker, so I have time.
But anyway, Ogata sure was close.
The Honinbou match...
I can't believe Kuwabara defended it.
He sure is persistent, that Kuwabara.
But,
Welcome to
Heart of Stone
Ogata will take a title in the near future.
He's got so much momentum.
What is it? What's going on?
Kawai-san!
There are Insei here.
Insei?
40... 50... 51...
Okay! I won by three moku.
I won, and Shindou won...
Yes! We don't have to pay the admission fee!
Not pay the admission fee!? What's going on!?
I resign.
Isumi-san won too! That's three wins!
Okay, well then.
That was a preliminary match. This time it's the real thing, at three stones.
Waya!?
Waya hold it. Three stones against these people will be difficult.
Aren't you underestimating them a bit?
They are decently strong!
I'm not underestimating them. The pro exams are coming up.
If we don't have enough momentum to get past this, we won't reach the goal line.
You're right.
We should be able to crush geezers at a Go salon at three stones.
Why you! Condescending little brat.
Looking down on us!?
Kawai-san, please switch. You're stronger than I am.
Okay! I'd like to see you win at three stones!
Okay! Let's have a real match at three stones!
We don't just have to pay the admission fee if we lose. We have to clean all the stones too!
Don't you understand!?
Third board, don't lose!
Yeah!
Good luck.
To let Kawai-san have three stones. That's just crazy.
I can't just play normally.
I have a three stone handicap on my back.
I have to find the key to winning the game.
Hmph, how many years has it been since I last played a handicap game?
Huh? A shinte!
Shinte means a move that has never been played before.
I see... this is a good learning place.
Since Hikaru has only played myself, someone stronger than him,
he will gain a new strength here.
In Go, if you have even half a moku more than your opponent, you win.
Playing out of Joseki is stupid if you're playing someone of your own strength.
If it's an even match, you start off even. All you need to do is hold onto a marginal lead.
But a handicap game is like giving  20 to 30 moku to your opponent to start with.
What Hikaru is doing, is making unreasonable move in hope of his opponent making a mistake, allowing him to take advantage.
In that case, you have to take territory with moves that you don't usually see.
In other words, you become better at terrorizing the opponent.
That will turn into a strength to come back from losing situations during even games.
Here! They're from me.
Thank you.
Here.
Arigatou.
You're quite a thing, to beat me at three stones.
We totally lost.
I look forward to seeing you kids becoming pros.
Yeah, good luck!
Thank you very much.
Shindou, you held yourself together really well.
Waya! Things turned out alright because Shindou and I won, but you lost!
That old guy was quite good.
What if we actually had to wash those stones!?
It would've been horrible!
All's well that ends well.
But it was really fun!
Let's do it again tomorrow! Waya? Isumi-san?
I'm going to my teacher's place.
I have to go to the Kyuseikai.
Let's go next week.
Okay! Next week then!
Cya!
Weren't we trying to get Shindou to deal with his weakness? Looks like he enjoyed it.
See, it was really effective!
Let's go to a different place next week! It might get even more interesting!
Waya!
So Shindou, you've been going to that Go salon everyday since last week?
Yeah.
Oh, so that's why you ditched the study session.
I didn't ditch it! I forgot about it...
And? How was it?
It was awesome! Everyone wanted to play me.
Me next!
Kawai-san lost to you at three stones?
I was caught off guard last time.
Kawai-san.
It won't happen this time.
Let me get a match too!
You just played him yesterday!
And the owner's really nice too!
Don't worry about the admission fee.
Lot's of people want to play you.
So you're saying he'll attract more customers?
Hey son, you've got to ask to get paid instead then.
I'm not asking him to tutor people.
He'll play at maximum of four stones. I won't let anyone worse than that play him.
Understand Iimi-san?
Tsk.
Two stones for me.
Saga-san, lighten up on the cigarettes for him.
Good luck.
That's great.
Hey! Are we doing a team match again today?
Yeah, let's ask the people in the store.
Let's see... there should be a large Go salon around here.
Oh that's it.
Just that this isn't interesting enough...
so why don't we make the guy that loses buy Sushi for everyone!
I'd rather have ramen noodles! Ramen!
What are you talking about?
Like I said, have the guy that loses buy Sushi for everyone.
Ramen! Let's have Ramen!
Then it's more painful if one of us loses than if two of us loses.
Yup! Sushi over ramen!
What if the guy that wins decide! How does that sound?
Hey! Wait! I'm at a disadvantage since I'm first board!
I'll be playing the strongest guy there!
Let's decide with rock paper scissors.
Okay, let's decide who's first board with rock paper scissors.
Okay! Rock paper scissors it is!
Welcome!
Three of you?
Yes.
We'd like to play the strongest people you have.
Oh, you're confident aren't you?
Please write your name here.
And... If two or more of us lose, we'll wash all the stones in the store.
But if we win, can we play for free?
A team match I see!
You guys can have a three stone handicap.
Three stones!? Then you're...
We're Insei.
He's first board! So send your best guy up against him!
I'm third board. He's second board.
Three stones again?
Insei?
Insei you say?
Team match you say?
Then of course I'll be the one playing first board.
You? Play first board?
I'm better.
Second boards should know their place, Tsuchiya-san.
What!?
Let me play too!
Then me too!
Funaboshi-san, you lost to me the other day!
Then I have just as much right to play too!
It doesn't matter who's playing us.
You're all the same.
Don't say stuff like that!
What!? So you think you're better than us because you're Insei?
They said they're going to wash the stones?
We'll make you wash those stones!
Everyone please calm down.
You kids better keep your word.
Of course!
What!?
W-Waya!
Good luck.
I'm not going to lose today!
Neither am I!
Yes! We won 3-0!
Huh? What about the ramen noodles then?
We didn't have time to pay to play. So I'll take you two out.
Isumi-san! Sushi! Sushi!
No! Ramen noodles! Definitely ramen!
I was the first board, so sushi!
That doesn't matter!
Rock paper scissors! Rock paper scissors!
~Wah~ I was going to take that maguro!
It'll come around again, be quiet.
Didn't you dislike Sushi?
I never said I didn't like it.
You should stick to eating pudding.
My left overs are good enough for you!
~Uwa~ My squid!
I'm not going to let any squid or maguro get to you!
Mister! Toro for me!
That's unfair! I'll take ootoro!
Amaebi for me then!
Then I'll take anago!
Then awabi!
Toro over here!
Don't eat! Don't eat any more than that!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Today we're at the home of Yukari Sensei.
They're having a study session.
Shall we have a look?
Let's!
That move will get you in trouble...
Even Yukari Sensei has a teacher and studies like this all the time.
Yes, no wonder she's so strong.
To be continued
Please lose to them.
Four of them...
What were you thinking!?
Why such a serious look?
If you're a pro, make it look good when you lose.