Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Not yet...
I won't defend just yet.
I'll move onward still!
I'll show you!
Each of my moves!
I understand...
Touya...
you're telling me to catch up to you right?
But, I won't forget the match today.
It was exciting.
Twenty-fifth match
Fear and Impatience
NcDonald's Hamburgers
Shindou.
Shindou!
You don't have a teacher right?
How do you study Go on a day to day basis?
What do you do Waya?
I'm Morishita 9-dan's student.
I go to his house after school to have him teach me.
And you?
At home... I...
Get taught well!
Kinda study...
So you teach yourself...
You read books on Tsumego and replay games?
Well, there are people who only do that.
People like that never progress!
If you want to get stronger, it's not genius or hard work.
You just have to play people who are stronger than you as much as possible!
That's most important.
Someone stronger?
As much as possible?
I play a sickening amount everyday, every night.
When I think about that, you really are progressing slowly Hikaru.
What!?
Hey Shindou.
Wanna come to my teacher's study session?
Study session?
It's basically what we do at the Insei sessions,
but it's on a totally different level.
My teacher's pupils come.
They're all pro!
We do it once a week in a room at the Go Institute.
How about it?
I don't wanna.
LET'S GO!!!
Let's go Hikaru! We're going! No matter what!
Wha... What is it?
Shindou?
Well... can you ask him if it's okay?
Hikaru! What are you doing?
Let's go to the study session already!
Leave those realistic looking fake fish alone.
Just wait, I'm nervous.
I don't know what goes on in a study session.
If only Waya was here...
the pros all look scary...
What are you talking to yourself for?
What is it today?
The Insei's don't meet today.
I was invited to a study session...
Study session?
Who's the master?
Dunno... I mean I don't know.
Hikaru.
This person made it so you can take the Insei exam.
You should thank him.
Oh y..yeah...
U-Umm...
Thank you very much for helping with the Insei exam.
Study session...
Want to come to Touya-Meijin's study session?
Touya-Meijin is that man right?
The man who aims for the hand of god like me.
I don't know much about study sessions....
Do you play each other there?
You were going to go without knowing what it was?
Well, we do play, but it's mostly discussion.
We sometimes go over a match after playing it,
or we may go over the Kifu from a title match.
You can hear Touya-Meijin talk about his play and how he thinks.
You mean he's...!
Touya is there too!?
Yes, it would be motivating wouldn't it?
Hikaru, let's go.
He'll be playing...
He'll be speaking...
Let's go Hikaru!
I'm not going!
H-Hikaru!
I'm not keeping you from going to that study session.
No! I don't want to study with Touya!
I want to play him!
He's... he's my...
I can't say rival when I'm 18th place in second class...
But how can I sit next to him and learn Go dammit!
Hikaru!
You want to play him... I see...
Then I'll be looking forward to that.
Hey! What were you talking to Ogata-sensei about?
He invited me to the Meijin's study session.
Why would he invite you of all things!?
All things?
The Wakajishisen is in 3 months...
I may be able to see you and Touya play there.
Wakajishisen?
You really don't know anything do you?
It's a tournament where Insei and young pros play each other.
Insei and young pros!?
Touya will be there! I may be able to play him!
You will be there right?
I'll be there! Of course I will!
I'll be waiting then.
Wakajishisen... there was something that fun!? Wow...
Shindou, do you really know what it is?
It's a match between Insei's and new pros right!?
Just so that you know, only the top 16 in first class can go.
T-Top 16 in first class!?
Yup.
It's a tournament between the top 16 Insei according to the May chart, and 16 pros.
Of course I'll probably be there.
What about you 18th second class?
S-Sixteenth in first class...
I'm eighteenth in second class right now so...
Do that in your head!
You're going after Touya aren't you!?
Yeah... Touya won't wait for me forever...
But... It's going to be tough...
You're still crying?
I wanted to go...
Stop crying Sai.
This is a study session among pros too.
Yup! This might be fun in its own way!
Why you...
Excuse me. Come on in.
Hikaru, him!
Teacher!
S-Shindou-kun! Why are you...
Shirakawa-kun?
He's someone that used to go to my Go class.
Waya, is he the Insei you wanted to invite?
Yes.
Insei!? You're an Insei?
What? Is that unexpected?
Well... it's not unexpected...
I was just surprised.
He's learned how to play go just over a year ago.
He reminds me of Kurata-kun.
But he's second class right? If he's that bad...
I'll rise up to first class right away! 16th in first class!
I want to go to the Wakajishisen!
No, I have to go!
Otherwise, I can't say "To defeat Touya Akira" anymore!
I have to go to the Wakajishisen and show him!
That I'm right behind him!
Good!
"To defeat Touya", well said!
Strengthen yourself here to accomplish that goal!
Yes!
Master, you need to accomplish your goal of defeating Touya-Meijin soon too.
You don't need to tell me.
Master Morishita became a pro the same time Touya-Meijin did, and thinks of him as a rival.
Who knows whether they like each other or not.
I don't like him!
You're only second class...
Don't worry, you'll grow when you do.
You still have three months right? Just work hard.
Yes.
Thanks for the game...
I lost...
I've had straight losses since last week...
Don't make that face. I'm fine.
Shindou-kun.
I'm your next opponent. Wanna start?
Good luck.
Hikaru... I know...
Why you keep on losing...
I lost again...
and by a small margin again...
If this goes on I'll never reach 16th in first class in three months...
Hikaru!
Hikaru...
Maybe I'll quit...
Quit?
I don't have much hope...
Even if I stay here, there's no point unless I can become pro.
I need to start thinking about what to do for college soon too...
You know how I don't have a master?
I wish I did at a time like this.
Why?
Because he'll cheer you up?
The opposite,
maybe he'd tell me to quit.
"You can't do it"
"Maybe you should give up"
or something.
Then I can just quit this.
Don't say that.
You're just thinking that way because you've been in a slump.
You won't feel the same if you just win one.
Yeah! Anyways, I just need to win one and cheer myself up.
Everyone has had streaks now and then.
Yeah! Everyone!
Japanese Go Institute
This is how they went in the real game but...
It's no good. It's a bad move no matter how you look at it.
But I don't see any better moves...
Even if you run away,
your opponent will just use that to tighten his holdings.
Then why not lightly flow around?
That's too soft against the corner.
Even if they...
I'm studying here like this,
but my records keeps growing worse...
Umm... Hikaru?
What is it Sai?
Umm... there's something I want to say,
but Hikaru you told me to stay quiet.
I'll listen. What is it?
In that situation, I'll survey the status.
When you take a peek from the inside, it makes it harder for the opponent to respond.
That might be good.
U-Umm...
What's a loser from second class going to say?
Go on. Say it.
Umm... here...
You're going for this...
I see...
Not bad.
I didn't see it.
You're pretty good.
Good job Sai!
I'm playing with that Sai everyday...
BUT! Why did my rank fall that much!
My record for February is horrible!
I have to start from the bottom of second class for March now!
I can't make it to the Wakajishisen like this!
I can't even rise up to first class!
I only have two months left!
I'm playing you every day, why is this happening!?
That's why.
You're playing me, that's why you can't win.
Honinbou Shuusaku, that player replied.
The strongest player in the history of Go...
That's an article from quite a while ago.
How peculiar Igo is.
More and more knowledge is built on it,
but the name of a player from a century ago rises up to the title of strongest.
A player's strength relies heavily upon himself.
Yeah,
I don't stand a chance against Shuusaku's ability to read ahead,
and the strength of each of his moves.
Right? Ashiwara?
But I can confuse him with Joseki that Shuusaku doesn't know!
What if he learned the modern style of playing?
Then he's definitely undefeatable!
I wonder if even Touya-Meijin can...
Master, Ashiwara just...
Sasaki-san! Don't!
A Honinbou Shuusaku that learned modern Joseki...
There was someone like that...
Sai isn't a pro.
He's getting stronger! As if Shuusaku learned modern Joseki...
The strongest player? That's what you were talking about?
But, I was thinking who would be good enough to become master's rival.
Everyone is my rival.
Kuwabara-sensei, Zama-sensei and Ogata-kun.
And, you too.
But the rival is just an analogy and...
What do you think master?
If the ancient ultimate player Honinbou Shuusaku existed in the present?
What do you mean!
I can't win because I play you?
Yes, Hikaru you are afraid.
Afraid? Of what?
My moves that cut into you on the board.
You used to come at me blindly,
but you are learning to see each of my moves... the tip of my unsheathed sword.
And you have started to fear it.
And you hesitate from that fear.
That turns into confusion,
and it shows itself in each of your matches.
Look back to all those close games from the past few days.
Do you see?
Then it's clear what you need to do.
See the line of your opponents sword,
and move in as much as possible!
See... as much as possible...
Yes... Touya always did so.
Just like Touya!
Turn your fear into courage, and come!
Fine!
Hikaru! Come on! Another match! Another match!
W-Why you...
The Wakajishisen is coming up.
I'm sure all the new pros are focused on you, and you wish to play a match against you.
I'd like to play a match against them as well.
I'm looking forward to the Wakajishisen.
Speaking of the Wakajishisen, how do the Insei do?
Some of them make it all the way up to the third round,
but only pros are left by the semi-finals.
As to be expected.
Akira-kun,
Yes.
Shindou said he'll be there when I spoke to him the other day of the Wakajishisen.
Isn't that exciting?
I don't care about him.
That child...
See the line of his sword...
and turn my fear into courage!
Over here...
Shindou-kun, would you like to play a game?
Shirokawa-kun, you have the third round of tryouts for the 10-dan title this week.
Playing an Insei will dull your senses.
It's an important match, that's why I want some of Shindou-kun's passion.
It's all over if you've lost emotionally.
Right Shindou-kun?
Don't lose... emotionally...
I'm going to go! I'll definitely...
Then let's play. It's not a game of tutoring Go.
Good luck.
Turn my fear into courage... and move in as much as possible...
Touya won't wait for me forever!
No, he keeps on moving forward!
A little more than a month left.
I have to rise up to 16th in first class by then,
and participate in the Wakajishisen!
To play against Touya!
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
We're here at the Japan Go Association
On March 29,
the awards for 2001 were presented.
35th Kido Award
Most Outstanding Professional
Rissei O Kisei (10-dan)
35th Kido Award
Outstanding Player
Kaiho Rin (9-dan)
Your opponents from today, are us, the first class.
I'm climbing much higher!
Y-You...
How do you know about my conversation with Sai?
Is he Sai after all?