この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
So this is Sai...
Fifty-sixth match
The Answer to His Millennium
This is...
Touya... Kouyou...
and... Sai...
Your important match is next week?
I don't mind you coming here to relax, but...
Why don't you try to enjoy it?
Don't you enjoy being with me?
There is nothing I enjoy more than Go.
What a boring man you are.
You're going to lose if you don't relax.
I'm cheering you on, so don't lose.
Like you even know what title I'm playing for.
I lost the Honinbou match against Master Kuwabara in the last game, but...
This time...
Maybe I'll stop by the hospital on my way home,
and check up on my opponent for the Jyudan match.
No visitors!?
Excuse me!
Did something happen to Master Touya?
Oh, the sign?
Don't worry about it.
It's only up there because Touya-san asked us to put it up yesterday.
He asked you to?
He said that he doesn't want anybody bothering him today.
He's really focused on playing Go on the internet.
Internet Go!?
Yes.
I just went in to pick up the plates from his lunch, but he hasn't touched any of it.
Are all Go players like that?
Just who is he playing? Someone he needs to turn away visitors for?
And have requested that he have no visitors ahead of time.
Then... this match was scheduled ahead of time.
When did he schedule it?
And with who!?
This is it!
Sai!?
Master Touya is thinking.
Why!? They're already near the end.
Wouldn't expanding from there let him win?
Yeah, I agree.
Then why?
Is there something we're not seeing?
Hey, let's try playing it out.
Okay.
Mother, aren't you going to the hospital?
Your father told me not to come today.
He told you not to come?
He said he wants to play Go on the internet without getting interrupted.
He knew about this match before today.
Father scheduled this ahead of time with Sai...
Master Touya played Nozoki!
Nozoki!? From there!?
Here?
Doesn't that seem too small to you?
Not at all, he's going to play there after he gains territory on the side.
That may be so, but...
Perhaps he wants to get Sente there and then go to the right side.
I think expanding there is fine though.
Wouldn't that result in a Miai?
No... Touya-kun may be right.
But wouldn't black win by just defending?
Though black has the advantage, it's incredibly small.
The Meijin must have decided that he can't beat this opponent by just defending.
He probably decided on solidly taking territory while eliminating the white territory on the top.
Yes.
Sai can read incredibly deep and calculate very well.
He comes up with a move to take control of the game,
after reading all of his opponent’s moves.
I know that...
he won't let my father keep his lead without putting up a fight.
Sai won't...
Sai definitely won't.
Touya-kun...
You know Sai?
I played him once during the summer two years ago.
Sai disappeared from the internet after that match against me.
And the same Sai is now playing Go on the internet.
And against Master Touya of all people...
My father... arranged this match against Sai ahead of time.
Father knows who Sai is!?
But... the only time father left the hospital was
for the fourth game of the Jyudan match...
Did he arrange to play Sai then?
If not...
Then someone who visited him at the hospital...
Could... one of them have been Sai?
Say, Akira-kun.
He's such a nice boy.
He came to visit the Master at the hospital today.
Shindou-kun came to see him!
Shindou came to see him!
It can't be...
I still...
can't forget about Shindou and Sai...
If the Master were to have arranged this match...
He must have met him face to face.
The Master doesn't know how to use e-mail...
Then it must have been someone...
who was around during the fourth match of the Jyudan match...
Or...
someone who came to see him at the hospital...
No. Shindou is not Sai.
His game during the Wakajishisen was not a game that Sai would have played.
Besides, if he was Sai,
he would have become well-known even when he was an Insei.
But... even if Shindou isn't Sai...
He might know who Sai is.
But even if Shindou doesn't...
Someone around me is connected to Sai.
Even though he can play this well against Touya Kouyou...
We don't know anything about him...
Sai...
Just who is he?
Do you have any ideas, Touya-kun...
as to who Sai is?
Shindou!
Are you Sai!?
I don't...
have any ideas...
But... he's playing this well against Master Touya, the number one Go player, with five titles.
He has to be a well-known pro.
He might be a pro from China or Korea.
Can't you find out where he's accessing the net from?
No... I'm not sure...
I might be able to trace him...
if I knew more about the internet.
Sai is not Shindou.
Sai is...
Sai is as strong as the most experienced players imaginable.
I remember... the match we played together on the internet, two years ago.
My opponent, shrouded in darkness...
Yes! You!
You can't be Shindou!
Who are you?
If you're not Shindou...
Why?
Why...?
Why do I see the old Shindou in you?
The old Shindou...
Back when we first met...
Black is leading.
Ooyose is about to end as well.
But...
I can't feel any doubt coming out of him.
From this opponent...
I feel spirit.
I can feel it because I'm playing him.
This feeling...
I've felt it before...
Yes!
This atmosphere...
This pressure...
I've felt it all before.
This is!
A good move...
He can't capture this white stone...
The black territory there... just disappeared.
It was close to begin with...
But now... Black's lost out...
It's a battle of spirit.
When it's played against you, you realize that it's the best move you can make in this situation.
But... how many people are able to notice this move?
How many people can make this move!?
Master Touya's moves...
None of them looks like a bad move, but...
Somehow the two sides are...
Even!
This... this can't...
No.
It's just by a little, but...
The Meijin is...
Losing.
Only Yose is left...
When I read the game out to the end...
I see...
myself losing be a half moku.
Unlike all the other conflicts on the board, there is only one path you can take for Yose.
Though it's difficult to play right, and easy to stray away from...
there is only one correct path to take.
He won't make a mistake.
He probably sees the final board just like I do.
He resigned!?
Master Touya resigned here!?
Sai...
Sai has...
Won!
Why resign!?
It's still close!
There's only Yose left, but it's very close!
I have no idea.
He read the game till the end already!?
But they still have to fight over Kos...
Is he serious!?
Master Touya resigned here...?
It can't be...
Although the Meijin has played calmly and rationally...
Sai still played above him.
That move he made...
and the moves that followed it...
Is there... no way for the Meijin to turn the game around!?
No... there is.
There has to be!
Sai...
Who are you!?
Sai!
He's the old...
Shindou...
I've come upon an answer...
The old Shindou is the person I see inside Sai!
This doesn't...
This doesn't answer any questions though...
It's over...
Touya Kouyou...
You responded to me exceedingly well.
Each of your brilliant moves...
made my body shiver in excitement more than ever before.
And I feel proud...
that I could respond to you beyond the best of my own abilities.
Thank you... Touya Kouyou.
Thank you... Hikaru.
Hikaru?
Over here...
Master Touya prevented himself from being cut here...
You would think that he needs to make that move...
But if...
before that...
he placed this stone in the corner...
See? White has to respond.
So he'll have gained more territory than he did during the match.
By placing the move in the corner, Black can kill White unless White responds. Even if White responds, it leads to Seki, in which case White loses several stones worth of territory in the corner.
In other words, if Black had played In the corner instead of connecting...
He would've won!
Sai, you would have lost!
Hikaru is...
absolutely right...
How's that, Sai?
Hikaru...
I finally understand...
God has...
given me a millennium of time,
simply too...
show Hikaru this match!
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Let's do another Fuseki problem today.
The problem arises when White moves here.
Should black play here...
or here? Which is better?
If he plays here...
White responds like this,
and he can almost immediately get two eyes.
White has plenty of space.
If he plays here...
It may proceed like this,
and White won't be able to readily make two eyes.
White has very little space.
If White comes into a place Black is strong in,
respond aggressively so that White can't live easily.
To be continued...
Sai, you say?
So you do know Sai after all!
Mr. Ogata...
Did you arrange that match...
between Sai and Master Touya!?
No! It wasn't me!
Let me play him, too!