この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
I'm saved?
I'm not playing Touya Kouyou or old man Kuwabara right now...
He's just a new pro player.
And... isn't this Shindou's first time playing One-Color Go?
Touya Akira isn't the only one...
who will be threatening me from below.
There is someone else!
Fifty-ninth match
Touya Kouyou Retires!
Touya Meijin retired!?
What!? Unbelievable!
Why is he doing this all of a sudden?
He simply made the phone call apologizing to me since I was the head of his supporters.
We did arrange for a press conference,
but all he said was that it was what he wanted to do.
Ichikawa-san!
I'm just as surprised!
A-Anyway, we have to... umm... hold an emergency meeting.
Umm... we have a phone call from the sponsor of a title match.
Could it be because of his health?
I'll try going to Kouyou's house.
It's not fair! It's too early!
I still haven't taken a title from Touya Meijin yet!
Being defeated in the Jyudan match has nothing to do with his retirement.
If you had to retire just because you lost a title,
then I'd have to retire as well.
I felt as if I was playing against a whole new Touya Kouyou in the last game of the Jyudan match.
So why retire?
Why!?
What's going to happen to the title matches that no longer have a current title holder?
Make the challenger the temporary title holder?
Wouldn't we make the final match to decide the challenger a five or seven game match?
I heard a rumor that Touya-san lost to an amateur on the Internet.
But boy was I surprised when I took a look at the Kifu.
It was an incredible game!
That had to have been a match between top-class pros.
So the rumor that he's retiring out of disappointment from losing to Sai is just a rumor.
But It is too bad that we still don't know which pro player Sai is.
Oops, I'm going to be late for the bullet train if I keep talking here.
You see, my wife's family is holding a memorial service,
and...
Really, you're such a selfish man, Touya Kouyou.
Nagoya
Good morning.
I'm Touya Akira. Where is the match hall?
I'll show you there right now.
Oh, Touya-kun!
About your father's retirement...
We're all worried here that...
It's because of his health.
Is it?
No. His health is perfectly fine.
He's doing well.
Oh...
We don't get very reliable information here or in the western district.
I heard that even you don't know his reasons for retiring...
Is that true?
Yes. My mother does not know either.
But, Mother said to me...
Akira-san, there's no need to worry about your father.
I mean, he doesn't look at all as if he's torn about this decision.
But wouldn't he miss being able to play Go?
Not at all. Many players have already come to our house to play him.
This way.
But... this is tragic news for Go fans!
Please let my father have his way.
I'll make up for him.
The match hall is right upstairs.
'I'll make up for him.'?
Make up for a pro with four titles?
He said it so casually. He's going to grow up to become somebody.
It's right here.
Oh? Touya-kun!
Master Ichiryuu... in Nagoya?
Right back at you. There are hardly ever matches here in Nagoya.
My wife’s family lives here in Nagoya, I'm here for a memorial.
So I thought I'd come here to take a look.
Did you stay at a hotel last night?
That must have been rough.
Not at all.
How is the former Meijin, Touya, doing?
He's playing Go.
Even Mr. Morishita and Mr. Ookubo have come to visit.
Even Mr. Ookubo!?
I heard Kurata-kun went as well.
Yes.
Master Ichiryuu!
Oh! Miyamachi-kun!
How are you doing?
Long time no see.
What is a person of your stature doing here, Master?
I came to cheer you on! Why else would I be here?
Oh, really?
Thanks for the game.
Thank you for the game.
But Master...
You said that you can play Go even now that you're retired,
but I don't quite agree.
I mean, aren't there things that you can only see in the tension of a title match?
Kurata-kun...
That is certainly true for you and Akira.
There are many things you need to learn through competition.
But in my case,
I'm happier about being freed from meaningless obligations
and matches in places that I have to spend two days getting to and from.
So now, you can sit here, and people will come to you for games instead!
Like I did today.
I'll come again.
Please do.
Kurata-san!
I learned a lot from you today.
Thank you very much.
I'll work hard to try to catch up to you and Ogata-san.
I may have lost to you in the second preliminaries for the Meijin match,
but I will grow stronger and get even with you some day.
You're always looking up aren't you?
You probably don't realize that there's someone threatening below you as well.
Below me?
Not really below you... but immediately behind you.
You and he are the people who are going to be threatening me in the future.
He just became a pro this year... Shindou Hikaru.
You probably don't know him since you're always looking above.
Well, I probably wouldn't have taken notice either if I hadn't met him at a convention.
I played him once in a Go salon.
Shindou...
He's someone you have to watch out for.
Even Kurata-san has noticed, Shindou...
If only I wasn't playing in Nagoya...
I could have watched your match today in Tokyo.
Shindou...
Tokyo
I don't understand how he can retire.
Didn't he make a hundred million yen this year?
Yeah.
Even if he won't have any financial problems...
Who's your opponent today?
A newbie named Shindou.
He had a win by default on his first match, and today is his second.
Win by default!?
His opponent, Touya Akira didn't come.
Master Touya collapsed that morning.
So it's his first time playing today.
He'll be frozen stiff from nervousness then.
Good morning.
When I checked up on his scores from the Wakajishisen last year,
I saw that he lost to Murakami in the first round.
And his new first dan series game was horrible.
G-Good morning.
What's more, he should be frozen stiff since it's his first match.
As a third dan, I can't afford to lose here.
The 19x19 grid seems smaller than usual...
It's strange...
I feel like I can't lose.
Hikaru is starting to walk down the path to the divine move.
Not me...
But Hikaru...
Is there no way I can escape this fate God has for me?
It's a difficult game...
No, he's making it a difficult game.
I have to change the flow... the flow...
Change it!
I spent too many moves on the upper side.
Black's done well gaining territory while attacking me.
Anyway, I have to make two eyes even if I have to make weak moves.
I can only endure for now.
You can't just make eyes.
I'm going to gain a huge lead while you muck around.
Not good enough!
I did connect...
but in the meantime, he's invaded my area of influence,
I lost out...
The only place left where I can make a comeback is on the left side.
I have to take a chance and attack it!
So this is Hikaru...
This!
All he needed to do was defend
against my reckless attack, but...
He's retaliating instead of defending!
I had no idea he had grown so much...
I resign.
Thank you for the game.
I wonder what happened in Shindou's game...
Ishihara-san, how was Touya Akira?
I'll never beat him.
No matter how much you study Go...
I've been thinking ever since the matter with Sai.
Shindou...
Why did you appear before me?
Why do I chase after you?
And why do you chase after me?
Why?
How was my match today?
Wasn't I doing great?
He just wouldn't give up.
His persistence almost became annoying.
I bet he thought he couldn't possibly lose.
What's wrong?
It's your turn.
What is this move you just made!?
How can you be so arrogant when you make stupid moves like this!?
Well, you're right, this is a bad move.
I-I know that.
Hikaru can't even beat me.
What did you say?
Hikaru, you can't even beat me!
I want to play
more Go!
Yes! Hikaru can't even beat me yet!
I want an
eternity of time!
Well, you can't even pick up Go stones without me!
Umm...
Hey... let's play...
Sai?
Man...
Hikaru... let's play...
No way.
You're the one that quit.
Hikaru, you jerk!
Why is he in such a bad mood?
Someone robbed Grandpa's storage shed!?
He called just now.
They only took some of the things in the shed, and both grandpa and grandma are fine.
Hikaru! The Go board... is the Go board alright!?
The Go board that you lived in for a hundred years?
Yes!
I thought it was disgusting because there were blood stains on it...
But it's a Go board filled with memories of Torajirou for you.
Let's go check! Hurry!
And to think Sai was picking a fight with me just last night.
Oh well.
Great! They didn't take the Go board.
It's not great at all! The pots, plates, and wall scrolls... they took them all last night!
But, I'm glad that you came here because you were worried.
Dad told me not to because it's all junk anyway.
W-What!?
Really.
Grandma is Grandma, she said it's a perfect opportunity to finally clean out the shed.
There it is.
Huh?
Is it just me?
The stains look more faded than they were last time.
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Let's do Joseki today.
Mai-chan, do you know what Joseki is?
No, I don't.
Joseki is a set pattern of moves, researched by people over a long period of time,
the lead to equal benefits for both sides.
Let me introduce a common one.
White goes to Keima to attack Black's Hoshi.
and Black responds with another Keima.
White does a Suberi to reduce Black's territory,
and Black stops White with a Kosumi to prevent White from going any further.
And to stabilize his shape, White does a two space jump.
This is Joseki.
It's the shortest Joseki there is, and it is commonly used even in pro games.
Is this the only Joseki?
There are tons of others,
but you only need to remember a few important ones.
To be continued...
Why? Why is it not me, but Hikaru, God?
I'm going to disappear, but...
Hikaru will...
Shindou! Let me play Sai!
Sorry Hikaru...
I'll be going soon.