Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Did you pass?
Waya, you know him?
I heard him say "To surpass Touya Akira" in the hall.
Really! I'm his, and he's my rival!
There's too much of a gap!
I'll catch up eventually!
Yuugen translates roughly into Spiritual Wonder or Spiritual Mystery.
Twenty-third
The Room of Yuugen
When you lose you get a black mark. That is what Waya is referring to.
Oh it's all black!
Touya Akira's rival experiences 6 straight losses in a second class.
What is it!? What are you trying to say?
Oh! I see! He's your rival at Shougi!
Don't mind him Hikaru, you're getting stronger.
And what's your rank!?
Me?
Let's see...
Waya... Waya...
6th... in first class...
Waya you're good.
Compared to the bottom of second class I am.
And still lost to Touya twice.
Though I lost to him, I'm a lot closer to Touya than you are!
Though he probably doesn't even know I exist.
What are you talking about?
Ah! Dammit!
I'm pissed at myself for letting Touya beat me at the pro exams.
I can't lose to him in spirit and skill.
I played against Touya-kun too!
I lost!
O-Oh...
Touya doesn't matter.
It's all a matter of making yourself the top.
Who was that?
Ochi, he's in the sixth grade.
He came three months before you.
Of course he started at the very bottom of second class.
Now?
He's third in first class!
Third... in first class?
He probably thinks he'll pass the pro exams today.
I want to pass them too this year, no matter what!
If I pass this year, I won't have to go to High School.
You don't like studying Waya?
I hate it!
Ahh! The pain of having to listen to a teacher for hours and hours everyday.
Same with me.
I'll be in the ninth grade by the pro exam in the summer.
If I pass it, I'll start as a pro the same time I graduate!
I'd like to finally pass this year too...
Isumi-san.
I'll turn 18 this year, it's the last year I can remain an Insei.
But, even if you're not an Insei,
you can take the pro exam until you're 30.
I know all that. It's a matter of feelings.
Last year, and the year before that, I failed the pro exams despite being ranked one in the Inseis.
If I fail this year too...
I'd feel too sorry for myself to continue.
How many people can pass the pro exams?
Three.
What!?
Just three!?
There's a long way ahead on the path you're walking, six straight losses.
Long way... ahead...
I didn't think that would work.
I mean, this flow here, that's not good enough for black.
Then, do you want us going after the 2 moku here?
Yeah yeah, extend yourself here.
Can you really win the battle?
Probably?
Probably!?
What do you think about it Akira-kun?
Akira-kun?
O-Oh!
What is it? Is your mind filled with becoming pro?
No...
I'd like to say "finally". Akira-kun is finally a pro starting in April.
What I don't understand is why you were fooling around in the Go club when you joined Jr. High.
Right Ogata-san?
But he had more spirit back then.
Go isn't all about skill.
In between the small difference in skill, your emotions, your spirit affects the outcome of the game greatly.
Right now you're...
not even worth pounding.
I don't feel different...
Akira-kun's scary enough existence for me.
That's because you're losing one out of every three matches, Ashiwara.
Touya-Meijin probably knows since he plays him every day.
Well, once the matches begin in April, the results will show it.
But Ashiwara-kun, how long do you plan on drifting in between the first and second preliminaries?
Umm... yeah!
Are you free this Sunday?
There's something I'd like to show you.
Something to show me?
Shindou...
You won!?
Yup! My first victory!
Just one win?
I'm just about to start my winning streak now.
Touya...
Touya!
What's with him?
Hey!
Touya!
What's with him?
Did he have some business with the teacher?
No... he came to see if I was here.
What are you talking about? He completely ignored you.
He's not your rival at all.
He said he'll never appear before me again...
He's waiting for me...
For me to rise to his level!
You didn't know did you?
That he became Insei.
Was he what you wanted to show me?
So what if he is Insei?
What does that have to do with me?
He probably did it in pursuit of Touya Akira.
Oh! Touya-kun you're here?
Hello!
Perfect! Do you mind if I interview you for a bit? About becoming pro, and about your father?
It's fine with me.
Will you come to the publishing department upstairs later?
I understand.
Thanks a lot.
Hello, Ogata-sensei.
Well then I'll...
Okay, I'm going home.
I just thought he would motivate you.
Hmph! That's funny. To chase after me with his skills?
Then, I'll move forward far beyond him, so that he'll never reach me.
I won't let him come near me!
He's motivated you plenty.
What an interesting existence he is.
So he'll get pummeled here for awhile as Insei....
Hurry up and come to the world of the pros...
No...
Will he be able to come at all?
What's going on?
Imanishi-kun! Wait!
What is with his attitude? Just over losing?
You were Imanishi's opponent just now right?
Yeah.
Did he make a stupid mistake somewhere?
Yup. A total miscalculation.
Maybe he's irritated because the High school entrance exams are coming up.
Oh, Arigatou.
He said his grades at school were dropping.
Of course, if I had time, I'd be studying Go.
And if it pays off and we become pro, it's all fine, but he's still in second class.
And he lost to someone like Shindou because of a stupid mistake, no wonder he's irritated.
Why you...
Hey, Touya doesn't study for school either right?
But he's in Kaiou Jr. High, he must be really smart.
Yeah! Doesn't that irritate you?
It doesn't really irritate me but...
It's irritating! He passed the pro exams in one shot too!
He'll be appearing in the new first dan series soon.
New first dan series?
You really don't know anything do you?
The new first dan series are matches between people who just passed the pro exams, and the top pros.
It's to encourage new pros.
Encouragement huh?
You start as a pro in April, but we have a match like this before then.
Last Tuesday, there was a match between Kuwabara-sensei and Mashiba-san!
Mashiba-san?
He was an Insei.
Hmm... so he passed the pro exams.
When Isumi-san and Waya failed.
You be quiet.
How did the match go?
He resigned helplessly before Kuwabara-sensei.
Oh...
Touya should have it soon too.
He keeps on moving forward doesn't he?
It's not just Touya.
Everyone who passed the pro exams keeps moving forward.
We Insei, don't move forward at all unless we pass the pro exams.
Who is it?
Down!
Hey who is it?
That was Zama-sensei! Ouza!
Ouza?
That's one of the titles.
You should know the titles at the very least.
Zama-sensei! Perfect timing.
What?
The day for your match against the new first dan has been decided.
We'll send a notice for it.
Who's my opponent?
It's Touya Akira. The Meijin's son.
Oh Touya... him?
I've heard about him.
He's supposedly really strong according to the players studying under Touya-Meijin.
Of course they won't say anything bad.
The new first dan series...
How have they been going? A sweep by us experienced pros?
No there are losses as well.
Hmm... so they're letting the new players feel some glory.
It is a festival of sorts.
Then maybe I'll let him win by half a moku too.
I'm sure everyone will like it.
"Touya Akira makes a great start as a pro," your headlines will read better.
Well the publishers may appreciate it but...
Oh yes, Kuwabara-sensei played it a few days ago didn't he?
Yes. His opponent was Mashiba-kun, and he used to be Insei.
I'd like this please.
Maybe he got nervous because he was playing Kuwabara-sensei,
or maybe he went out of it because of the room of Yuugen, but he defeated himself.
Kuwabara-sensei went "Huh?" when Mashiba-kun resigned, as if he played the game half asleep.
I feel sorry for that boy.
Kuwabara-sensei can be quite a bully at times.
Well, I'm hoping for a great games between a hopeful new pro, and one of the top pros right now.
Events for today
Public Match Room
Mid Kyu Class
New First Dan Series
Use for matches
What!? Today!?
Did you read the sign outside?
There's a match between Touya and the Ouza today in the room of Yuugen in the afternoon.
I wanna see!
You can.
There's a camera in the room of Yuugen during matches,
and you can watch it on a monitor.
It'll be shown on that TV.
We have our own matches, so we can't watch all of it.
But you can catch at least the second half after your Insei matches are over.
Oh... I can't watch all of it.
While we're here, wanna look at the room of Yuugen as well?
What!? We're allowed?
Here, this is the room of Yuugen.
It's so dark, I can't see anything.
Hikaru...
Sai...?
Maybe I feel it because of the state I'm in...
but the air here stings me.
Enough to make me smile from quivering in anticipation.
How is it? Isn't it awesome?
Do the pros always play in places like this?
No. They usually play in the main room where we play.
Rooms like these are used only for title matches.
Oh.
Using this room today, is kind of like encouraging them to work hard so that they can play a real game in here.
Next year, I too will...
We'll be taking a memorial picture before the match.
Take some extras. He may become big in the future.
Gotcha.
Could you face each other and converse a little?
Converse he said Touya-kun.
I'll be fighting you with all my strength today. My regards to you.
Oh, you have my regards as well.
Don't be scared by my title of Ouza.
We're all the same once we're pro. You can't win if you lose emotionally.
Come at me thinking that I'm a new pro just like you.
Yes. I intend to do so.
He intends to do so? How arrogant of him.
Could you look this way please?
Change of plans...
I'll crush him.
Has Touya's match started yet?
Hikaru, concentrate on the match before you for now!
I-I know!
This is the first time you've been in the room of Yuugen right Touya-kun?
No, it's my first time.
It may be your first time playing, but you've been in here before at least right?
Your father is a regular here. Have you never come with him?
No, not even once.
You've never even sat here to keep time or record the moves?
I was not an Insei, so I've never kept time or records.
What? You were never an Insei?
Oh! But jobs like that come to new pros too right?
I'd better learn how to do it by April.
Heh! How annoying, feel at least a little nervous.
It's time, so we'll begin the match.
The new pro will move first, and Komi is a reverse-komi, 5.5 moku.
You each have 2 hours.
After you use it, you have a minute per move on the byouyomi.
Well then. Good luck.
Good luck.
What? Ashiwara-sensei!
Hello.
Oh yes! Ashiwara-sensei studies under Touya-Meijin!
I'm Touya-kun's friend. The closest to him in age too. All of Touya-kun's friends are adults.
Is that why?
He's really calm. Every new pro I've seen so far have been nervous or not confident,
but he's neither.
Oh yes, Mashiba-kun, you were frozen stiff.
Kuwabara-sensei was really scary.
Kuwabara-sensei slammed the stones onto the board really load on his first move.
Hehe, you can't be getting swallowed up by such obvious scare tactics.
Kuwabara-sensei's just the type of person to do it.
Well, let's see what happens with today's match.
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Wow, Yuki, you captured so many.
That hurts, doesn't it, Mai?
Yes.
When your stones are captured in a star-shaped pattern,
we call it shicho (ladder).
As Black escapes, create atari.
If Black escapes again, create another atari.
If this continues, Black cannot escape.
If you get caught in a shico, give up as soon as possible and look for a better move.
To be continued
Touya...
you're telling me to come all this way right?
Not yet...
I won't defend just yet.
Touya won't let it end here, with the way he's been playing up to now!
I'll show you!
Each of my moves!