この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
What's wrong, Sai?
Hikaru, your move here looks like something I might play.
You can tell?
I played there after thinking about what you might do.
My match against Waya,
Might be tougher than my match against Ochi.
While Ochi's already passed,
Waya is just a step away from passing, so he is going to be more desperate.
I'm a little scared of playing him.
Let's fight.
If I turn this area under white's influence into my territory, your loss is definite.
If black lives, you win.
Forty-fourth match
A Desperate Life
The Twenty-Sixth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Become... a pro!
I can win.
So long as I don't move too quickly and make a mistake.
I've passed...
Master!
Hikaru...
What's wrong, Shindou?
You're thinking?
I...
I resign...
Honda-san...
The small chance that Honda-san had of passing...
disappeared...
Sorry...
I'll walk.
Oh, okay.
A walk might do you some good.
Hey, you can try again next year. It's okay.
Now... There's Shindou and me and... Isumi-san.
Two of us will pass.
I will be one of them!
Honda-san has failed but...
I'll pass with this match!
I'm going to become a pro!
Come on.
Play anywhere you'd like, Shindou!
I'll kill your stones, no matter where you play.
It's a difficult and hard to see path.
But, there is a way that black can live.
I can't find a way to live...
But...
Sai would...
If it was Sai...
He would find a way for black to live in all this space.
Let's say if Sai was...
Let's say that Sai were in my shoes...
And...
Yeah... and let's say that I'm Waya.
I'm playing just like Waya is right now.
and I'll think just like Waya is thinking.
Can I kill this black or not?
Is there a way that black can live?
There's no way for black to live.
There isn't.
There is no way to live... anywhere.
But...
If I look up at Sai...
He'll... Sai will...
I've considered that already.
It won't work.
I didn't see this!
I didn't think of this...
Can black live now?
No... it can't be...
He saw it. Hikaru's found it,
the only path there is.
If... Hikaru doesn't make a mistake.
Black will live!
Hikaru's reached it...
The only path he can take to life.
If I connect, he'll make an eye in the center.
But I have to connect in the corner.
He's managed to make it live...
I can't kill it.
The black stones that I thought I had killed... has life!
Listen, you WILL pass!
I'll say it as many times as I have to.
You WILL pass!
Have faith in yourself, Waya.
Become a pro!
Master!
I resign.
Hikaru has...
completely surpassed Waya with this match.
Thanks for the game.
Thanks for the game...
Sai...
We... talked about a good player on the net called Sai. Remember?
On the day we first played each other.
On that day I...
said that you might become as strong as Sai one day, remember?
Yeah... I remember.
You played... as well as Sai today.
Thanks.
Just as Waya said, Hikaru is getting very strong.
Okay!
Only Ochi is left!
First, tell me how it went today.
If you're talking about me, I won.
Oh, congratulations. Now you've passed with the best score.
Like it matters to you.
It does.
It shows how strong you are.
I'm glad.
And, Shindou's strength will...
be shown by his match against me.
And? Shindou?
He won.
He's still at three losses.
Oh...
Just as I thought.
Touya only cares about Shindou.
Even though I passed with the best record this year.
Ochi-kun.
Good evening.
Mr. Touya! Thank you for all your help!
Kousuke was able to pass with the best record, thanks to you.
Oh, please sit.
Thank you.
Well, I'm thinking about having a celebration for him passed the exam.
Celebrate passing?
Yes, it would be great if you could come too, Mr. Touya.
Let's talk about that after Kousuke-kun has won the last match.
Yes... we shouldn't increase the number of losses,
even though he has already passed.
But, it almost sounds like you doubt that Kousuke can win.
Umm...
Well, you should never under estimate your opponent.
That is true but...
Can't you put more faith in Kousuke's abilities?
Is your opponent for the last round that strong?
Kousuke?
Shindou isn't...
You'll lose if you under estimate him!
Then, if I win the last match,
will you recognize me as your rival?
If I win, let me go to Touya Meijin's study sessions!
Okay. I'll ask my father, if that happens.
That's great. That's wonderful.
It's the perfect place for Kousuke to learn in the future.
I believe that Ogata 9-dan, who is just now on the rise, was studying there, too.
What a wonderful prize that is.
Work hard, Kousuke!
Shindou... let's play!
The Final Match of the Pro Exam Finals
I feel sorry for Waya, but... Fuku has the advantage.
Yeah.
Not only is Waya weak against Fuku, but he's under a lot of pressure, too.
Then... it'll be a playoff between Isumi-kun and Waya.
There's Shindou too.
Who do you think will win between Shindou and Ochi?
I think Shindou has the advantage.
Ochi has already passed,
he doesn't have to go for the win forcefully.
I disagree.
Why?
Think about Ochi's personality.
Even though he has a loss from Isumi-san,
he was trying to go undefeated!
Yeah...
I guess he won't let himself lose to Shindou for nothing.
If the two of them go at it full strength...
If they go at it?
Fifty-fifth I think.
FIFTY-FIFTY!?
You must think very highly of Shindou.
Sensei...
About the playoff...
There was Isumi-kun, with four losses.
And Waya-kun and Shindou-kun, both at three losses.
There may be one depending on how they do today.
There's a good chance of it.
If either Waya-kun or Shindou-kun loses today...
The three of them would all have four losses,
and we would have a three-way playoff.
If that happens, we'll determine the pairings by lottery.
We'll have the first match tomorrow, the second match...
It would be a lot of trouble.
Shindou! How long have you been there?
A while...
Then you should have said 'Hi'!
How can I, when you're talking about me?
Y-Yeah, morning...
Hey...
Shindou...
Never mind...
Is there anyone in the match hall?
I think Fuku's there.
I don't think Isumi-kun and the others are here yet.
Thanks.
What were you about to say to Shindou?
He's going to pass if he wins today.
so I was about to say, "Try your best". But, I didn't.
There's no point in saying that now.
Shindou knows best, exactly how important this match is...
and we're the ones that need to try harder.
What should I do next year?
Shall we go to the match hall?
Actually, let's go outside and do some stretching.
Ochi...
Shindou... I'm not going to lose today.
Why are you so quiet?
Say something back to him, like 'that's my line!'
T-That's my li...
I played against Touya every night.
Just to beat you.
Touya...
played Ochi!?
So...
I'm going to win today!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
The anime for Hikaru no Go has been broadcast in Taiwan since June.
A press conference was held for it the other day in Taipei.
Children from the Taiwan Go Institute were invited, along with the press, and various VIPs.
The show is very interesting to watch...
and if people learn Go, and Go becomes popular because of it, it would be great.
I hope the children who watch the anime will one day become and play others in other countries.
The dream will spread.
To be continued...
I have Touya standing behind me!
Is there anyone standing behind you, Shindou?
Then, Touya's going to recognize me as his rival if I beat you, right?
Damn it! I won't let it end like this!