この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
You seem to be concerned about Shindou.
Is there something about him?
You'll be playing Shindou on the last day right?
If you'd like, I can come here until then whenever I can.
You just want to see how strong Shindou is by using me!
I've got to work extra hard this year.
I have to graduate this year after all.
You'll be playing Isumi-san tomorrow.
It's your turn, Sai.
You'll lose if you don't pay attention to the game.
Hikaru, your opponent for today is here.
Thirty-ninth match
The Dead Moment
The Twelfth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Morning.
Y-y-yeah...
Y-y-yeah?
But...
It's important match to both Isumi-san, who's undefeated, and myself, who has one loss.
Only three people can pass the pro exams...
Morning...
I guess it can't be helped that you're both nervous.
Let's go to the match hall, Sai.
Okay.
Okay! I'm going to grab another win today!
Yes.
If I lose today... I'll have two losses...
I want to stay at one loss.
Isumi-san hasn't played the rest of them yet either.
With Hikaru's match today,
the top players are going to start playing each other.
It's time, so please go to the match hall.
I still haven't played Honda-san, Adachi-san, Waya, or Ochi yet.
I'm going to gain some momentum by beating Isumi-san today!
Hikaru, that's the spirit.
Good morning, please get started.
I'm going to grab another win...
A win.
What are you looking at?
Did you write something on your hand?
I-It's nothing.
Please begin.
A match between someone undefeated and someone with one loss...
I don't need Iijima or Komiya to tell me.
I know that Shindou's getting stronger.
But I am confident that I'm stronger than Shindou.
Would you have preferred ice tea?
Oh, thank you.
It's already the 12th match.
Not as many people are in the running now.
You're right.
I think it may be difficult for some people to pass.
I wonder how the top players are going to do.
There was a match between someone who's undefeated and someone with one loss today wasn't there?
The undefeated boy is Isumi-kun, and he's strong enough to be the number one Insei.
But just being the top Insei doesn't guarantee that you pass right?
No, it doesn't. Last year Isumi-kun...
They always trip up somewhere...
Not everything goes well even if your strong...
That happens sometimes.
There are some boys who pass the wall easily because they have some momentum.
Mashiba-kun was like that last year.
But anyways, losing confidence is the worst thing you can do.
Oh, look at the time.
I'll go get the lunches we ordered.
Yes, please do so.
It's time for lunch so please halt your clocks.
You still have a good chance Hikaru.
I know.
Shindou...
So Isumi-san's black.
Shindou's at a bit of a disadvantage.
But they haven't progressed at all.
Isumi-san's already used more than half his time!
Isumi-san, you're done already?
Yes.
The atmosphere gets so gloomy when the finals are half way through.
They're all facing their critical games soon.
I'm gonna go get some fresh air.
It's already hot outside today.
You sound like an old man Isumi-san.
One, two!
Shindou...
Okay, now stick your arms out forward!
Yeah!
One, two!
Hey, Sai I've had enough.
No! You have to do some stretching and clear your mind.
I can't win against you.
I can't win? He's giving up already?
I guess Isumi-san is going to win after all.
Okay! Hikaru say it out loud energetically!
One, two!
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven!
I'll be playing Isumi-san tomorrow.
But I have to win my match today before that.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven!
One, two... three, four.
Isumi-san, I looked at your match clock.
You seem to be playing very cautiously.
What's so strange about playing cautiously against Shindou? He only has one loss.
You're not scared of him are you?
What is it all of a sudden?
I was wondering if you had an over inflated opinion of Shindou too, Isumi-san.
Are you talking about how Iijima and Komiya said that Shindou's gotten stronger?
Shindou is stronger than them, so what's surprising about them saying that?
It's not just them. I met Touya Akira the other day.
Touya!?
I learn Go by calling pros to my house.
My grandpa called Touya Akira the other day.
All he asked me about was Shindou.
As if he wanted information about a rival.
When I told him, that the last time I played Shindou was three months ago.
He said "that's far in the past."
What do you think Isumi-san?
Isumi-san?
Far in the past? That may be right.
He has...
He forcefully made himself third board to play me.
Forcefully?
That's the kind of guy he is.
It's true! I'm his and he's my rival!
Everyone thought that it was just the new kid making up a story to make himself look bigger.
When Touya was looking at Shindou's match during the Wakajishisen,
I thought he just happened to be looking at the match behind him.
But now, Ochi is saying that Touya Akira kept asking about Shindou.
Then does Touya really think of Shindou as his rival?
It can't be!
No, I thought it may be true.
Ever since I saw the match between Shindou and Hong Su-Young.
That move that everyone thought was a mistake.
That bad move Shindou made, he made it for the fight on the top left!?
I'm not confident that I could have beaten the Shindou from that game.
I don't know how far I could have gone against Su-Young either.
Who could have imagined it back when Shindou first became an Insei?
That he would become this strong.
Touya! Did he?
Maybe Touya knew...
Maybe he knows what Shindou is going to become!
Is Touya chasing after...
the Shindou of the future!?
My last opponent was so bad, I was wondering why he was even taking the exam.
Not just me either. I thought he was here just to give a win to everyone taking the exam.
He was horrible.
Isumi-san.
Waya...
Let's go to the match hall. The afternoon's about to begin.
Yeah...
No. Don't lose confidence.
Isumi-san...
Shindou just happened to play better than usual when he played against Su-Young.
Don't lose confidence!
It's time, please begin.
Only three people can pass...
I came through this very same path thirty years ago.
Good luck to you all.
Thanks for the game.
Well, let's see how Shindou and Isumi-san are...
They're still playing.
Isumi-san is winning.
Shindou must be desperate.
What!? Byouyomi!?
Isumi-san's already used all his time.
Now he has to play each move in a minute.
I doubt that he'll make a mistake due to lack of time...
Shindou has gotten stronger...
But not enough for Touya to get worried.
I don't need Touya's help to win.
Isumi-san is more important. I'll play Isumi-san next week.
But I will play Waya before that...
I need to watch out for Waya too...
He seems to be doing well, defeating Honda-san and all...
I'll go take a look at Waya.
I see the goal.
Don't panic.
It's already difficult for Shindou to come back.
Calm down. What do you have to be worried about?
I've got to work extra hard this year. I have to graduate this year after all.
Shindou Hikaru!
My name is...
I just need to keep playing like this.
Don't worry about them!
Don't worry about the shadows of Touya and Su-young that I see behind Shindou.
I came to atari in the wrong place...
That's so stupid, why did I go atari from the left?
It's obvious that I should go to atari from the right here.
I intended to do so, but I was worried about Touya and Su-young and...
Sai... didn't his fingers leave the stone just now?
Sai, did you see?
Playing somewhere else after your fingers leave the stone... That's an automatic loss.
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Continuing from last week... Yuki, you try it now.
Okay!
I'll take this one.
Then... I'll go here.
And if I take these?
Huh?
And again?
It's over...
Mai, you try it next.
Okay!
I'll start here.
I'll take these.
There here next.
I'll take that, too.
And then here.
Correct!
You'll improve greatly by working on tsumego problems.
Try solving lots of different problems.
To be continued
Should I not ask Isumi-san?
If his fingers left the stone?
It'll cost you dearly if you've cracked emotionally.
No one here is going to take it easy on you.
Don't you want to finish the game?
I might win if I say something!
I want the win!