Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
I resign.
I thought... I saw the hand of god in you...
Fifteenth match
The Player on the Net
How was this?
Should I simply have connected here?
But what if he went to atari from here?
Is teacher Akira taking the pro exam?
Yeah, seems like it.
I heard about it from Muroi-san this morning.
Is it true Ichikawa-san?
Really!? That's big news.
The world of Go's going to be exciting starting next year.
It sure was sudden though. I completely thought he wasn't going to take it again this year.
Did something happen to Teacher Akira?
Who knows?
I asked him how his Go club at school was because he stopped talking about it but...
"It doesn't matter anymore, it was just a detour" he said.
Could I get some over here too?
Just a second.
The Fourteenth Annual
NCC Cup Tournament
Fifth game
Hey! The TV broadcast of the NCC cup's about to begin!
If you subscribe to our magazine for an extra year, you will get a special on the subscription fee.
You can even play Go through the internet these days.
Why don't you try it once?
Hmm... 29... Oh here it is!
But is it interesting at all watching a match from this far away?
A pro player uses a big board and explains each move for us.
Don't the people playing the game find it annoying? Having people talk so loudly right next to them.
I'm sure they enjoy it.
Wow! What a Go board!
Great, seems like Sai's enjoying himself.
It's about to begin.
Greetings ladies and gentlemen of the audience, and everyone watching on TV.
We are about to begin the fifth game of the first match of the fourteenth annual NCC Cup Go tournament,
between Fujisawa Kikou 9-dan and Takada Kouichi 7-dan.
The game will be explained by Murase 9-dan and the moves will be read out by Yoshinaga 2-dan.
Let's get on with the game now.
Well, Murase 9-dan, what do you think will be the most interesting point of our game today?
Well, Fujisawa 9-dan has a seat in both the Meijin League and the Honinbou league...
I did something horrible to Sai...
I did play his match against Touya instead of him...
Touya...
I'll try it! I can't see it until I play myself!
I want to know the gap between him and I!
Stop messing around!
What I did was bad to Touya too...
He wanted to play against Sai so badly...
Hmm... How interesting, what an exciting development.
Will he go around here next?
25 seconds, 6, 7, 8...
4-12... hmm...
Wow, you were right!
I'm not explaining the game for nothing you know?
But what will I do now?
I want to let Sai play every now and then, but he's so strong.
It'll make me the master of winning through luck.
This is becoming a fierce battle.
10 seconds, 1, 2, 3, 4...
4-13
Ohh... he went here?
Oh oops, I haven't been paying attention at all.
Has this stone been killed?
Yes, but, maybe he could have gone to atari from this side as well...
Let's try playing it out.
This hand here... and this...
Are we going to keep on watching this Tsutsui-san?
Keep on watching... but it's not over yet!
I'm gonna hang around the lobby for a bit.
Hikaru!
I'm at the limit, I can't just sit around any more.
But!
I was looking forward to today so much!
Sai...
Look they're selling books about Go.
Looks like they're playing Go on the PC over there.
Hey, Sai, let's take a look at it.
Did your dad or someone else bring you here?
No, I came with a friend.
Wow, you don't see much of that these days.
Do you have a computer at home?
No, I don't.
Are you interested in stuff like the internet at all?
Internet?
Yeah, this kid is playing someone over the internet right now.
He's black and, look, his opponent just played a white stone, and now he plays a black stone.
Hey, if you play there...
See?
What do you think you're doing?
This isn't a computer game!
I've got to apologize.
I'm sorry for ending the game so suddenly...
What does it say?
Hey jerk off!! Don't quit the game just because I captured a bunch of your stones! Moron!
He typed something in first...
Wow, it's interesting!
I wonder if this person is a child.
A child?
He's a child?
Given what he said, and his nickname, he might be a child.
Nickname?
It's a fake identity that you use on the internet.
Zelda... huh?
Wow there are kids too?
Neither your face, name, nor age gets revealed on the internet, so you don't know.
It's not just kids, look, people from other nations are here too!
JPN is for Japan, CHN is China, CAN is Canada.
There's USA, and GER.
What about NLD?
It's the Netherlands.
People on this list challenge each other or are challenged be each other for games.
It's easy to operate.
Like if you want to play a game, do this here...
Then you do this...
Wanna try?
Nah, not yet. But could you teach me some more about operating it?
You have to register first, right?
Wanna start at loading this homepage first then?
They can't tell your face, age, or real name!
First enter in world Igo net and try a search.
This is it!
Sorry for making you play someone so weak.
Nah, it's okay.
And if white goes here?
Here right?
Here?
Yup.
Here? Or Here?
Once you've come this far, it doesn't matter.
This is okay right?
Huh? Just the two of you?
What about Shindou-kun?
He said something about internet.
Internet? Already?
Already?
I went to watch a public pro match with Shindou-kun yesterday, but...
He got tired of sitting around, and left half way through.
Why is that?
What was Hikaru doing then?
He was doing something on the internet.
I'm not sure what drew him.
But they were displaying internet Go in the lobby,
and he listened to the guy's explanation the entire time.
Until I came out after the pro match.
But where did he go to to access the internet?
You can do it at this store that Mitani's sister is working at.
Mitani's sister?
My sister's working at an internet cafe part-time.
He rushed out of here when I told him where it was.
Tsutsui-san, you wanna play?
No, that's okay.
Here you go.
Fujisaki-san, are you starting to understand Go?
Yup, I just learned shichou and geta.
It's off the subject but, it's almost summer, what will we do with the club?
I have summer school so I'm kinda busy.
Oh yeah, Tsutsui-san has to prepare for High School entrance exams.
From the way Hikaru was acting earlier, Hikaru'll probably be on the internet the entire time.
I'll... go to that Go salon again.
I'll go to that Go school that Hikaru went to.
And once second quarter begins, I'm gonna get some female members.
I want to go to the tournaments too.
You can compete in individual matches too.
No! A group match is better!
I thought so when I was watching you guys play.
A group match is definitely more fun!
You're right...
We lost to Kaiou but it was fun.
Yeah, group matches are nice.
Hey let's meet at least once a week during the summer!
Yeah, I can make it once a week at least.
Yeah.
Experience
the
internet
here!
State-of-the-art
systems
available.
World Igo net?
I just have to access this?
But even if I know about computers, I know nothing about Go.
That's okay, I learned how to play on my own.
World Igo net.
And search!
Let's see...
Oh, this, right?
You can play against people from all over the world here.
All over the world? But do you speak English?
I don't have to speak English, all I'm doing is playing Go.
Hikaru. You were looking at a box like this yesterday too. Though it was flatter...
Yeah, but the inside's the same.
But, what are you trying to do?
I thought I'd let you play all the Go you want.
Huh? Hikaru, what did you just say?
Well, wait and see.
Hey, where did Mitani learn Go?
From our late grandfather.
When he was in grade school he had a teacher that knew how to play, and they played each other a lot.
After he graduated, he started going to Go salons.
Is Yuuki good?
Yeah he is!
You didn't know?
Oh really!? What about you?
Me? I'm... okay I guess.
You're only okay and your playing people from all over the world through the internet?
Yeah, thanks.
Sorry, sorry. I guess your skill doesn't matter.
You can handle the rest, right?
Hey, can I really play for free?
Yeah, it's fine. But don't tell anyone. And you can't when I'm not working here.
Okay, thanks!
Call me when you're about to leave.
Then, later.
Well, gotta get a nickname first.
Hey, all I want? Really?
The name will be...
S...
A...
I...
Sai!
Well, let's go.
I'll be in Japan next month for about a week Mom.
Yeah, I was chosen as the representative for the US for the International Amateur Go Tournament.
Yeah, about 50 nations.
One rep for each nation. I became number one in the nation during tryouts.
Of course, Asia is strong. Japan, China, and Korea.
The US? We were eighth last year.
But we're rising in strength every year, thanks to the internet.
We can play someone strong when ever we want.
And I hear that Japan is getting weaker these days.
Yeah, I'll do my best.
Oh, a challenge right as I was about to hang up.
Well then Mom, take care.
Sai? I've never seen this name before.
Well, let's see how strong he is.
Oh, here he comes.
Master! Could I get a tutoring game...
The Master's training through the internet right now for the International Amateur Go Tournament next month.
Too bad... I have no choice then.
I'll play you instead though.
Yeah, yeah, thanks.
Were no match for the master at all.
He's the rep for the Netherlands two years in a row! He's incredible!
He was sixth last year! Sixth!
He might be able to break Asia's control this year!
But what about his real job?
He's so intent on Go he even opened a class like this.
Yeah you're right, he might get fired from his position as Assistant Professor.
Master?
Oh! He's a pro! He's a pro!
That's gotta be it!
You can't tell who it is over the internet.
I heard that Asian pros sometimes play over the internet amongst amateurs to kill time.
Master?
Master...
Did you lose?
I was slaughtered!
I thought I'd get a heart attack from how badly I lost.
Huh? His name's off the list now.
I'd never heard of him before....
I doubt any of my contacts over the net will know who he is either...
Sai... I wonder who he is...
Wasn't that fun!?
Yup!
Okay! We're gonna come to play on the net everyday for the rest of the summer!
What!? You're going to let me play everyday!?
Yeah. I'm gonna make you play until you get sick and tired of it!
Yeah!
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Last time, we talked about choosing for color.
Today, we'll discuss another important topic.
Once you have decided Black and White through nigiri,
Black must spot White 5 and 1/2 points.
This is called komi.
In Go, the player who goes first has an advantage,
so by giving 5 and 1/2 points of compensation, the advantage disappears.
What do you mean by a half point?
It means half of one point.
Take a look at this board.
This is after the territory has been calculated.
Black has 25 moku, or points.
White has 20 moku.
Adding the komi gives White 25 and 1/2 points.
That makes White the winner by half a point.
The half point is there to eliminate ties.
To be continued
Teacher, there's someone really strong...
How peculiar.
Why can we play Go with so many people with a box like this?
The internet is so much fun.
Okay, let's play him!
Where are you... Sai?