Who is it!?
This is not the best move...
or the strongest move...
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
First match
The Eternal Rival
Run Akari!
My grandpa's house is right there!
I knew we should've gone straight home!
Grandpa!? Grandpa!
We're coming in!
Is it really okay?
None of these look really valuable.
Hikaru! Let's leave!
It's creepy in here!
Are you sure you can do this?
I have no choice, I only got 8 points on the last social studies test.
And my parent stopped my allowance.
Hey how about this?
I know this! It's the table you use for gomoku narabe right?
Gomoku narabe is a simple game in Japan where you try to get a straight line of 5 stones on a go board. Since the game is simple and played on a go board, Akari thinks that a go board is for Gomoku Narabe / "Connect 5".
It looks really old.
Maybe grandpa used it when he was young.
Maybe I can get quite the pretty penny for this.
Are you sure this is okay?
It's fine, it's fine.
I'm sure Grandpa doesn't even know it's here.
And if I wipe the dust off of this...
But why isn't this stain coming off?
Huh? There aren't any stains... It's pretty.
This right here.
Where?
Here!
Huh? There's nothing... where are you pointing to!
It's right here!
Can you see it?
I've been telling you, I can...
Can you hear my voice!?
You can hear my voice, can't you?
No there aren't any stains...
Who is it!?
Hikaru! Quit joking around!
I found someone. I finally found someone!
Is it you, Grandpa!? Come on out...
I-I'm going home!
The gods before me, I thank you.
I...
I will now, once again...
return to the living world.
What's wrong? Hikaru!
Hikaru!
Grandpa! Something's wrong with Hikaru!
Who are you?
Fujiwarano Sai.
Sai?...
What are you?
I taught the emperor Go at the capital during the Heian period.
Day after day,
I played Go and I was very happy.
However, the emperor had another tutor of Go.
One day he declared to the emperor...
Only one tutor is necessary.
We should play a match, and the victor should continue as the tutor.
And you guys played right?
Who won?
The match proceeded evenly.
It really was unbelievable that under the gaze of so many men, I was the only one who noticed it.
A white stone was mixed into his goke.
Goke is the container for the go stones that each player uses during the match.
He saw a moment of chance,
Agehama is the container for the stones that were captured during the game. Since captured stone come into play during the final scoring, placing extra stones or removing stones from the agehama is cheating.
and placed that stone into his own agehama!
So he cheated?
When I was about to bring this up...
You, you just...
YOU!
You just placed a mixed in stone from your goke into your agehama! Didn't you!?
Wh...
What are you saying?
That is what you just did!
What a pathetic excuse!
You took a moment of chance when everyone was concentrating on the board to place an extra stone into your agehama!
You're lying!
Be quiet.
I don't even wish to think that such a despicable act has occurred before me.
Continue the game.
I lost...
With a charge of cheating added to my name as well, I was run out of the capital.
Without my livelihood, I had no reason to live.
Two days later...
I drowned myself.
I still wanted to play Go, I wanted to play much more.
Unable to seek solace, my spirit possessed a Go board,
There is a small ocean south of Honshuu, Japan called the Setonaikai. He is referring to that ocean and an island within that ocean there.
and after a great length of time,
I heard the voice of a boy on an island within the sea of Seto.
His name was Tora-jirou.
Child...
If you can see the tears of grief that I shed...
please allow me to inhibit a corner of your heart.
Torajirou changed his name to Shuusaku...
and took the place of his master at the age of 20.
At the age of 14, he took the name of Honinbou Shuusaku.
Honinbou... Shuusaku?
However, he fell due to the plague and one night, at the youthful age of 34, he...
The blood on the Go board must have been his.
And you possessed me, because you wish to play more Go?
Yes...
because I still have not obtained the hand of the god yet!
Hikaru!
I heard you rode in an ambulance!?
Hikaru?
Hikaru? Are you really okay?
What happened yesterday?
Well, I don't remember all too clearly myself,
when I came to, it was today already.
Please pass the test back.
Okay you may begin now.
Fill in the blanks in the following passage with the appropriate code from the word bank.
This year, the new government reset the year to _ Declaring Tokyo as the _ they decided upon the capital of the nation. In the rural areas, the ongoing _ was stopped and _ was started. The _ that the government started. This is called _ The feudal system was destroyed, and people gained the freedom of movement, this is called _
Then in 1868 the government declared a new direction of governing and gave power to the people, this is called _ The fifteenth generation general _ returned the governing of the nation to _ This is called _
Read the following passages and choose the correct one. Circle the blank. _ Revolutionizing the school system, the program giving all children the right to go to elementary and middle school _ Newspapers and Magazines were allowed, but Christianity was forbidden _ The sea was filled to increase land area, and industry and residence was developed. _ Through Healthcare, the populace was treated for disease _ In order to create a greater army, military factories were created, and industry was promoted. _ In order to get enough taxes, the feudal lords were demanded to pay taxes for the land.
A) Emperor B) Tokugawa Government C) Daimei D) Rural areas E) Feudal Government F) Sanpou G) Taisei Henkyaku H) General I) Chigato J) Freedom of the Rural Areas K) Meiji L) Taishin M) ID O) Raku P) Go Q) Haimatsu Shobun R) Everyone is equal S) The 5 declarations.
Oh, history problems I see...
You!
What is it?
Umm... No...
I'm sorry...
Sit back down and continue the test.
Yes ma'am.
The thing that happened to me yesterday wasn't a dream!
No, it wasn't.
And what was your name again?
It is Sai.
Oh, Sai?
Do you really love Go that much?
Yes!
Do you still want to play Go?
Oh I'm sorry, I have no intentions of playing Go.
Hikaru!
Shindou-kun!
What the heck did you do!?
I didn't do anything! Really!
Hikaru are you okay?
Shindou-kun!
Shindou-kun are you okay?
Do you want to go to the nurse's office?
No, I'm okay now.
The grief I felt from the thought that I can't play Go,
simply encompassed your awareness...
Your love of the game's held out for a thousand years? That's impressive.
But I have my own plans for my life.
Are you sure you can't move onto someone other than me?
Probably not...
Fine
If I only have to play every now and then I'll deal with it.
BUT! my mind is my own.
And also, don't talk to me unless you're spoken to.
Okay!
Hmm...
Who was it again?
10 minutes remaining.
If you're done already, you should check over your answers again for mistakes.
I can't do it.
Sai do you know anything about the revolution of the Tempou?
Revolution of the Tempo? The one that Roujyuu no Miizuno-sama started?
Yeah Yeah! That's the one.
What a fond memory. We played Go once within the castle.
Do you know anything about Perry?
Perry?
Perry!? You know? He lead a couple of warships here?
Oh! Commodore Perry!
Yeah! That's the one. Where did that Commodore Perry come to?
He came to Uraga. There was a huge commotion over that incident.
Uraga...
Sai.
Yes?
You're pretty useful sometimes.
Shindou-kun why are you talking to yourself?
Are you done with the test?
I'm almost done.
Good luck.
She passed through my body without an apology!
How rude!
Hikaru are all the women of this age...
Okay, okay, just don't yell so loudly in my head.
I'll take you somewhere where you can play Go as soon as this is over.
Wow! There are so many people here.
This is Tokyo after all.
And, and... Where are we playing Go?
A Go salon.
My grandpa goes there every now and then.
It's a place where all the old folks from the neighborhood go to play Go.
No matter what period it is, there are always Go lovers!
Domestic and
International travel
Sky Blue Travel
Tours of various locales -- Rental
Go Salon
Weekdays 1PM~10PM
Weekends 12PM~9PM
6F
Hair Studio
Joy
Oh, hello. Come on in.
Oh wow, it's filled with old people.
Is this your first time here?
Yeah, it's my first time.
Can anyone play here?
Of course.
Okay, write your name here.
How strong are you?
My strength? I'm... not sure.
What?
I've never played anyone, although I'm pretty sure I'm decently strong.
Oh there is kid! Can I play him?
Yeah... but he's...
Are you looking for someone to play?
Sure, I'll play you.
But he's...
Let's go to the back.
Hold it for a sec.
If you're a kid it'll be 500 yen.
What!? I have to pay!?
It's his first time here, can you cut him some slack?
If you say so Akira-kun!
I'm Touya Akira. what's your name?
I'm Shindou Hikaru. 6th grade.
I'm in the 6th grade too!
It is boring playing old folks after all!
How strong are you?
Umm... I'm not sure.
I think I'm pretty strong though.
You're not sure but you think you're strong?
Then why don't you place 4 or 5 stones for a handicap?
A handicap?
I don't need anything like that! We're the same age after all.
No handicap against Touya Akira!?
That's crazy!
Okay. Go ahead first.
I might be a little slow playing, excuse me.
Sai... are you that happy?
It's been more than hundred years...
Hikaru, I'm going to start.
Okay!
17-4, upper-right corner, komoku!
17-...
1, 2, 3, 4...
That's the way a beginner holds a stone...
16-17, lower-right corner, komoku!
16-17...
Here it is.
3-16
16-5
Kosumi is a standard response to a keima attack, prevalent 200 years ago.
Kosumi?
14-4
He holds the stone like a beginner,
but he plays well.
No wonder he claims to be strong.
What's wrong? It's your turn.
Oh, sorry.
But... his joseki is old...
Joseki: A set pattern of moves that brings benefit to both sides.
and sometimes, he slows down at some weird places...
14-11...
Oh here it is.
He doesn't cower to my attacks, no...
it's not just that, he's dodging them easily.
That white stone is yours. Take it off the board.
This?
Yes.
19-15
Is that okay? He took that stone.
18-4
I can take this right?
Yes.
What happened?
That cluster of white has died, those stones will become yours at the end of the game.
All this!? Then we've practically won!
No, he is not that weak.
I did not take that cluster, he threw it away.
Look carefully.
This...
I still have a chance.
That cluster on the upper left was large,
but I control the center.
Is it going to be okay?
Probably
4-13
8-5
8-5...
There it is.
This...
This is not the best move...
or the strongest move...
he's testing me to see how I would respond...
he's measuring my strength...
from a far higher position...
Cya, later.
Thanks!
Oh your game's over.
I guess I'm not ready for a match yet.
It took a really long time to play, and I'm exhausted.
Oh really?
Oh yeah, there's a children's Go tournament soon.
Here...
Why don't you go watch it?
I'll think about it.
Thanks for today!
Come again!
It was 50 years to early for him to go up against Akira, I guess.
What!? You lost!?
That can't be!
Akira-kun lost!?
But Akira-kun is just as strong as a pro though!
You gave him a handicap, right?
What handicap did you give him?
Unlike with Chess, with go, black makes the first move. Since black is considered to have an advantage because of this, 5.5 moku is taken away from Black's final score, this 5.5 moku is called komi. A moku is one intersection on the board.
The other boy played black, and moved first.
What was the result?
He lost by 2 moku.
If it was only 2 moku, he wins after taking away komi.
Moku: one empty intersection on a Go board.
Komi: 5.5 moku handicap that white receives for letting black play first.
It's not a matter of 2, 3 moku.
H-hold on a second.
Akira-kun did you really lose?
Unbelievable...
but he's never played anyone before.
Never...
played...
anyone...
before?
Who the hell is he!?
Oh man I'm tired.
Are you satisfied now Sai?
Yes.
Okay! Then we're doing my history homework as soon as we get back!
Okay!
We're running home.
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
I am Yukari Umezawa.
In this segment, I will be show you how to play Go in an easy-to-understand manner.
Mai, Yuki... I'll be counting on your help.
Onegaishimasu, Sensei!
How is Go played?
To play Go, we need a Go board and Go stones.
Go board
Go stone (black)
Go stone (white)
We take turns placing black and white stones on the board.
Now then, you two..
Try placing stones on the board.
Okay!
That would be correct for other games,
but in Go, we place the stones where the lines intersect.
Let's try it.
To be continued
That move,
and that move...
it was a tutoring match.
If that's his real talent...
There can't possibly be a child like that.
Who the hell is he?
I finally found you... Shindou Hikaru!