Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Kaiou's first board!
Do you have time?
Twentieth match
The Road to Becoming Pro
Hey Kishimoto-kun, it has been awhile.
Hey.
Sit at an empty spot.
I wonder what it is...
he said there was something he wanted to know... and he takes me all this way.
Is it about Touya and me?
But why at a Go salon?
Oh shoot! I forgot to buy the English reference book.
What do you want to know?
Your real strength.
Do you mind?
Wow it's incredible over there. They're really good.
The tall boy, right?
Kishimoto-kun.
He's exceptional.
Bow to him and plead for a game later. He's just that strong.
The tall boy is strong,
But the little boy...
he's very strong too.
You want to know my real strength?
Just you see! Not Sai's, MY STRENGTH!
It won't be like at the tournament, right now I'm...!
About the same as our second board.
The Furikawari over here is a very good idea.
That's not all, you play patiently, and don't rush the game.
Kaiou's first board complimented me.
But you're not strong for Touya to see you as a rival.
Or is there something else to you?
Touya just overestimated me, that's all.
And then, he found out how strong I was and it burst his bubble.
Don't mess around!
Touya...
That's all.
And?
You burst his bubble and that's it?
You still have that certain quality that pulled Touya to you, don't you?
You're not going to chase after Touya?
Well, he is my goal...
I'm sure I'll catch up to him someday.
Quite a gap between you and Touya...
No, I'm not talking about your strength.
I'm talking about your attitude towards reaching your goal.
You don't know what Touya was like in the Kaiou Go club, do you?
Touya really chased after you full strength,
not caring about the people around him.
'I'll catch up someday!"
When is that "someday"?
Touya has already passed the Pro examinations.
Really, Kishimoto-kun?
By Touya he means Touya Akira-kun, right?
That's a round robin tournament lasting two months,
so it should last until the end of the month shouldn't it?
He said to his teacher at school.
Starting in April next year, he's a pro player.
Pro?
You've gotta be kidding, he's only in 7th grade.
Most pros become pro in their teens.
All of the top pros qualify when they're in Junior High.
You didn't know?
Most people don't know about it.
It is a peculiar field of work.
What about school?
They don't go when they have a match.
They don't go? They're allowed to not go?
Their teachers won't get mad?
What a peculiar boy.
Pro...
Pro but...
I thought he wouldn't become pro for a long time...
I didn't think it would be this soon,
I thought it would be when he became an adult and...
Adult?
By that time, Touya will be in a place you can't reach.
April next year, Touya will start his race.
And he will move forward faster than anyone else.
You can't possibly catch up to him unless you desperately run after him starting now.
I... haven't thought about it much...
It thought that I'd get closer to Touya if I just kept playing Go...
Having Touya as your goal while clowning around.
You not only sicken me, you disappoint me as well.
What exactly was it that Touya was chasing after?
Well, it doesn't concern me.
Do you mind if we stop this game?
My advantage won't change.
Sorry for taking up your time.
Kishimoto-kun, another cup of coffee?
No thanks, I'll go home.
The me that Touya chased...
That was...
Sai...
The me right now is all I can be...
Hey, Touya Akira passed with all win, right?
No, he has one loss.
But it was a loss by default.
Loss by default?
I'm not sure why, but he didn't go to the first match.
The last Sunday in August.
Not go to the pro examination? Really!?
The last Sunday in August!?
It's that day! On the internet!
I'm not talking about your strength.
I'm talking about your attitude towards reaching your goal.
Hey!
How do you take the pro examination?
The pro examination occurs once a year. The next one will be summer next year.
Besides, you're not strong enough to become pro, right?
First you should maybe get better by becoming an Insei.
Do you know about Insei? From the Japanese Go Institute?
Yes, yes. Play against good people aim to become pro, and learn about Go.
Then take it.
I'll tell you this,
you're not good enough to even become an Insei right now.
Hikaru...
There's a test to become an Insei too.
The Insei examination occurs four times a year.
The next one is in December, right?
You play against a pro to judge your strength in the Insei examination, right?
Yes. Of course, not just anyone can pass it.
Hikaru...
April next year, Touya will start his race.
And he will move forward faster than anyone else.
Hikaru...
Sai...
They said that was impossible straight to your face...
I won't give up even if it is impossible.
Hikaru!
I can see the distance between Touya and I now.
If I want to reach up to him, I have to pass that Insei examination easily,
and crush all those other Inseis,
and pass the pro examination with all wins!
No matter what Kaiou's first board says, I won't give up!
Because, Sai...
He didn't give up on you!
He was shivering from fear of your strength at the tournament, but he still faced you!
It's not impossible...
It's not impossible.
Yes! This time you will chase after Touya, Hikaru!
Japanese Go Institute
Huh? Hikaru, we came here once before didn't we?
Yeah, when we came to watch the children's tournament.
You're going to learn Go here?
The ones called "Insei" are...
I'm having a hard time picturing it...
Are a lot of guys like Kaiou's first board playing with a scary face?
But Hikaru, you will get better if you play there.
But, I should ask how to take the exam before that.
Everything is a step towards Touya!
Okay Hikaru!
Let's go!
Oh! This! It's what we saw earlier! Those fake fish that look really real!
Oh it's still here! Look Hikaru! Look!
Why you!
The Insei examination for December?
Yeah, we're holding it this Sunday, but we're past the deadline for the applications already.
What!? But! I want to take it now!
You want to take it now... you can't take it in March?
But I came all this way! Let me take it, cheapo!
Cheapo!?
Touya's going to keep on walking forward!
Rules are rules! That's crazy.
But, isn't there anything you can do?
That boy...
Something I can do... but...
What's going on?
Oh, Mr. Ogata.
Huh?
This guy's...
I think I've met him somewhere before.
This boy says he wants to take the Insei exam for First Quarter.
Insei exam? Oh...
We're past the deadline,
and he isn't sponsored by anyone,
and he doesn't even have any Kifu!
He just barged in!
Mr. Ogata we're short on time...
I know that boy,
I'll sponsor him.
Could you let him take it?
Oh... okay.
Excuse me.
Mr. Ogata just who is that boy?
That's what I want to find out.
It's finally going to get revealed...
Oh, now I remember!
That guy! He's the guy that was with Touya-Meijin!
What do you mean by "That guy"! Watch your language!
Oh... sorry.
Really... why did Mr. Ogata sponsor a child like this?
Listen.
This is the Insei application form.
What you need to bring with you on the day is this Insei application form,
and your resume, and three Kifu.
You'll also need to bring the exam processing fee, and the exam match fee.
And have your parents come with you.
Processing fee!? Parents!
Yes. Understand?
Let's see... application form, resume, Kifu...
Kifu? What's a Kifu?
You don't know what a Kifu is!?
What is it?
Oh, a child who doesn't even know what a Kifu is, is trying to take the Insei exam.
You've gotta be kidding. Just tell children like that to go home.
But, Mr. Ogata asked me to help him out so...
Mr. Ogata?
And! What's a Kifu!?
Kifu paper
I see,
Kifu is a record of a game I played...
But how am I supposed to write it down?
Well, I'm sure either Tsutsui-san or Mitani will know.
Your path is getting paved, Hikaru.
Yeah!
Touya... it's a path that leads to you...
Shindou! I got a new member!
New member?
Yeah, come on in!
Hey!
He's called Natsume, he's in my class, he can play a bit.
I just started this summer, so I'm still not very good.
Great! Now we can go to the tournament even if Tsutsui-san can't make it!
Yeah. That's the case.
Hikaru!
Chemistry Lab
A new member? Really!?
Then we can go to the tournament!
We won't just be going there this time.
Shindou's gotten really strong, and I've gotten stronger from playing him.
If we throw away the first board,  and go for two wins between the two of us...!
We can beat Kaiou... Maybe!
What's going on? You're all so happy.
Tsutsui-san!
Oh? A new member?
Yup. Isn't it great!?
Now, both the guys and girls can all head towards the tournament!
Girls too?
Who's your third player?
Remember that girl Hikaru brought before? She said she'll participate in the tournament.
Oh yeah!
There is a girl who actually knows how to play Go!
See, we've got three now.
Hey, Akari, team, does that mean me too?
Yup.
Already!?
It'll be okay,
Oh yeah, Shindou-kun...
But I'm no good at all.
Just have Mitani-kun teach you some more.
This here.
Monthly Go World
This book surprised me.
Touya Akira passed the pro exams!
Oh yeah.
Yeah? You know?
Yeah, I knew. I heard from Kaiou's first board.
Kaiou's first board? Kishimoto?
Yeah, it must've been a month already...
I bumped into him inside a book store.
He told me that Touya's going to become a pro starting April.
So, I have to keep up, and I've been studying really hard.
Oh I see, that's why you've been improving so quickly.
See!?
So I'm going to take the Insei examination later.
Insei...
Examination!?
Yeah! Isn't it incredible!?
Are you surprised?
Anyways, Kaiou's first board told me that I've got to chase after him desperately or I won't catch up.
And they told me to bring three Kifu with me, but I don't know how to write them.
Tsutsui-san, do you know?
Tsutsui-san...?
Shindou...
I thought Insei's couldn't go to amateur tournaments...
Hikaru?
Isn't it great that you realized before the exam?
Give up on becoming an Insei, let's play Shindou!
What's wrong, Hikaru?
Or...
are you...
going to quit the Go club!?
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Wait a minute, Mai.
That move actually cost you territory.
Even if you did nothing, this black stone can't get away.
If the game ended here,
this stone would be considered agehama (captured).
If you place a stone here, White would get four points.
But if the game ends here, this stone is the same as agehama.
so White would get five points.
You gain one point by not doing anything.
Yuki, there's one other place like this on the board.
Where do you think that is?
Right here.
Correct! That's where it is.
This can be difficult at first, but try to get accustomed to it.
To be continued
Shindou-kun's goal is Touya Akira.
You don't have time to think when playing multiple games!
Play with your instincts! Instincts!
You made me join the Go club to make me a member for the tournament, right!
Because Hikaru isn't quitting Go!