この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
I see the goal.
Don't panic.
It's already difficult for Shindou to come back.
Don't worry about the shadows of Touya and Su-Young that I see behind Shindou.
I went to atari in the wrong place...
Didn't his fingers leave the stone just now?
Playing somewhere else after your fingers leave the stone...
that's an automatic loss.
Fortieth match
Whereabouts of the Win
Sai...
Didn't Isumi-san's fingers leave the stone just now?
It did look like his fingers left, but I didn't see it clearly.
It is against the rules to take back your move but...
Hikaru...
Isumi-san isn't saying anything.
Is it because his fingers didn't leave the stone?
Or...
Should I ask Isumi-san?
If his fingers left just now?
You're going to ask him!?
Hikaru!
Isumi-san is undefeated, I have one loss...
Only three people can become pros.
Hikaru!
Don't you want to finish the game?
I know you have an idea that would turn the game around!
But I'm sure it wouldn't work!
I've already lost this game!
If I say something, I might win...
I want to win.
Even Isumi-san's been struggling for years to pass the pro exam!
This win is priceless...
I want the win!
Isn't Isumi-san staying quiet for the same reason? Is it because he wants the win too?
Hikaru! What I'm talking about is your...
Is...
I resign.
His... fingers really did leave the stone.
But I picked up a big win!
A big win...
Shindou... his match ended.
Shindou is recording the match!?
Shindou won!?
From that board!?
It can't be! What happened!?
Sai...
Why do I feel so bad about winning?
Thirteenth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Isumi-san's play isn't as deep or aggressive as usual.
He's emotionally down from losing to Shindou yesterday.
He hasn't even said a word to me.
This is not like you, Isumi-san!
It may have been a shock, but what good does it do to drag it on?
Your emotions can get in the way. No one here is going to take it easy on you.
Certainly not me!
I resign.
Okay. I might make it this year.
Isumi-san, what are you doing?
I'm going to do it!
My next match is with Ochi!
I can't do it... this game is horrible.
I always beat Fuku but...
And to think, I managed to pick up a win from Isumi-san just yesterday.
The match that I didn't finish yesterday keeps bugging me...
The match from yesterday is...
I was worried that this would happen.
Yesterday's match is leaving a bitter trail in Hikaru's mind.
He has already lost this game, but he's still continuing...
A loss by nine and a half moku...
It's all because of yesterday Match against Isumi-san.
I couldn't focus on the game today!
Hikaru!
I hadn't given up... on yesterday's match!
There was a slight chance that I could've had a comeback!
But, when the win by default dangled in front of me, I reached for it.
Because I wanted the certain win...
It's all because I'm weak... I reached for the win by default because I'm weak.
Hikaru...
Let's finish yesterday's match.
I'll play for Isumi-san. We'll settle the game in your mind, and take a step towards tomorrow.
I want the strength to believe in myself.
I want to become stronger.
I'm never going to play a match like yesterday, or a match like today.
Hikaru, that determination, is well worth a loss or two.
Come, let us begin.
The Fourteenth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
My opponent today is Waya... I'll have to be careful.
He may be the biggest hurdle towards going undefeated.
Honestly, I'm more scared of Waya than Isumi-san right now.
Not only did he lose to Shindou, but he lost to Waya too.
But, I still don't know anything about the match that Isumi-san lost to Shindou due to a careless mistake.
Isumi-san doesn't make many careless mistakes though. Was he thinking about something?
Was it because you were scared of Shindou?
The day you lost to Shindou, I talked about Touya.
Maybe that scared you a bit, and you made a careless mistake. Is that what happened?
Have you not told anyone because you didn't want anyone to think that you were scared of Shindou?
Am I wrong?
Hey, say something already.
Isumi-san...
Ochi, what were you saying to Isumi-san?
You weren't asking him about his match against Shindou, were you?
He hasn't told me anything.
There's no way he'd tell you.
I don't know what happened, but he should just forget about the match like that one.
Why doesn't he say anything? I don't understand him.
It was a careless mistake.
When I looked at it, I figured Isumi-san had just about won, so I went to go watch your game.
And it ended while I was watching you.
There's no way he could have made a comeback that quickly.
A careless mistake?
There's Isumi-san who dragged the shock of it over to the next day and lost to Waya...
And Hikaru who lost to Fuku because he probably got overconfident about winning against Isumi-san.
Neither is a problem.
Really.
You look as if you think there's no doubt that you'll pass.
Yeah. That's probably the case if I beat you today.
Morning.
Sup.
It is time. Please go to the match hall.
Is Isumi-san still depressed?
Why did he make a mistake like that anyways?
Was he concerned about something else?
Hikaru.
Oh yeah, I have to pay attention to my own game.
Yes.
I know. It's okay.
I'm calm today.
It's time, so please begin.
Good luck.
This is a definite win. I just have to be calm.
Oh yeah, what about Isumi-san?
Can I see the chart? I need to stamp my game.
Ochi! Then Waya...
Waya...
It didn't go badly...
I did well on the left side.
But then he got sente, and pushed me around.
It became close, and I lost by two and a half moku!
Damn it!
You?
I won.
Waya... Isumi-san...
lost again today...
Against Fuku.
I guess this is it.
I misread this part.
I guess I'll have to start placing another handicap stone.
But, are you sure you should be playing me during the pro exams?
No, it lightens me up.
Have you read Weekly Go?
Touya 2-dan's won the first match of the first preliminaries for the Meijin title.
So?
He's won the second round for the Honinbou challenger position too.
He's been doing well since he debuted.
He's incredible.
He's saying that he'll teach you as much as time permits.
Just ask him to come.
I don't need Touya.
I beat Waya today, and I've already beat Honda-san.
I can go undefeated without him.
Passing undefeated.
That sounds great.
But you haven't played Isumi-kun. Didn't you say he was your number one rival?
I thought he was.
Fifteenth Match of the Pro Exams Finals
I'm going to pass undefeated. Undefeated.
I'll increase my confidence when I'm a pro.
I won't lose to Isumi-san when he's in a slump.
I doubt that I'll lose to Shindou either.
There's no doubt anymore.
I don't need the likes of you Touya!
You even lost to Fuku yesterday, Isumi-san?
I'm disappointed.
I thought that Isumi-san would be the biggest hurdle towards my passing undefeated.
You're too worried about Shindou.
I kind of regret ever seeing you as a rival.
Though thanks to that...
Ochi.
...it shouldn't be difficult for me to pass undefea...
Shut up.
Please begin.
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Are you two familiar with doubles play in tennis?
- Yes
- I know
It's a two against two match.
Yes. We have it in Go where teams of two play against each other.
Pair matches have special rules, so let's learn them.
Okay.
In a Go pair, the players must play each move alternately.
A player cannot play a move consecutively.
Also, talking with your partner is not allowed.
And you must not discuss the game or help your partner.
Of course, even if there's no talking,
you cannot point or make signs to your partner.
The strongest player does not necessarily win in pairs Go,
and there's a different kind of enjoyment.
So both of you, please try it one day.
To be continued
All right!
Ochi, I know that you're strong,
but I've never for a moment thought that I couldn't beat you.
I'll be playing you in the last match Ochi.
I'll be a lot stronger by then.
Shindou...
Grandpa! Please call Touya 2-dan!