Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Sai... sent a challenge...
He's made the same moves as last time, so far.
Last time?
Yes... the second match against him when I cut him in two.
It's the match from then.
I'll request a rematch on a different day.
Touya Akira...
He hasn't arrived yet...
He's not coming...
It doesn't matter If he loses the first match.
Man, that guy pisses me off.
Eighteenth match
Akira vs Sai
I get to play him again, right?
Yup, I'll let you play all you want.
Last time, during the team match, I played instead, so.
Touya... Akira...
It's 10. Let's log on.
He's not a pro...
but he's as strong as a pro.
It's as if Honinbou Shuusaku learned modern Joseki.
Is he a God... or a demon?
He may be a child.
A child.
It can't be!
It just can't...
He's here!
I'll be going first.
Come, tell me...
Who are you!?
An hour's passed...
In exchange for a loss, he's messing around on the net.
He must think very little of all of us.
He's strong...
I feel a wall higher than when Shindou defeated me.
He's...
not Shindou!
I'll force white to reveal his eyes structure with the move.
That was...
Could it be...
Could it be!
No... This strength...
This strength that tore through the top players on the internet is...
different from his.
Then why did that move look like one of Shindou's moves?
I still have a chance but...
I feel like I've already lost...
Oh no! I didn't block white off soon enough!
Now it'll be difficult to take control of both the center and the left side.
The black in the center... is dead...
He resigned...
Sai, how about it? Was it Touya?
Without a doubt.
Oh... and, your thoughts?
Sai?
Oh yes, he was very strong.
His instinct is great, and he always thinks in all the critical moments.
And? Was he stronger?
I was the one that grew stronger.
And Hikaru, you too.
Me too?
You watched dozens of my matches.
The two of us seem to have grown considerably within the past month.
White
Captured: 1 stone
Black
Captured: 0 stones
Match information
komi
moku
move
white
I see, Sai...
He defeated Touya Akira easily...
I wonder if even I'm a match...
I can't believe that he's and amateur.
Though it is unlikely that there are pros anywhere on this thing.
Anyways, the internet is an unknown.
But... he's not a child.
Children are careless with their play.
No matter how much potential they have, they always make mistakes.
But... Sai's play is different...
The solidness of his play suggests a great deal of experience.
It's him...
No... it's not.
It's definitely not him...
The match against Haze Jr. High that was all he had, wasn't it?
But, why do I feel as if I've finally caught up with Shindou, after chasing him for so long?
No... he's not Shindou...
He's not...
The person that lurked in the darkness, isn't a child!
Akira-kun!
How was yesterday?
Huh?
Not huh, the pro exam!
Of course, you won the first match, right?
Umm... I didn't go.
Okay! You didn't g...
Wha!?
There was someone that I really wanted to play,
and I kinda chose to play him.
Kinda... what!?
Ichikawa-san don't worry. It's okay.
I'll go to the second match tomorrow.
O-Oh...
Akira-sensei!
Hirose-san!
Hello.
How was it? Your first match?
Oh, how rude of me to ask Akira-san whether he won or not.
Hiroe-san, you don't need to worry about the pro exams.
Pay up already!
Okay, okay... money...
Oh yes, Akira-sensei.
Yes?
I saw him on my way here.
That boy who beat you before, umm...
Shindou?
I don't know much about it,
but you know those stores where there are lots of computers and you can access the internet?
Shindou!
Is it you!?
Shindou!?
Are you Sai!?
T-Touya...
Go! Go! Stupid Eggplant Boy!
This is?
It's a web comic! What is it all of a sudden!?
A friend?
Yeah, a friend... I think...
Sorry, I'm gonna go outside for just a second.
Really!
Why do you suddenly appear before me all the time?
What is it?
Crap, he seriously suspects something.
Have you ever played Go on the internet?
No!
You know about it?
I saw it once.
They were doing it when I went to go watch a pro match with Tsutsui-san.
Okay, I'm gonna lie my way out of this! Just try your best!
There's a strong player.
His name is Sai, I played him yesterday.
Huh? What's a Sai?
A white rhinoceros? A black rhinoceros?
The joke comes from the word Sai meaning rhinoceros in Japanese.
It's a handle. The people who play Go on the internet are raising a ruckus as to who Sai is.
Huh? Who Sai is!?
Crap!
So you thought that I might be Sai?
Oh yeah, I did beat you before.
No wonder you thought it was me.
But when I played you as the third board for the Go club, you didn't stand a chance.
Oh that? I played poorly on purpose there!
It can't be! You have no reason to!
If you were as strong as Sai you'd try to become a pro and take a title or two!
Am I wrong?
Thanks for saying what was on my mind for me!
Do you finally get it?
I guess it really wasn't you.
What do you mean by that?
So you didn't think it was me.
No, it can't be you.
Sorry.
I'll never appear before you again.
Touya...
Wait! Touya!
If you...
If you keep chasing after an illusion of me, I'll pass you by eventually!
You?
Do you want to play now and not eventually?
Screw you!
Screw you...
Who was he?
I'm going home now.
Oh.
Raising a ruckus over who Sai is... can't play on the internet anymore.
Let's stop Sai.
Thanks for everything Mitani's sister.
Hikaru-kun?
I won't come anymore. Summer vacation is going to end soon too.
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Today, we're at a Go salon.
When I was a child I came here often.
I brought two beginners.
Please show them around.
First, I'll test you to see how strong you are.
Okay, I have a pretty good idea... You're about 25 kyu.
Mai's strength is about 22 kyu.
At this salon, players are given a game card
One for each of you.
Let's take those cards and try playing someone.
Onegaishimasu.
To be continued
That last match, the comeback that he made, that is his real strength.
We're going to win this time!
I can feel it myself, that I'm getting better!
You really can't judge how strong your opponent is unless you're strong yourself...