この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Rain...
Waya won.
If Shindou losses, he'll have a playoff match against me, at four losses.
It's over.
Forty-seventh match
To the World of the Pros
NcDonald's Hamburgers
Isumi-san quit the Kyuseikai!?
That's not all.
He's not an Insei anymore either.
Although, even those that graduate usually stay until March.
Kyuseikai is the Go school that Isumi-san always studied at, right?
I wonder what Isumi-san's going to do now that he's quit the Kyuseikai and the Insei program.
Waya, do you know anything?
No... I couldn't bring myself to call him.
So I went to take a look during an Insei study session.
And Shinoda-sensei told me that Isumi-san quit.
What... What did he say!?
That this may be better for Isumi-san.
Why!?
Here. It's hot.
Thanks...
Well, everyone is different.
He's probably trying to look at himself from a different perspective.
Even though he has quit the Kyuseikai and the Insei program,
playing games isn't the only way to get better at Go.
At his level, it's more than enough to replay other games.
Sometimes it's important to be alone for awhile.
That's what he said.
I don't really get it...
How can the teacher say that?
Isumi-san might have given up on becoming a pro.
The teacher said 'Isumi-kun still hasn't given up, he'll come back next year.'
Serious?
Yeah. He looked serious.
'He definitely doesn't think that his Go will end here.' He said.
Let Isumi-kun worry about himself.
You have yourself to worry about, too.
You're a pro already.
Is what he said to me.
You too, Hikaru.
But anyways...
I thought I'd teach you how to record games today.
Record games?
We have to do it sometimes.
Though they don't usually ask people going to school to do it.
We record all pro matches after the third elimination round.
I know how to record a Kifu.
You have to record the times, too.
Here's an example.
What is this?
You record how long they spent on each move, or the total time.
Hikaru, you can't possibly do this.
And there's byou-yomi, too.
Waya, you can do this!?
Of course.
How can Waya do something like this!?
What did you say!?
You called me out over something like this?
I'm doing this as a favor for you! Remember that!
But...
Don't mess up when you're doing it.
And? How are you supposed to do this?
Hikaru is finally taking a step into the world of the pros.
But anyways, pros have to play games, right!? Games!
When do I get to play Touya!?
Do you know, Waya?
Of course not!
I'll be playing lots of people, right?
Like you, or Saeki-san, or...
Am I going to play Touya-Meijin, too?
Yes! Yes!
Will I be playing him!?
Listen here...
It's going to be at least five years before you play the top pros.
Even if I keep winning?
I still can't play them?
Yes, can we!?
Well, if you keep winning you will reach the top, but...
That's impossible.
The second elimination round is as far as pros lower than 4-dan can go.
But I am connected!
To Touya, and to Touya's dad.
Yes! Yes!
We're in the same world already!
I'll be playing them someday!
'I'...?
I want to play Murakami 2-dan from the Wakajishisen again, too.
And I want to play Ogata 9-dan or that old guy who's Honinbou, too.
Don't be elated!
Hikaru...
But I want to play Touya first!
I want to play against Touya!
I...
He's still a lower-dan player.
So, if your lucky, you'll get to play him sometime soon.
Our pairings are randomly made.
Random?
I...
I'll get to play Shirakawa-sensei or Morishita-sensei in a real match, too!
Like I keep saying...
You won't play high-dan players for a long time.
But we are connected!
That means we'll be playing sometime!
I mean, we're in the same world already!
Yes...
I'm not the one that's connected...
Hikaru...
It's just Hikaru.
Will Hikaru...
not let me play anymore?
That is true, but...
Right? Let's see who becomes 2-dan first!
The 48th Ouza Title Match
The 23th graduating class of Koike Jr. High School, Reunion
Ten minutes before the match starts...
Good morning, Master Zama.
Good morning.
Now that I think about it, I still haven't congratulated you...
for the sixth successful defense of the Meijin title.
Congratulations, Master Touya.
Thank you.
But you lost the challenger rights to the Kisei title.
I'm sure it's because you're exhausted from playing too many matches, Master Touya.
You may be right.
I may have lost the final match to decide the challenger
for the Kisei title, because I was tired.
But I am in the best condition today.
I believe it is your son who is in the best of conditions.
Isn't he undefeated?
He has had twenty straight wins so far.
The only match Akira lost was the new first dan series match, from right before he became pro...
Master Zama,
just that match against you.
Then you'll be trying to get revenge for your beloved little boy today!
You first, Zama Ouza.
Ouza Title Match
Affiliates Only
The First Game of the Ouza Title Match
What is it, Master Kuwabara?
Is there an interesting article?
The results of the pro exam are on this.
Pro exam?
Ochi Kouske (13)
Shindou Hikaru (14)
Waya Yoshitaka (15)
That boy passed...
I see, his name is Shindou.
Shindou? Who is that?
Just a boy I passed by once.
That you just passed by?
Yes... right over there.
I think it was six months ago...
When I got off the elevator,
I saw a lot of youngsters from the Insei program.
And...
I felt something exceptional about that boy.
Something exceptional?
That sounds interesting!
Yes, it's very interesting.
He may be part of the new wave that Ogata was speaking of.
A new wave... 'Nouvelle vague.'
Looking forward to it.
I'm really looking forward to it!
Spring... it starts in the spring!
I wonder who my first match is going to be against.
Hey, Sai!
Sai?
What's wrong? Come on, let's play!
Just like Hikaru can't wait to play other pros,
They are also waiting for Hikaru...
They aren't waiting for me.
Hikaru...
Hikaru!
It's Hikaru.
You come to report that you passed after all this time!?
We've known about it forever!
That hurts!
You're late! You should have come earlier!
It's all thanks to me that you passed, remember that!
How is it thanks to you, Kawai-san?
What? That boy said he passed the pro exam.
Terauchi-san, you don't know Shindou-kun, do you?
So you think it's not all thanks to me?
He came here almost everyday during the his summer break.
It's not all thanks to you, Kawai-san!
What'd you say?
The results of the pro exam were in weekly Go, a little while ago.
Here, this one.
Shindou Hikaru is his name...
Say this when you get a title,
'It's all thanks to Kawai-san that I am here today.'
What are you talking about!?
A title? sounds good!
Get four of them, just like Touya Meijin!
Nah, he'll have five of them soon.
Five titles? Touya Meijin?
If he wins the Ouza match.
There is a good chance of it, since he won both the first and second games.
I'd hate to be Zama Ouza right now.
And? How many times do you have to win to become Ouza?
The Ouza match is a five game match!
You become Ouza if you win three times!
He's even defended the Tengen title in between the Ouza games.
Touya Meijin sure has it tough.
Tengen?
Is that a title, too?
It might be a little tough for him to get a title if he doesn't even know that...
Actually, are you sure he's going to become a pro?
Why you! Don't embarrass me like that!
It doesn't concern you, Kawai-san!
Why you!
Calm down. I'll give you some old papers, so read up on it.
Th-Thanks, master...
Oh, this is Touya's dad.
It says he's going to play the Ouza match.
There's a kifu for it.
His opponent is Zama Ouza.
So this guy is Ouza...
Hikaru, this is only part of the kifu.
The rest is on the back.
This is...
'First game of the Tengen match'...
It's Touya Meijin who has the Tengen title and...
Ichiryuu Kisei is the challenger.
Look.
Touya's dad is in this one, too!
Hikaru, turn the page! Turn the page!
Let's see...  Touya Meijin... sixth successful defense!?
He really is incredible...
Don't put it on top, put it next to what I'm reading, Hikaru!
Oh boy.
Let's see...
Here... There's still...
What? They're not in order, and some are missing.
This is August... this is May...
This one below it is...
January!
It's old!
It's Touya!
It's Zama Ouza standing next to him...
Oh! This is the new first dan series match!
Hikaru! Turn the page!
Yeah, this is it!
We all watched this match together on that monitor.
The new first dan series...
Yeah... I forgot about this...
I'm getting really excited!
Right, Sai?
Hikaru, show me that one!
The new first dan series...
It was snowing...
It was snowing that day.
It's my turn now.
I'm going to begin with this match.
When the new year comes...
Touya Kouyou
Sorry for interviewing you during New Years.
But now that you have your fifth title, Meijin,
you and Touya are both going to get busier.
It's too bad your winning streak stopped at 26 last year.
But, I'm expecting just as much from you this year.
I'll try my best.
Well I'll be leaving for today, then.
Thank you for your time.
Amano-san.
Yes.
That thing where you have a new pro player play a top pro...
The new first dan series?
You're going to play in it!?
You were too busy to play in it last year and the year before that.
So I wasn't going to ask this year.
Are you really going in it for us?
But I would like to choose my opponent for it.
So there's a new player good enough for you to request to play?
It's been two years since I last met him.
He's finally here.
You mean...
Shindou Hikaru.
I-I see... that stops me from fighting back...
S-Sai...
Your expression's been scary lately...
H-Hey...
About these newspapers...
Mom is going to yell at me again if I don't clean it up already...
I know that you can't look at it unless it's spread out, but...
Go ahead, put them away.
I have already memorized,
all of his games that are there.
Oh yeah, Mom's out shopping.
Hello, this is Shindou.
Yeah... I mean, yes, it's me.
The new first dan series? Yes, I know what that is.
Okay.
Umm, who's my opponent?
Touya Meijin?
Y-Yes! I understand.
Did you hear that, Sai?
I'm going to be playing Touya Meijin!
Remember the new first dan series?
We watched it last year, remember? Between Touya and Zama Ouza!
Oh yeah, Touya... will he... will he come watch?
Yeah, he'll definitely come!
Okay! I'll show him how strong I am now!
Hikaru...
What?
Let me...
Let me play!
Let me play that match!
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
August 30th Japanese Go Institute
Go Go Igo Cup Junior Pair Go Tournament was held
It's finally the day of the Go tournament!
Yup, let's do our best!
Yup!
In the morning, 300 pairs played in the preliminaries
Start your clocks!
Only 32 pairs can go to the finals!!
Go Go Igo cup's Junior Pair Go Tournament was finally held today. I'm glad.
Katou Masao Honinbou and Suzuki Isao 7-dan came to cheer them on
It was a good match.
Good luck next time.
In the meanwhile Mai and Yuuki were...
Unfortunately eliminated from the preliminaries, with 1 win and 4 losses
How was it?
I wanted to go to the finals.
What about you, Yuuki-kun?
I wanted to go to the finals, too.
I'm sorry for the both of you. But you tried your best.
The finals tournament is next!!
I'm going to be hidden in your shadow again.
Then hide in my shadow!
I can't!
I understand how you feel, but...
Show me how strong you are.