この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
It's all because of my match against Isumi-san yesterday!
I couldn't concentrate today!
Hikaru, Hikaru!
I want to become stronger.
I'm never going to play a match like yesterday, or a match like today ever again!
Was it because you were scared of Shindou?
So you got scared of him, and made a careless mistake.
Is that what happened?
Waya... Isumi-san...
lost again today...
against Fuku...
Honestly, I'm disappointed. You're too worried about Shindou.
I kind of regret seeing you as a rival.
Though thanks to all this...
Ochi...
It's easier for me to pass undefea...
Shut up.
Forty-first match
Three Weeks Isn't Enough!
He's coming in this deep?
I'll be short on territory if he survives here.
I won't let you survive that easily.
Just you watch.
Ochi.
Though I respect your skill,
I never once thought that you were stronger than me.
So that's what you did.
Isumi-san is back to normal.
Fine!
Let's go!
Will that really do it?
Wow. He connected it.
Now white's stones are all connected!
I lost the fight on the right side!
Damn it!
Shindou Hikaru!
My name is...
I'm me.
It's not that I lost confidence.
My Go supports me!
I resign...
Thanks for the game.
How did this part go?
I saw it. It went like this.
Yup. Black lost the game there.
I need to clean up.
Oh, we'll take care of it.
Ochi. I thank you.
You helped me get back on my feet.
Isumi-san, you're back.
I feel as if I haven't seen you in days, Waya.
What do you mean by that? What about Shindou?
The pro exam isn't over yet.
Yeah.
It's just starting, for both you and I.
Yeah!
I don't know if Shindou is stronger than me or not.
But, I'm still getting stronger.
Shindou isn't the only one that's getting stronger.
I should believe in myself more.
Yes, this is it. I shouldn't have done a Hane when white did a Tsuke.
It would have been better if I had simply pulled back there.
White would have had a harder time connecting then.
That's it... that's...
I won't lose next time!
Next time...
Ochi, find out for yourself how strong Shindou is.
Ochi: 14 wins 1 loss
Isumi: 12 wins 3 losses
Waya: 13 wins 2 losses
Shindou: 13 wins 2 losses
Honda: 12 wins 3 losses
Fuku: 8 wins 7 losses
Nase: 8 wins 7 losses
Twelve matches left, we're in the final stretch Hikaru.
Yeah.
Shindou...
I'll be playing you in the last round Ochi.
I'll be much stronger than I am now.
Sixteenth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
I resign...
Thanks for the game.
Great, I managed to win.
I was scared of losing today, because of the shock of losing to Isumi-san.
But Waya and Shindou won too.
The same is true with Isumi-san and Honda-san.
What if I mess up and fail?
No way. That's impossible.
Shindou!
Iijima-san looked sad when he left.
Looks like you won, Ochi.
You're doing well too, staying at two losses.
You played Nase today right? Easy win?
Not at all.
Even if you're at an advantage, mistakes happen if you try to rush the win.
Since it's the pro exam, it's hard to play normally.
Being too determined to win can make you falter too.
Emotions are difficult.
Shindou has changed...
And it's not just his strength in the game.
No, I can't be worrying.
Seventeenth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Oh! Shindou lost to Honda-san!
Okay! Now Shindou has three losses!
I knew he'd start falling.
I wonder if Honda-san has gone home yet.
Oh, Honda-san!
You beat Shindou!
Now you, Isumi-san and Shindou are all tied at three losses.
I feel relieved that Shindou lost.
Everyone's making such a fuss that Shindou has gotten stronger.
How was your game?
Honda-san?
I just barely won. No, I thought I had lost.
When we counted, I had half a moku left.
I played well for myself, and I gained a lead.
I made the shape for a win. and I was determined not to budge.
But... Shindou kept pushing at me and pushing at me.
I tried to hold on, and the game ended just when I thought I had lost.
There was half a moku left...
But, I can't believe that I won...
10...
20...
Hikaru!
I dreamt that I was half a moku short.
Is your loss from yesterday troubling you?
I'm glad that you don't have a match today.
What are you worried about?
I can play, even if I have a match today.
His losses and his wins...
All of the games leave something behind in Hikaru, and make Hikaru stronger.
He grows with every game.
Hikaru...
Grandpa! Please call Touya 2-dan.
I'll do my best, in the three weeks left of the pro exam.
Thank you for your determination.
Please feel free to dress casually in the future.
I'll be excusing myself now, I have some work to take care of.
I'll have someone bring you some tea.
I doubt you can do anything in just three weeks.
But, grandpa told me to call you so...
Call me "teacher" for the next three weeks.
How can you listen to anyone that you're disrespectful to?
You can call me "you" or "Touya" or anything else, after the pro exams are over.
You just said that I can't do anything in only three weeks.
You're right. You won't get better just by learning from a pro.
But, I think I can help you in your match against Shindou.
I will be taking advantage...
of your obsession towards Shindou, teacher.
I'll try to come every day.
But, I may not be able to come on some days because of matches or my schedule.
On those days...
If I know about it in advance, I'll have another pro come.
No, don't do that.
They'll get in the way.
Get in the way?
Instead, replay Shuusaku's games.
Shuusaku?
I think there are around 400 of Shuusaku's games left on record.
Replay all of his games, as many times as you can.
What does that have to do with Shindou?
What is he thinking?
Well, let's begin.
We're not playing.
I want to show you this game first.
A Korean kenkyuusei, Hong Su-Young, is black.
Shindou Hikaru is white.
Shindou played a match against a Korean kenkyuusei!?
A teacher from my Jr. High just happened to be there.
That teacher, replayed this game for me.
This... this white is Shindou!?
That move that I thought was a mistake,
was actually preparing for the fight here!
I hear that some of his Insei friends were there too.
It's Isumi-san...
Isumi-san saw this match.
That's why he was cautious against Shindou.
And in the end, white...
Shindou... wins by one and a half moku...
If this is really Shindou's strength right now...
Three weeks...
isn't enough!
That's not true.
That's what I'm here for.
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Today, we're visiting Kodaira Public Middle School No.5 located in Kodaira City, Tokyo.
The Kodaira Middle School Go Club is brand new, formed just this year.
In the beginning, they played on Go boards they made themselves,
but now, as you can see,
they are very active, recording every match and solving problems.
So, once again, I challenged a club member.
But I ended up losing.
I should have won.
At the end, Yukari Sensei gave Life and Death problems that everyone solved together.
The Go Club just started, but they were all strong, weren't they?
I lost too...
Please keep on working hard!
To be continued
The top five just won't fall.
I've finally lost my grip on the cliff.
Who is Shindou!?
That's what I want to find out.
I want to find out how strong Shindou is. His mysterious strength.