この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Yeah, I'd like a title. Meijin might be nice.
Might as well write it. Most of the way Meijin...
Who is he?
Umm...
Who are you?
What!? You don't know me!?
I'm Kurata! The pro player, Kurata! Most of the way Meijin or Honinbou!
The really scary people are coming up from below me.
That's why I'm scared of Touya Akira than Touya Kouyou.
The battles against the people below me will be tough.
I'll remember your name.
As Honinbou Shuusaku's Writing Authenticator.
Fifty-second match
Hikaru vs Akira
The new first dan series...
Ochi won and Waya lost.
And... in March...
What!? I can't believe it.
Waya, shut up!
But Master! Shindou said he doesn't know what an Ooteai is!
What? You don't know what an Ooteai is?
"oo" means big in Japanese, but when put together with ooteai, it means something different.
So what is this big teai your talking about?
Big... teai...?
Really, I've never seen someone as stupid as he is. He doesn't even know how to keep time.
You're not in the position to call anyone an idiot, Waya.
An Ooteai is a match to decide a player's rating.
He became a pro before he learned what an Ooteai is.
Shindou-kun's improvement at the game is incredible.
I agree. I have a hard time believing that he went to my Go class just a short while ago.
Well, he did have a wonderful teacher.
Whatever.
Well, I'm just glad that you both passed.
I guess you're competing with us now.
But for the time being, the only people you will be playing will be lower dan players.
Get some practice there.
Umm... what do you mean by Ooteai deciding your rating?
You'll play ten or so Ooteai matches every year.
Whether your dan rating increases or not is decided by how well you do.
Saeki-kun is 4-dan right now.
Tsuduki-san and I are both 7-dan.
I want to rise to 5-dan already.
Say Saeki, Isn't Ashiwara from Touya's study sessions also 4-dan?
You have to rise to 5-dan before he does.
Master, why do you always make us compete against them?
First you have to play your Ooteai match.
Then once Summer starts, you'll have to play in the preliminaries for many title matches.
You'll probably play two or three matches a month.
Oh, that's all?
You'll be playing more whether you want to or not, if you pass the preliminaries.
Touya Akira has already moved up to the second preliminary round for the Honinbou title, and the Meijin title.
He'll be playing more and more matches as time goes on.
He's the center of attention.
Ahh! One of you stop Touya Akira!
Saeki-san, you can't talk about Touya in front of the master.
It doesn't suit you.
I don't care. Today is a special occasion.
I have to go to the new first dan umm... classification ceremony.
You mean the new first dan certification ceremony.
Besides, you really shouldn't be wearing a necktie.
And you're only in Junior High, too.
Ochi's in Junior High, too. Touya's in Junior High as well.
What kind of profession is that?
I'm so worried about you. Did you remember you application and resume?
Yup.
Oh yeah, Saeki-san said to open up a bank account.
Bank account? Oh, they're going to wire money in.
Yup.
Oh, and this won't be for awhile, but I'll have to file tax refunds, too.
T-Tax refunds!?
Waya!
You're early, what a surprise.
Oh, it's Shindou!
Oh, Kurata-san.
I'm not going to give you my autograph anymore, even if you ask for it.
I don't want it!
Oh, Kurata-kun.
You know Kurata-san?
I met him the other day when I went to a Go event.
He's a weird guy.
What's with that Kurata-san?
He was the recipient of the Most Victories Award and Most Matches Played Award.
Most victories?
Yeah. A lot of pros are here today to receive awards.
Touya Meijin is getting the Top Player Award, and there are other awards, too,
like Exceptional Player Award or the Women's Award.
Touya's getting the best Win/Loss Ratio Award and the longest Winning Streak Award.
Best Win/Loss Ratio... Longest Winning Streak...
The award ceremony is the main event today.
We're extras.
Extras, huh?
So what? Touya was here as an extra last year, too!
Yeah, but...
Touya took things step by step to reach where he is today.
One match at a time...
Shindou?
I wonder who my first opponent is going to be.
That's the spirit. That's where it all starts, Hikaru.
It might be me.
But your opponent doesn't have to be a shodan.
It might be a 2-dan or 3-dan.
Touya...
Finally... I'm finally here.
We're both pros, Touya. What do you think of me now?
Touya, I'm...
finally...
What's up with him? He didn't have to ignore you.
Man he pisses me off. Just because he's doing well...
I guess he's not just doing 'well'...
Morning...
Morning.
What's wrong?
I won't just catch up to him.
I'll pass him.
That bastard...
He's here.
Touya-kun.
Did you look at the pairings for the Ooteai matches?
The pairing committee should have sent it to you.
Have you gotten it yet?
That boy... Shindou-kun's opponent for the first round is...
I know.
Testing, testing.
We're about to begin the award ceremony, and the new first dan certification ceremony.
Anyone participating should gather at the main hall.
We're about to begin the award ceremony, and the new first dan certification...
I'll catch up to Touya...
I'll surpass him!
New First Dan Briefing Room
That's about all.
That's all we have to say.
Then please open your envelopes. We'll explain what each thing inside is.
Ootei Pairings
prepared by
Japanese Go Institute
Oh, these are the pairings for the Ooteai matches.
Yes. It has the pairings for all the Ooteai matches you will be playing this year.
Huh? Where am I?
Towards the end.
The person to the immediate right of your name is your opponent for the first match.
Shindou Hikaru... there it is.
My first opponent is...
Tou...ya...
My first opponent is... Touya!
We'll inform you by mail when your match is. Lower dan matches are on Wednesdays...
Touya!
Upper dan matches are on Thursdays. Get used to leaving your Wednesdays open.
A match against Touya. Exactly what you wanted.
Touya... I wonder if he knows.
He's already declared hostilities against you.
His eyes when he passed by us...
Didn't they seem to you like he already knew that he would be playing you?
Let's show him....
how strong you are!
Okay!
Just you wait... Touya!
Jyudan Match        Five game match        Second game
Ogata 9-dan wins by 3.5 moku
I resigned the first match to you, Master. But now we're even again.
I look forward to the third match.
I'm home!
Hikaru, you have mail from the Go Institute.
Match
Opponent
Date
Ooteai
Touya 2-dan
April 4th Wednesday
It's finally time.
Yeah, it's April 4th.
My first match as a pro... against Touya!
April 4th
Saeki-san!
You're late.
Late? I have half an hour before it starts.
I came early just so that I could help relieve your tension.
I came really early to my first match as a pro,
and I was so nervous I could barely pick up the stones.
You don't seem that way though.
Yeah...
It's probably because I know my opponent.
I feel some pressure... but I don't feel nervous.
Touya, right?
Neither Waya nor Ochi is here today.
Shindou, what are you doing for lunch?
Order here if you want something from the store.
The store?
Oh...
Why don't you eat out with us today?
Yeah!
The match hall is the same one you used for the Insei study sessions.
But there are a few differences.
They give you tea in a pro match.
You can bring in Coke or coffee or what ever you want, too.
Saeki-san, who are you playing today?
Sakurano-san from the women's division.
It looks like you've calmed down.
You looked a little tense when you came off the elevator.
R-Really!?
You shouldn't be too relaxed, so let me teach you a little trick.
Huh? What?
Picture Master Morishita's face.
Do something about Touya Akira!
Ahh! Too much pressure!
It's the opponent you've been waiting for.
You've gotten a lot stronger, Hikaru. I look forward to the game.
Soon... Touya will...
Hikaru?
He's the same as Touya was back then...
The Summer tournament.
The third board match between Haze Junior High and Kaiou Junior High.
Back then, Touya was chasing after Sai.
Now, I'm sitting here in pursuit of Touya.
It's the same.
I understand how he felt back then.
To fight an opponent you fear...
You have no idea how envious I am of you.
When will I once again feel the pleasure of facing such an opponent?
Touya, I'll be the one playing you today.
Not Sai, but me!
He's late...
Touya...
Good luck.
Touya...?
Shindou-kun, can I have a second?
Touya-kun isn't coming.
He called with big news.
Touya Meijin collapsed,
and he's in an ambulance, on the way to the hospital, right now.
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Let's solve a problem today.
It's a black first white dies problem. You should all thing along with us.
Can you do it, Yuuki-kun?
Here.
I capture.
What about here?
White got two eyes.
What about you, Mai-chan?
Here.
If I take it?
And if I go here?
I made two eyes.
It's a difficult problem, so I'll give you a hint.
"A"
"B"
"C"
The correct answer is one of these three.
To be continued...
You play go over the internet?
I'm thankful that I can play even while I'm in the hospital.
He's eager to play against you, Master Touya!
His name is...
Sai!
Fine. If I lose, I will retire.