この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Ochi.
Though I respect your skill,
I never once thought that you were stronger than me.
I resign.
Ochi...
Thank you.
You helped me get back on my feet.
Isumi-san, your back.
I'll be playing you in the last round, Ochi.
I'll be much stronger than I am now.
Grandpa...
Please call Touya 2-dan.
Have you seen this game?
Black is a Korean kenkyuusei Hong Su-Young.
Shindou Hikaru is white.
This...
White is Shindou!?
If this is Shindou's strength right now...
Three weeks... isn't going to be enough!
Not at all.
That's what I am here for.
Forty-second match
The First One to Pass
Eighteenth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
I resign.
Thanks for the game!
Thanks for the game...
Komiya and Adachi were both at five losses, but Komiya just beat Adachi.
Really?
The top five have all won.
You?
I won today but...
Six losses...
I'm at the end of the cliff.
Then I guess I'm hanging off the cliff by one hand since I'm at seven losses.
I'm not out of it just yet!
Later Tsubaki-san!
Yeah!
He's become something...
But...
You and I, and Komiya and Adachi...
None of us have played against the top five yet.
We still have a chance if we can beat them.
We can't afford any more losses.
Yeah!
The Twentieth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Please start your clocks.
Ochi: 19 wins 1 loss
Waya: 18 wins 2 losses
Shindou: 17 wins 3 losses
Isumi: 17 wins 3 losses
Honda: 17 wins 3 losses
Komiya: 15 wins 5 losses
Adachi: 14 wins 6 losses
Katagiri: 14 wins 6 losses
Tsubaki: 13 wins 7 losses
The Twenty-First Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Nase! You beat Honda!?
Yup!
I played a great game!
Wow!
I wish you could have seen it.
It's because I can play like that...
I can play like that...
That is why I can't give up on becoming a pro.
It's over.
Thanks for the game.
You played well.
It was a good game.
The top five won't fall...
They refuse to fall...
So... this is the end for me.
Last year, Touya Akira was far ahead of everyone else,
so we had to compete harder for the two remaining spots.
Next year...
What will happen next year?
Did you win?
Yeah!
Things have turned around since the preliminaries.
I wanted to try it at least once,
before I reached the final year that I am allowed to take the pro exam.
Tsubaki-san...
But...
I've lost my grip on the edge of the cliff.
Hey!
You asked me for a ride on my bike awhile ago didn't you?
Oh, yeah...
Come on, I'll give you a ride to the station.
What is it Hikaru?
Hey!
Come on! Let's go!
Oh, yeah!
Tsubaki-san! Slow down a little!
Are you at three losses right now?
What? What did you say!? I cant hear you!
You're doing well!
I said, I cant hear you!
A month between the preliminaries and the finals.
A month and a half since the finals started.
You were getting stronger all the while.
I didn't change at all. That's the difference between us.
Tsubaki-san! I can't hear anything you're saying!
Hey! You're Shindou, Right?
What!?
I'm leaving my dream of becoming a pro with you!
I can't hear you!
I said I'm leaving my dream of becoming a pro with you!
Thanks for the ride, Tsubaki-san.
Umm... what you said earlier.
Oh, that.
I will be cheering for you.
I won't forgive you if you mess up in the end.
Thank you, Tsubaki-san!
I was afraid of what would happen when we first met him.
Come on, let's go Sai!
Sai?
I told you! This move is pointless!
There's no way a blunt move like this could work!
Weren't you troubled by the combination of a nobi after a nozoki!?
You should have settled for meeting it with a jump.
I told you the same thing just three days ago.
Are you even trying!?
I am trying.
It's just that I don't understand why you're so obsessed over Shindou.
Yes, his match against the Korean kenkyuusei did surprise me.
I've had an incredible game or two as well.
So what?
I know exactly how strong you are already!
Why are you so obsessed over Shindou!?
It's an even match I had two years ago.
Shuusaku's kosumi...
I'm white.
And black?
Who's black?
His play seems rather archaic but...
This person playing black is quite good.
His moves assault white's weaknesses viciously.
This strength is...
Who's black!?
It can't be!
It's him.
Shindou!?
I know Shindou!
I looked at his game when he first became an Insei,
I played him during the study sessions too!
I resigned here.
It can't be! It's impossible! Two years ago!?
I didn't stand a chance.
No one would believe that this black player is Shindou from two years ago.
No... that is why I haven't shown anyone this match before.
You are the first person I've shown it to.
I don't believe it either!
I don't expect you to.
But, this match did indeed happen.
Just who is Shindou!?
That's what I want to find out.
Come on, let's continue.
The Twenty-Second Match of the Pro Exam Finals
I resign.
Okay! I won by three and a half moku!
This is your nineteenth win.
Adachi: 15 wins 7 losses
Shindou: 19 wins 3 losses
Thanks for the game.
Waya: 20 wins 2 losses
Komiya: 16 wins 6 losses
Good job seeing it.
Now, black has the advantage.
I resign.
Honda: 18 wins 4 losses
Isumi: 18 wins 4 losses
Great! Great!
I'm still at four losses.
There is a good chance of a playoff.
Five matches left. I can still pass!
Playoff?
There's another round if two people are tied for the third place.
I see.
A playoff...
I'm in danger of that since I'm at three losses.
That move where Honda broke in decided everything.
It looked as if it went in too deep, but there was no way to stop it.
It was a good move.
He lost at least eight moku because of that.
There was no where else to make it back either since it was the end game.
Isumi-san's failed.
He hasn't failed yet!
Yeah, if you lose two more games, there can be a playoff.
I won't lose!
I'm going to pass.
Me too...
Five more matches.
I'm almost at the goal.
Almost...
The Twenty-fifth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Congratulations Ochi-kun!
Thank you very much.
Even if you lose the last two matches, your win today has guaranteed that you will pass.
Yes.
Were you nervous when you were playing today?
No.
Really? That's incredible.
You didn't get overzealous when you were trying to pass?
Someone told me that if I set an even higher goal for myself, passing the exam will happen on its own.
That may be why.
A higher goal than passing?
What kind of goal is it?
It's to beat Shindou!
Shindou-kun? Didn't you beat him during the Insei study sessions?
Shindou has changed since then.
Oh...
He has grown very rapidly but...
Well anyways, congratulations on passing.
Thank you.
Well, good luck with the rest of your matches too.
Hey, Ochi.
Congratulations on passing.
You don't have to force yourself to say it.
Can't you just accept my congratulations as they are?
How was your game?
I won, but I'm not the only one.
Shindou is still at three losses,
and Isumi-san and Honda-san are still at four losses too.
The top five have all won.
But, I guess it doesn't matter to you anymore.
Waya, you'll be playing Shindou next.
Yeah, I'm at two losses. I'll pass if I beat Shindou, who's at three losses.
Well, either way, you'll just be watching us from above without a care in the world.
I do care about something.
I'll be playing Shindou in the last round.
It's not a throwaway match.
It may be the most important match for me, out of the entire pro exam.
Did you always think so highly of Shindou?
I want to find out Shindou's strength.
His mysterious strength...
Mysterious?
I'll be looking forward to your match against Shindou. Good luck.
Later then, Ochi.
This is the Shindou that I know.
I won't know unless I play him.
But, I won't lose... I don't want to lose!
Not to someone like Shindou...
Okay, I won!
I guess I'll go to sleep after another game.
Sai!
Seriously!? Is he playing a game!?
I haven't seen him since last summer...
You idiot! Why are you using the name Sai!? You suck!
Don't use Sai's name! He's a legend on the net!
Didn't I mistake Shindou for Sai's student once?
Zelda...
Oh yeah, you said that you were an Insei.
So Waya, you're Zelda!
Y-You...
Why do you know about the conversation between Sai and I?
Could it be he's...
Shindou is... Sai?
It can't be... that's....
His mysterious strength...
Who cares?
I'll win and pass the pro exams!
Two more matches.
I'll be playing Waya next...
Do you remember? What he said to me the first time I played him?
When I just made it up to first class?
Yes, I remember.
It was a good game, Shindou.
The opening was fun.
You might get good!
As good as Sai one day...
I think I started working harder thanks to what he said.
You're right.
I'll win...
I'm going to win!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Today, let's discuss proverbs.
Do you know what proverbs are?
Useless as gold coins to a cat!
Yes, that's one! Go has its proverbs, as well.
Take a look at the board.
This is a Life and Death problem where white dies if black goes first.
The hint is the proverb: "Play at the center of symmetry."
Want to give it a try, Yuki?
Okay, I'd go here!
Yes, that's the center.
If I go here, what would you do, Mai?
I'd go here.
Exactly!
So now, even if I take your stone...
You can take my stones right back.
And that way, there will be only a single eye.
Even if I played on this side, and you went here, it's the same.
Playing at the center was the key.
Let's cover more proverbs next week.
To be continued
Damn, I can't find it...
The way for black to live...
Okay! If this black cluster lives, you win.
If I kill this black cluster, I win!
Can I kill it?
Can I live?