この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
I see... this is a good learning place.
Since Hikaru has only played myself, a stronger opponent, he will gain a new strength here.
In Go, if you have half a moku more than your opponent, you win.
In an even match, you start off even. All you need to do is hold a marginal lead.
But a handicap game is like giving 20 to 30 moku to your opponent to start with.
In that case, you must take territory with moves you don't usually see.
In other words, you become better at terrorizing your opponent.
That offers a strength to come back from losing situations in even games.
Thirty-fourth match
Don't Win
Good morning!
Morning!
Oh there he is.
Okay, let's play!
But the fee...
Don't worry about that.
Hey!? Oh well.
Oh well what?
It's okay for him.
Good luck.
Friendly Go Festival
Oh, Mr. Touya good morning.
Good morning.
Hey! Don't place your cup on the Go board! Put it on the table!
Okay. I'm sorry.
Everyone is playing and enjoying themselves and the event hasn't even started yet.
It is a gathering of Go fans.
Who are the four people I will be playing during the morning?
A city council member, his secretary, and two of his supporters.
Honestly the council member isn't very good.
But please lose to him.
He gets grumpy if he doesn't win.
He is a big sponsor that helps run this event.
The council member won't use a handicap of too many stones to show off, so it may be hard to let him win.
It will be fine.
How dare you not send someone to greet me at the door!
Oh! My apologies sir.
We didn't expect you to arrive so early.
I came early so I could meet Sakurano Chieko-san.
Is Sakurano-san here yet?
Unfortunately Ms. Sakurano could not come due to circumstances.
What!?
It was an emergency. So we had Touya 2-dan come in the place of Ms. Sakurano.
Touya 2-dan? He's just a little bratty kid.
Touya 2-dan is Touya Meijin's son, and highly praised in the Go world.
It's nothing special to be playing the son.
Oh well. Give me some iced tea.
Okay, this way please.
Friendly Go Festival
My apologies.
It's okay.
That's who they are, but please lose to them.
Let's start then.
We would like to begin the matches now.
Good luck.
Give me five stones.
Then I'll need six stones.
What about you? Three stones?
Yes. I was told three stones would be plenty when playing a tutoring game with a pro.
If you're playing with three stones, I'm playing with three too. I can't put anymore down.
Is three stones really enough?
Yes! I'm always beating pros at five stones!
Well then, good luck.
Good luck.
You can't just look inexpressive like that.
Your job deals with people, you have to learn how to be friendly.
Please lose to them.
Four of them...
What's wrong Mr. Touya?
Nothing, let us begin.
64 moku...
It's my turn now!
Are you bad at counting?
Counting is when you determine the territory of each player and estimate who's winning. Also called mokusan.
Huh?
What!? Are you not even counting?
I'm counting! I can estimate how much territory there is.
Looks like you're not precise enough.
This next match, try to force a draw.
Intentionally make the game a draw.
Intentionally?
Yes, intentionally. With a handicap game, there isn't a 5.5 moku komi so a draw can occur.
Listen, make the general estimate during the mid-game, and calculate precisely during the endgame.
That's the hard part.
The board changes with every move of your opponent, so you must keep counting.
And you have to be exact, so you can't miss by even one moku.
Just so you know, you can't just force a draw. You can't play any slower than usual.
You have to play at your normal speed.
Hikaru! Sounds fun!
And...
There's more!?
You can't make a bad move to let them catch up.
You have to play well enough so that your opponent, doesn't realize that you're trying to force a draw.
I already know though.
You just play normally Doumoto-san.
Let's do it Hikaru!
Give it a try, it'll help you.
Okay.
Good luck.
To force a draw...
If you manage that, try it with two boards next.
Two boards!? Force a draw on both?
Owner! That's crazy!
Want to try three if you can do two?
If I do that, will I be working on four?
Easy to say that, but I wonder how far you'll get.
Don't be getting cocky!
If you can't count properly, you can't force a draw.
Try to force a draw against Doumoto-san first.
It's your first time with even one person right?
You'll be playing two people with two boards! That's impossible.
No! Hikaru you'll be okay. Let's do it!
I can tell how strong they are after ten moves.
The two people on my sides are more or less what I expected. Their handicaps are about right.
This person is very weak just as I had imagined.
He is a good player. He'll take advantage of any weak moves I make.
A kid who just became pro last year.
He's probably been told to lose to the council member.
I guess you'll do it hesitantly. Or will you refuse to let someone like him to win?
You can't do that, though you're just a kid. You are a pro. Good luck with losing.
Yes! A draw!
Good job Hikaru!
Nice job!
Hey! Stop that!
But, it's not too hard now that I've done it.
Just so you know, a pro can easily force a draw 100 times out of 100 games.
Good point. I take back what I said earlier. If you're an Insei you can't be satisfied over just one board.
Okay.
Okay let's go with two boards now! Two!
I'll play.
Hey! That's not fair!
Then Doumoto-san, switch with me.
Kawai-san...
You don't have to be good right? Then let me play too.
I don't care who it is!
With two opponents you'll have to calculate twice as much. It'll be hard.
I'll triple with three people right? I know.
You can probably manage two. But three will be hard.
Hurry! Three! Let's do three Hikaru!
Like I said, I haven't done two yet.
So end it quickly!
Really...
Okay going with two boards!
The handicap stones placed in the beginning.
I've already gained back most of it.
15 moku with him.
10 moku with him.
I'll bring my throwaway stones back to life, and turn the right side into white territory, and that'll be enough.
6 or 7 moku against him.
What's with his serious face?
He keeps staring at the game against me.
He's going all out against me. He doesn't look like he's holding back.
Oh I see! Because you're letting the council member win, you're going to beat us no matter what instead.
You may be able to beat the other two easily, but that's not the case with me.
So you're concentrating on your match against me.
You must be really angry about having to lose to him.
But if that's the case. I'll beat you no matter what and make you, the Meijin's son, cry.
Mr. Touya certainly is impressive. He's the same age as my grandson, but he's much more mature.
But I'm still a little worried...
that he may slaughter our customers in a tutoring game.
I'm sure he won't. He's a pro after all.
That may be so but...
I'll let him get 2 moku with seme-dori.
I'll let him take sente for 4 moku.
With him...
I've read all the moves till the end.
If I go straight through, it'll be fine.
But, he won't let me do that...
Adjust for that...
Adjust...
Okay. After that, this game is over.
It's over.
This is...
Yes.
I'm losing? No I'm winning.
Black, 63 moku.
White, 63 moku.
A draw!
Yes! I drew them both!
Why you! I guess there's a reason you're an Insei.
Hey stop that!
Okay let's do three board with me in the fray now!
No!
Why?
I'm the one joining in.
Huh? Why!?
Soga-san, that's unfair!
No it's not.
You'll come in next.
Hikaru! It's so fun! It'll be four boards next! Four!
I haven't done three yet.
And, it was a little too early to come to atari on these two stones.
White was able to take territory in the center in the mean while.
Other than that I think you played fine.
Touya failed to beat me, but the rest should be easy wins.
He still looks serious...
What could...
Oh a draw!
What a shame!
It must have been because I lost those four stones.
Concerning that, you probably intended to come out, and extend after I responded...
A draw!? again?
Could he have done it... intentionally?
Nothing out of the ordinary happened in my game...
It should have been difficult for Touya to even beat me.
I was told to place three stones when I was the only one playing.
Playing me at three stones with three other games, should be very difficult.
And to end it nicely in a tie?
It's impossible! It's just a coincidence.
20... 40... 77...
You have 77 moku too!? A draw...
Ahh what a shame! I could've won if I had just another moku!
And I thought I played well even for myself.
Oh, you had a draw too sir?
You mean you had a draw too?
Don't compare yourself to me. I was playing at three stones and you were at six.
Oh, I just thought it was peculiar.
This means that I can play at three stones against a pro.
Oh yes, you were at three stones too. How was it?
It was a draw...
Oh what a...
What a coincidence...
Coincidence!?
Argh, you've caught up.
I wonder if I have any left... it's pretty close...
10... 20...
Aw damn! It's a draw.
What a shame, it's a draw...
Huh? What's wrong?
All four of us...
Hey, a coincidence like this can't... possibly...
No, but... he can't... can he do it?
I mean I played the way I usually do.
Now let us discuss the match from the first move.
Go ahead.
Oh, I hope you're not angry about it...
Don't worry. They're all more surprised than angry.
And it'll be good for the council member to deal with this every year now and then.
I'm sorry!
Make sure to do a better job in the future Mr. Touya.
It's rude for you to do it with just anybody.
Yes!
Now that I can think about it, I can brag that I tied a pro at three stones!
Yes that's it sir!
Then sir, would you like to play a game sometime?
No, I've had enough Go for awhile.
But anyways...
Anyways?
Pros are really amazing.
Akira-kun!
Ashiwara-san...
I heard about the four way game you played this morning.
But I...
No buts! What were you thinking!?
I'm sorry, I was going to let the...
No!
Don't waste your effort at a place like this!
You have the first round of preliminaries for the Honinbou titles between your normal matches for promotions.
If you keep winning, you'll necessarily be playing more games.
You shouldn't go all out at places like this and exhaust yourself.
Are you irritated about something?
No, I'm not.
Okay then.
But you... well, you seem as if you're not confident, or you're too emotional.
Really?
Don't worry! Don't worry! No one's coming up to get you.
But...
He passed the preliminaries for the pro exam.
It's nothing.
You missed by one moku against me.
One moku...
Even if it's just one moku, it's not a draw.
It's all because you're so loud Kawai-san!
What!? You're blaming it on me!?
Yeah!
Why you!
Stop it! Stop it already!
Even if he missed it by one moku, he forced draws on the other three right?
Isn't that enough?
Yeah... more than enough.
I've finally seen someone grow before my eyes...
Don't be upset about it.
Another round!
Make it succeed this time.
Oh well, we'll play you until you do it.
Okay!
Thanks!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
On May 24th, the second game of the 57th Honinbou match...
was held here in Kure City, Hiroshima Prefecture.
Masao Kato 9-dan is challenging O Meien Honinbou.
Each game of the Honinbou match is played over two days.
During the Edo period, the title of the Honinbou was
bestowed upon an official Edo government Go master
and passed down through the generations.
Among all Honinbou, Shuusaku who appears in Hikaru no Go,
was acclaimed as the "Go Saint."
Next time, I'd like to visit Innoshima, the birthplace of Honinbou Shuusaku.
To be continued
Yes. So-Young is trying to become a pro in Korea.
It'll be more fun for me to play the customers here than to play you.
You're that scared of losing to me!?
I'll show you! And then leave this place.