Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Why don't we tie his arms and legs behind his back and make him play?
That's a good idea...
Ninth match
An Irritating Presence
Hmm...
Where's Itou and Kojima?
They came today right?
They're not here?
They took Okumura-kun, a freshman, and the three of them sneaked off earlier.
Sneaked off?
Yes...
Wakajishisen is a fictional tournament that appears in Hikaru no Go. It is based on a real tournament where new pros play Insei in a tournament style match.
Insei are children who go to the Japanese Go Center to learn Go. They all aim to become pros some day, and they're all frighteningly good at the game.
Shuusaku is the person that Sai inhabited 100 years ago. He actually did exists, and is considered one of the greatest players of all time.
A Hundred
Different
Tsumego
The Key
to
Solving
Tsumego
Collection
of
Shuusakus's
Matches
Famous
Pro
Matches
Waka-
jushisen
Ouza
Matches
As you can see, it's a mess.
When we didn't have very many members, this was the club room.
But now... it's just storage for the club.
At the next tournament, we're going to use this place as a preparation room for the women...
So Mr. Yun told us to clean it up.
Anyways, chores like this are work for the freshman and you looked bored Touya, so if you don't mind...
I understand.
Oh wow, it's Kifu...
and old Go magazines.
Wow!
The Japanese Calendar doesn't work on the same system as the Western calendar. They have periods that begin and end with the government. Currently they are in the Heisei period which started about 15 years ago. The Shouwa period was before the Heisei period and lasted more than 60 years.
There are things here from the beginning of the Shouwa Period.
Wow, this book is old too!
Old Joseki...
I've felt it since I first met Shindou Hikaru.
For example blacks next move..
These days we would hane the white stone.
It's considered to be the best move.
But, you used... a nobi.
That's an old Joseki.
Sometimes, things like that happen.
It may look like a weakness to attack...
but you crushed me with your strength before I got a chance.
Just improving slightly won't surpass him.
Surpassing him...
Master of Tesuji
will require a strength great enough to... create new Joseki...
Could you play a game against me while you're at it?
Oh wait...
You just keep cleaning up like I told you to.
Don't you dare look at the board in the middle of the game.
Not... look at the board?
You're telling me to play blind folded?
No, not at all.
It's just that if you're a member of the Kaiou Go club...
You have to do the chores, and you also have to obey your senpai.
Go is different from Shougi, the board is a lot larger.
Are you aware that blind Go is difficult even for pros?
You can do it right?
You are the future Meijin after all.
Why did a guy like you have to join the Go club?
No one in any tournament will be able to beat you.
Why don't you just go pro and take 4 or 5 titles?
Or what?
Did you want to show off your strength to others and make sure everyone knows that you're the best?
The best?
What? Are you saying you're not?
If I'm the best...
You're saying I should be able to play blind Go easily?
Please make your first move.
16-4 hoshi
4-16 hoshi
4-16 hoshi...
16-17 komoku
4-4 hoshi
4-4 hoshi...
If I beat you at this, it would be great.
After all, it is an even match.
Beating the great Touya Akira at an even match...
It won't be interesting if you kill yourself off too quickly, so try to hold back on mistakes.
I don't care if you show off, but do it after you beat me.
You sure do talk a lot!
You just said that it's hard even for pros.
This will be an interesting match.
6-4 kakari!
3-6
6-6
4-14
Touya should be struggling by now.
Blind Go has to be tough, even for Touya.
So this is what he meant by tying his arms and legs behind his back.
I understand.
Well, I'm next.
Isn't it still a little early?
I wanna see Touya's desperate face.
Hey Touya!
Will you play a game...
Itou...
T-This is...
a resignation from to great a gap?
But you've only gone through half a game!
I didn't think there was another person.
If you wish to play me, go ahead.
Oh...
He was beat easily since it was a match without any handicap...
with so little moves, blind Go is not impossible.
Like this, I would also get defeated.
Hey Itou!
Okumura!
Come here Okumura!
You're gonna play him too!
But... he can't play against 2 people at the same time!
It won't even be a close game.
It didn't work out as we planned with only one person.
Really!?
Two... opponents?
What?
You're going to quit now?
Then why don't you quit the Kaiou Go club too!?
If you can't play us, then why don't you leave the Go club?
You're irritating.
Make your first move.
But...
I won't give up so easily.
What's the matter?
The future Meijin wishes to play you.
Then...
16-4 hoshi!
4-16 hoshi
4-16... hoshi
17-4... komoku
4-3 komoku
16-17 komoku
4-4 hoshi
4-16
6-17... kakari
16-15
15-3
13-17
17-17
17-15
17-14
17-18
17-16
3-3
5-3
5-17
4...-17
6-6
7-5
Damn...
Kojima's not as strong as I am...
and the freshman's even worse!
5-8
If it continues like this, they'll lose with even fewer moves than me.
Hurry up and move!
4... 4-18... osae
Kaketsugi, Hiraki, Ate, Osae are all names for moves that have a specific purpose. Hiraki is there to capture more territory, Ate is a move that places one of your stones next to an opponent's stone, Osae is a move made to limit the mobility of your opponent's stones, Kaketsugi is a move to move your stones out of your opponent's containment.
Man...
2-5 kaketsugi
10-4 hiraki
6-18 ate
What a stupid...!
Hmm...?
Hey! Why are you so slow whenever you're moving against me!
Touya is struggling?
It can't be, haven't made very many moves yet...
and it's stupid Okumura, not Kojima...
Oh!
Touya's going to lose without holding out even 5 minutes...
Against Okumura.
Touya! Hurry up and move!
Touya! Hurry up and move! It's your turn.
Oh... Okumura's stupid moves are throwing Touya's rhythm off...
Memorizing each move can only happen when those moves have meaning.
But... Okumura's moves are so meaningless that Touya's having trouble understanding why he's making those moves...
and that's throwing his memory off!
10...17...
10-17
Touya, one of my stones is there.
Dammit!
4-9 hiraki!
4-9 huh?
He's finally starting to collapse!
Wait, can't let my guard down, I'm playing Touya.
You can just keep acting stupid.
3-14 kakari
4-11
10-4... hiraki
17-...
...6
Keep moving Touya!
Upon this battlefield which you can't see you shall wander around blindly and die.
Touya are you here?
Hitaka... Senpai!
Itou... Kojima too?
Hey, Touya...
You said you'd play a tutoring game with me earlier...
You're a freshman, right?
What are you guys doing?
Umm... ahh... this is...
Er, umm... Mr. Yun...
Said to clean up this room, so we asked Touya...
We wanted Touya to play a tutoring match with us too...
but Touya had to work so...
So!?
So...
Umm... we played a little...
Blind Go.
Moron!
Touya had to work?
Then why didn't you help him!?
Itou... you're behind this aren't you!?
Umm... Well...
You too Touya, what do you think you're doing!?
I'll clean this up, so you go ahead and clean them up.
Hitaka-senpai...
I took this match...
I'll continue it like this.
Shut up!
They're bullying you, I won't let this continue.
But this is something I...
If you weren't here...
Then they wouldn't be doing something like this!
And you even accepted their challenge!
You're the one that made the bullying worse!
If only you weren't here!
But...
what I'm trying to say is...
you're a student of Kaiou, so be in the Go club with pride...
So... don't accept challenges like this, play them fairly and crush them.
Yes!
Thank you very much!
Hitaka-senpai...
It should end in about 5 minutes, so please, allow me to play you afterwards.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
Let's... finish this!
Tsutsui-san!
I found a member!
Someone who can play Go!
Really?
Now we can go to the tournament!
You... can play Go?
Yeah I can.
You don't have to know, the Go club here is...
Are you stupid!?
Of course it's better that they know how!
Either way, Shindou-kun..
Team matches are seated by gender so she can't be on our team.
I know!
Let's have her dress up as a guy!
She'll fit the role perfectly...!
I don't mind entering if it's just for the tournament.
I'm busy with the volleyball club.
Hikaru, you said something unnecessary again.
So a team match in Go work on a 3 player team?
Damn, a guy!
We have to find a guy!
I guess we want a guy who can play...
and someone strong as possible...
Isn't there anyone like that Sai?
The only strong person I know is that person...
We can't have Touya's dad dress up as a Junior High student!
Hey, let's put a new poster! One that attracts more attention.
We can put a difficult tsumego on it and have anyone who can solve it come!
That again?
I don't really care if they're strong anymore!
Doesn't Kaiou Junior High have dozens of members?
Yup, the grass is definitely greener on their side.
Man I'm jealous...
Come on, it's your turn Shindou-kun, Kaiou is Kaiou and we're us.
Hmm...
Touya...
Itou of the second year just quit the club.
Why did you enter the Go club, Touya?
Because of you, all of our members are nervous.
I, the president, am as well.
to be honest...
I want to play you, and learn from you...
But...
everyone around me is talking...
they don't want to see the president lose to Touya in an instant.
Although...
I want to challenge you like Aoki did, I can't.
Touya...
I heard the rumor that you entered the Kaiou Go club to fight Shindou Hikaru of Haze Junior High.
But why a tournament?
Why did you have to enter the Go club?
Your existence in the club causes a hundred problems for us, without a single benefit.
He refused my challenge.
I don't know why, but if he refuses...
Then I have to enter the tournament no matter what.
You said earlier that "I cause a hundred problems. without a single benefit for the Kaiou Go club."
But Shindou Hikaru will come to the next tournament!
It's not ego or selfishness!
I'm the only one who can play with him evenly!
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Today, we're visiting Hoya Middle School.
Sensei and I were overwhelmed at first...
by the Go club's warm reception.
Once the games began, however everyone was all business.
I tried playing some games,
but I was no match for them.
I need to practice more!
Yukari Sensei played five people at the same time.
Yukari Sensei is awesome.
Thank you very much, Yukari Sensei!
Go club huh? Not too exciting...
Hey, umm, there's a tournament soon.
A Go tournament, for Junion High Schools.
This child has quite a bit of potential.
He makes honest and good moves.
He's cheating at seichi!