Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
He's strong...
He's not Shindou!
I'll never appear before you again.
W-Wait! Touya!
If you keep chasing after an illusion of me, I'll pass you by eventually!
You?
Thanks for everything Mitani's sister.
Hikaru-kun?
I won't come anymore. Summer vacation is going to end soon too.
Nineteenth match
Hikaru's Strength
I can't go on the internet anymore...
I guess we have no choice, Sai you wanna play me?
Really!?
Hikaru you never mentioned that before!
That's because I didn't want to play you.
I mean, I have to place stones for two people! That's so much work.
But Hikaru... You don't have a Go board in your room.
Or Go stones.
You...
have gotten stronger.
Really?
I thought so.
You're not getting as large a handicap next time.
Mitani, if you're giving up you should say "I resign".
Why you! Don't get cocky, I'm still better than you are.
That doesn't matter, even with a handicap, a win is a win.
What!?
Hey everyone! Ms. Tamako bought two sets of Go boards and stones for us using the club budget.
Go board and Go stones!?
Hey you!
Wow, they're foldable.
It's like a toy. Well it is a toy.
Don't say that!
We have a new member!
Come in!
Oh, hi.
Just a girl?
What do you mean by "Just a girl".
Well, if it was a guy, we'd be able to go to the tournaments even after Tsutsui-san graduates.
Hey Akari, I don't know anything.
Don't worry, I'll teach you everything.
Who's going to teach what?
I'm going to teach Go!
I'm even going to Go class!
Serious!
Alone?
Yup.
Why?
The Go club's going great.
It's too bad I have to study for High school entrance exams.
You can come play every now and then, right?
He's gotten strong over, summer break.
Okay, let's play a game.
Play me with no handicap!
Really?
Then, Mitani-kun, teach us!
He said he'll teach us!
Oh yeah, Tsutsui-san, how much does a Go board and stones cost?
This probably wouldn't even cost about 10,000 yen per set.
That's expensive!
I guess I have no choice but to talk to Gramps.
What are you talking about?
Yeah, I heard. You're playing Go?
You knew? Yeah, it's been about a year now.
And you're in the Go club at school?
Yup!
And I came to ask you for something today.
Ask me for something?
No! No!
Your mother strictly told me not to give you money all the time.
I don't want money! I want you to buy me a Go board.
Go stones too.
A Go board!? You don't have one?
Okay! It's my grandson's request, I'll buy you one!
A foldable one's fine, right?
I want one with legs!
If I beat you with no handicap, will you buy me one with legs?
N-N-N-No handicap!?
Who do you think I am!
How's this!
Champion of the third City Go tournament!
Winner of the 8th Go salon Grand prix!
Countless other wins as well!
Yeah, you showed me all that before.
Come on, let's play already!
If you beat me in an even match, I'll even give you this Go board.
What? A used board?
Quiet you! This is a good board!
Yeah! Gramps, what about that Go board in your shed.
Oh that? From when you collapsed?
Can't give you that.
Why?
There's a rumor that a ghost with a tall hat appears from it.
A ghost?
Though it's just a rumor.
That Go board is something my brother bought from an antique shop out of curiosity.
Then when my brother died it was given to me as a memoir of him.
But I've never seen a ghost like that even once.
I'm with Hikaru right now.
About a hundred years ago I was with Torajirou.
Before that, I played within the palace in the capital.
It's been a thousand years since then.
I am still before a Go board.
How long will God allow me to continue with my selfishness?
Oh no! Don't!
All my stones are going to get captured!
Yeah, so you should have gone here instead of here earlier.
Then can I take back my move?
Sure sure.
Thanks mister!
Akota-san, you're so nice.
Really, Akota-san's really changed since Fujisaki-san started to come.
No it's not like that.
Speaking of, how's Shindou-kun doing?
He's fine, Hikaru seems to have gotten a lot stronger.
Oh yes, Fujisaki-san's been here before with Hikaru-kun!
Yup.
Hey, hey, Fujisaki-san you like Hikaru-kun don't you?
N-Not really...
Come on! You wouldn't suddenly take up Go if you didn't.
That's...
W-Well, ask Shindou-kun to stop by here again sometime.
Okay.
What am I doing in a place like this?
Let's see...
I think I'm lacking a bit.
What is it gramps, stop groaning, it's distracting.
You said you've played for a year now?
Improving this much in just a year...
Well, you're really become strong.
Really?
This is why you can't underestimate children...
or actually you've got talent.
Really!? Then I'm winning this!
No not at all, even if you don't make a mistake in the endgame, I'm still winning.
Then I lost.
Like I said, who do you think I am!?
I was the only one who beat Inoue-san from Kutsuwa city!
Who is that? No one knows him!
With legs... I guess it's okay.
I'll get you one, the cheapest one.
If that's all it takes to encourage you further, it's a good buy.
Really!?
I have a delivery!
Oh thanks.
Hikaru! What are you doing! Are you okay?
5-50,000 yen!? This!?
Thanks gramps!
Did you thank your grandfather properly?
Yeah, yeah.
I had no idea he would continue Go for this long.
What will we do?
What will we do and what will we do?
It's nice having a Go board in my room.
Hikaru! Let's play! Let's play!
Okay! Okay!
It's so cool! New stuff's so good!
Hikaru, place all the handicap stones you want!
All I want?
What's that!
I don't need any handicap!
Come on, Nigiri!
Nigiri? B-But... Nigiri!?
Oh man. Fine then you're white and I'm black. Komi is 5.5 moku. Okay?
China recently enacted a new rule setting Komi to 7.5 moku. Korea has been working with a Komi of 6.5 moku for a long time now. Japan is still at 5.5 moku though.
Sure.
There we go.
4-3!
Umm... Hikaru.
Oh yeah, I'm placing it...
17-16!
This is really a lot of work.
It'll be fine once you get used to it.
You go over there! Over there! Otherwise it's not a match at all.
O-Okay!
I guess this is fine.
Go Sai.
10-3
You placed it in the wrong spot.
But 10-3 is over here.
But this is...
I sat over here so that's this and this is that and...
Stop calling it out then!
Point out where you want to go with that!
Yeah, I guess this is fine.
I guess this is fine.
You jerk! I give up!
You're not holding back at all are you!
Why you! The first time you played Touya you said it was a tutoring game and took it easy on him!
Come on Hikaru, one more game, one more game.
Hikaru! Why are you raising a ruckus all alone? Be quiet.
AHHHH! I resign!
Clean up the stones.
Huh? But! Clean up? But...
Hey Hikaru! Hikaru!
53... 54... 55... 56... I lose by 2 moku.
Yes! I beat Tsutsui-san giving him a 2 stone handicap!
Damn it!
I'm angry... why do I have to study for High school?
Shindou-kun's so much stronger... and Mitani's here...
and Fujisaki-san and Tsuda-san are here...
It's great! I want to keep playing here too!
Not just stopping by every now and then.
If you keep getting stronger like this, the winter tournament's going to be great!
Though we'll need another member.
I'll put up another poster, like last time.
You haven't been playing as many stupid moves lately.
I hope we don't experience what happened at the last tournament again.
I resign...
Touya!
Thanks for the game.
I resign.
Oh, you want to play till the end?
Thanks for the game.
We're going to win this time!
I can feel it myself, that I'm getting better!
What are you getting excited over?
Akota-san, that was a good move.
Really? Yeah, don't you think so?
But Shindou-kun's development is really astounding.
Your Go club must have taught you a great deal.
You're still a little weaker than me though, right Shindou-kun?
How's this?
I guess this is it. Please drop by every now and then?
He can't hear me. What great concentration he has.
Thanks teacher!
Thanks to you too Akota-san. It was fun!
Oh, wait! Hikaru!
Goodbye Teacher!
Hey wait a second!
Be careful!
Teacher! The reason he made a comeback is because I underestimated him.
I thought Shindou-kun would be weaker and because you complimented me on that move,
I lost concentration and...
Akota-san.
You didn't make any real mistakes.
That last match, the comeback that he made, that is his real strength.
It's not even a year since he started Go.
Is his club sponsor that strong?
Or is Shindou-kun that dedicated?
What is it Hikaru?
You really can't judge how strong your opponent is unless you're strong yourself...
Akota-san was really strong...
I finally understand that now.
But Hikaru you beat that Akota-san!
Yeah! I'll beat Mitani too someday!
Oh well, if Hikaru was this strong at that last tournament...
Maybe Touya-kun wouldn't have yelled out "Stop messing around!"
Umm... he's...
He's not someone you can catch up to getting a little stronger.
Yes! I beat Mitani at an even match!
I caught up! I caught up! I caught up to Mitani!
What are you talking about! You only won one game!
I want a rematch! A rematch!
Oh yes!
Did you hear me Shindou? I want a rematch!
I thought he'd catch up eventually... but he caught up to Mitani so quickly...
Maybe at the next tournament Shindou-kun can make our goal...
of defeating Kaiou come true...
Maybe... he'll make it come true...
Hikaru, buying manga again?
No, I need a reference book for English.
You really can't help me with English.
Of course not.
Is it over here?
Oh! Kaiou's first board!
Wait.
Do you have time?
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Today, let's learn about dame.
Place where neither Black nor White can benefit are called dame.
Where do you think the dame in this game are?
Here.
This one isn't a dame.
Okay, let's look at them both.
If Black plays here, nothing changes, right?
And even if White goes here, there is no benefit.
Now how about this one over here?
If Black plays here, White will lose a stone with Black's next move,
so it must move to protect.
That means that this was not a dame.
This one, however, is a dame.
These dame should be played before the game is over.
Also, fill in dame after the game is over to simplify counting.
To be continued
What do you want to know?
Your real strength.
Huh?
You can't possibly catch up to him unless you desperately run after him starting now.
Touya has already passed the Pro examinations.
I thought Insei's couldn't go to amateur tournaments...