この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
A month between the preliminaries and the finals...
A month and a half since the finals started...
You were getting stronger during all of that time.
I didn't change at all. That's the difference between us.
I can't hear anything your saying!
Hey! You're Shindou right?
What?
I'm leaving my dream of becoming a pro with you!
Waya, you'll be playing Shindou next.
Yeah, I'm at two losses. I'll pass if I beat Shindou, who's at three losses.
Well, either way, you'll just be watching us from above without a care in the world.
I do care about something.
I'll be playing Shindou in the last round.
It's not a throwaway match.
It may be the most important match for me out of the entire pro exam.
Did you always think so highly of Shindou?
I want to find out Shindou's strength...
His mysterious strength...
Forty-third match
Waya vs Shindou
I can't believe that he once hesitated because he feared my moves.
He's even getting better at Mokusan and Yose.
Is it all thanks to me that he can play a well balanced game now?
What is it Sai?
Hikaru, your moves here look like something that I might play.
You can tell?
I played there after thinking about what you might do.
I do it when I can't think of a good move.
I can sometimes come up with a good idea that way.
If you were me?
Yup!
I can tell because we're always playing together.
Always together...
How long will we be together?
I thought I'd never die...
I thought I'd be with Hikaru his entire life,
and that I would inhabit a Go board once Hikaru died,
and that I'd just have to wait until the next time I returned.
Now that I think about it... there's no guarantee of that...
Anywhere...
My match against Waya...
might be tougher than my match against Ochi...
While Ochi's already passed, Waya is just a step away from passing, so he'd be more desperate.
I already have three losses... I'm even more borderline than Waya is...
Dammit...
I'm a little scared of playing him.
Waya is under just as much pressure as you are.
Yeah...
Two more rounds...
Yes...
Right now... yes now is not the time to be worrying about myself.
The Twenty-Sixth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Morning.
Waya went to the match hall already.
W-What's your problem!?
You're looking forward to watching our game aren't you?
I guess you don't have to worry now that you've passed.
Hmm... you there.
Where do we place order for lunch?
Oh, right here.
Here.
Thanks.
You're wondering who I am? Shinoda-sensei, the Insei teacher,
couldn't make it today, so I'm here in his place.
What's your name?
Shindou, it's Shindou Hikaru.
Shindou-kun, how have you been doing so far?
I have three losses. I'll pass if I win the last two games.
Oh, wow. Good luck.
Thank you! Excuse me.
Hey!
Have I met you somewhere before?
Oh, I just have this feeling that we've met before.
Sai, do you know?
Nope.
Oh well, sorry for stopping you.
You're the boy that ruined a match during the Children's Go Tournament by commenting on it!
Oh! Now I remember!
He's the person that scolded you about it!
Close one, you should've played one above it.
Really...
'I accidentally chimed in' doesn't settle this.
Sorry...
Him!?
I-I already apologized for that!
Besides, Sai, you're the one that said that 1-2 was critical. Not me.
But you're the one that said it out loud!
I knew back then that you were exceptional.
You said that you're close to passing right?
So you're already almost a pro!
Oh, doesn't look like he's going to yell at me.
Nope.
I see. No wonder you were able to see that 1-2 was critical so quickly.
But I'm the one that saw it!
I still remember the shape!
Hikaru you... Hikaru... umm...
Right now, you could...
Right now I can?
You can do it but...
Alright!
I just said it on impulse, I'm sorry about that.
Ogata-san and Master Touya showed interest in you, too.
I have to tell them about you.
Those two already know about me.
What!? They already have their eyes on you!?
That's incredible!
Good luck with the pro exam, I'm looking forward to your passing.
Bye.
Thank you!
He reminds me of what the teacher from Kaiou was like when I played Su-Young.
Now I can believe, that you indeed did play that unbelievable match.
I will also remember, once more, the name Shindou Hikaru.
He recognized my strength! My strength!
Didn't...
doubt just cross my mind right now?
It is time.
Everyone, please go into the match hall.
Hey, Shindou!
Let's start!
Sure!
No... this isn't time to be worrying about myself.
Right now I need to be watching over Hikaru.
Please start your clocks.
Good luck!
Master!
It's already been five years... since Waya started studying under me.
Isn't this your fourth time taking the pro exam?
Why do you keep it up?
Kazuo!
How dare you say that! You're a pro player's son!
Listen, Waya!
You're doing well this year. If you still don't pass, you're no longer my student!
No longer my student!
Say it don't spray it, Dad!
Dear...
Don't pressure him so much, dad.
You've only lost two matches, right?
Th-Thanks for the food.
You've practically passed already!
Chieko! Stop pressuring Waya-kun.
I'll help!
Sankyu!
You told your family that you're eating here tonight, right?
Yes.
Finish cleaning up already.
I'll teach you again as soon as you're done.
Okay.
Kazuo! Drive him home after we're done.
Waya-kun! Treat me to something if you become a pro!
Idiot. You're supposed to treat him.
Saeki-san treated me when he became a pro.
Quiet! You two go away!
Really! You're both kids of a pro player, and neither of you can play!
And to think I taught you, too.
It just wasn't my thing.
I blame your teaching.
How long do you plan on being like this?
Master!
I...
Waya's white stones, have been working hard all game.
Let's fight!
If I turn this area under white's influence into my territory, your loss is definite.
You have to try to take some of it.
Come on let's play!
Okay.
If this black lives, you win.
If I kill this black, I win.
I would pass the pro exam.
Can I kill it?
Can I live?
Is there a way for black to live?
A way for black to live...
Master...
Waya...
Yes!
You're a good student.
You're obedient and earnest, despite your age.
But don't expect to be babied just because of that!
If black goes there, I'll extend.
No... it would be better if I just do a sagari.
Okay! He can't do anything there.
I've had a few students.
There were a few who couldn't become pros.
But you are different!
You have the potential.
I'll do a sagari if black does a two space jump to a tsuke.
Okay, I can kill that too.
Listen, you WILL pass!
I'll say it as many times as I have to.
You WILL pass!
No way!
Have faith in yourself, Waya.
Hurry!
Become a pro!
There's no way for black to live!
I won!
There is...
There is a way for black to live.
It's difficult to see and carry out.
But... there is just one way.
Damn...
I don't see...
a way for black to live...
Master! I can do it!
I can become a pro!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
I'll talk about the maxim "hane two stones blindly" today.
This maxim says that white should play a hane right away when there are two stones lined up like this.
Doesn't black look cramped when white plays here?
He might get taken.
And it looks like white can develop over here.
But what if black extends here?
White is in danger.
It looks a little scary for white, and black can develop here now.
Yup. This is a spot that neither of them can give up.
If you're in a situation like this as white, play a hane right away.
Please remember "hane two stones blindly!"
To be continued...
Okay!
Then if I win the last match will you recognize me as a rival!?
You'll lose if you underestimate him!
I fell sorry for Waya but... Fuku has the advantage.
I passed!
Master!