Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Ogata-san!
Tell me! Shindou's game from yesterday, something... something happened right!?
You saw what happened.
Ogata-san, what I want to know is...
...that awkward stone formation. I can't imagine what order the moves went in, to form that shape.
Something must have happened!? Exactly what did Shindou do!?
His bad move from earlier, turned into a good one.
What a guy... it was a bad move at that point.
Don't be so impatient.
The answer will come to you soon.
In another two months...
The pro exams...
Yes. He's now walking the path that you went through a year ago.
Isn't Kadowaki the guy that got the 3 titles Student Meijin, Student Honinbou, and Student Jyukketsu? That Kadowaki?
I can't believe you know that Isumi-san.
There was quite a commotion over him.
So Kadowaki is...
Thirtieth match
Ogata Vs Honinbou
Haven't been here since the Meijin match college.
Oh yeah...
It's me. I'm at a place full of memories right now.
The team match, we lost it thanks to you didn't we?
I told you! I'm taking the pro exam.
Yes really. I have all the paperwork.
Yeah! I'll be a pro player next year. If you want an autograph, ask now while you still have a chance.
Later.
Kadowaki's probably going to be tough.
But is he really taking the pro exams?
I heard on the net he might.
We Inseis have to work hard this year. Mashiba was the only Insei to pass last year.
Lots of strong players come from the outside.
Kadowaki, gotta watch out for him.
Damn those Insei brats, they didn't even recognize me.
Heard on the net? Gotta be that guy then.
Look forward to my play!
Leave it to me.
I resign.
What is he laughing about?
He's creeping me out.
Thank you very much.
They say that you don't get worse even if you don't play Go for awhile. But I should get my senses sharpened.
The teacher yelled at me.
You resigned too quickly?
Who was that?
He was so creepy.
Are you an Insei?
Might as well warm up a bit for the pro exams.
The pro exams are coming up. Are you taking it?
Who are you old man?
Old man!?
Well, it's normal to become a pro in your teens in the Go world, I guess a 26 year old like myself is just an old man...
Oh, I have a bit of confidence in my play, do you want to play a game?
Now!?
It's still light outside. Come on! Let me warm u... uhh... test my skills.
Okay! Let's play!
Sai!
Wow, there was a place like this in the Institute?
It's where the normal customers play. You didn't know about it?
Hikaru?
Yeah.
You play.
It's just a random game, so there's nothing to wrong with you playing it.
He says he wants to test his strength. So he's probably decently strong too.
We go first. Sai!
Good luck.
Sai?
This is the first time I've played someone other than Hikaru since I played Touya Akira on the internet.
Don't think too much. I want to go home before it gets dark.
Okay.
Upper-right corner, komoku!
Seventh game of the Honinbou game
The first day will done in two more minutes.
Master Kuwabara will probably be sealing the move.
But it really is already the seventh game of the Honinbou match...
I totally thought that Master Ogata was going to take the title when he won the first match two months ago.
But he managed to drag it into the seventh match today.
Master Kuwabara sure is stubborn.
Mr. Ogata has much more energy, but Kuwabara's experience must be working to his benefit.
It's time...
It's time, so please seal the next move.
It's been half an hour already...
The Kifu...
Oh! Here!
Here you go.
Okay.
I'm starved! Let's eat! Let's eat!
There's a store with great eel around here. Record keeper boy, come with us.
Thank you!
I'll go change, so please wait for me in the lobby.
Kakimoto-san, you're coming too right?
I'll be right down, as soon as I store this sealed move in the vault.
Mr. Ogata, will you be coming too?
No, I'll eat alone.
I'll be right down.
Okay.
Ogata-kun!
You already think you've taken the Honinbou title, don't you?
You must be joking. The match has only begun.
Yes! It won't be decided till tomorrow.
Speaking of which, did you seal your move properly?
It's your first time sealing a move right?
This Honinbou match is the first time you've played Go over two days,
and I've sealed every move up to now.
What are you trying to say?
I just hope you didn't mark it wrong.
Mark it wrong?
People do make mistakes. It really did happen once before.
Someone marking it wrong that is...
It's only natural to get nervous in a challenging match for a title.
Weren't you a little nervous about your first time sealing a move?
Didn't you have trouble trying to decide where to go?
Is A better? Or is B better?
You may have written B even though you wanted to write A.
You've been in front of the Go board all day, you must be tired.
Are you sure? That you wrote it correctly?
The six previous matches... did he not let me seal the move on purpose!?
They couldn't all have been so. But between his plottings and coincidence, he weaved a small trap to make me panic.
You're getting worried aren't you!?
Old man...
Well, let's go eat now!
You said earlier that you had a feeling that a new wave was coming upon the Go world.
Sounds interesting. It's still to early to leave then.
I think I'll face that wave, keeping this title of Honinbou.
I resign.
T-Thanks for the game.
H-He's really strong.
Are you... really an Insei?
Oh crap!
Wait!
Hey you!
Sorry! I'm in a hurry!
How long have you been playing Go!?
A thousand years!
What is it?
I'm not doing it.
What do you mean what? The pro exam.
I'm not doing it, I underestimated them too much.
NO! That's not it. Moron. You wouldn't understand.
I'm gonna re-train myself for a year.
Yeah. I said I'm gonna take it next year.
I'm going to do my best. My very best.
It's time, so please begin.
Kakimoto
3-12
3-12... so he decided that going for the left side was the best.
I guessed wrong...
Did you have a nice night's sleep, Ogata-kun?
Did something happen between Mr. Ogata and Master Kuwabara?
I have no intentions of listening to an old man's ramblings.
I will take the seat of Honinbou.
The next generation is almost here!
Honinbou Match Seventh Game
Kuwabara Honinbou Defends His Title
Hey! Is it true that neither Waya nor Isumi-san have to take the preliminaries for the pro exams?
Yeah. The top eight in the Insei rankings don't have to take the preliminaries.
I was ninth last year, man that sucked.
Oh yeah!
I rose up to seventh this month!
Sorry, it's your average ranking during the last three months that needs to be in the top eight.
This is the last Insei study session.
The pro exams will begin as soon as we enter.
Good luck! I'm looking forward to seeing you during the first match of the actual exam.
Yeah.
Later.
See you at the exam.
I've got to go to the bathroom.
Shindou was laughing... does he understand that we're all rivals?
Ochi...
He lost to me.
We're all desperate, only three of us can become pro.
I won't lose!
Shindou... we can't all pass it together...
It's finally time!
Kyu Ranked Players Day 2nd Floor
Public Match Room 2nd Floor
Pro Examination 6th Floor
Today's Events
I'm finally here...
You're finally here? Your journey starts here.
I know!
But... I really am here...
The first day of the Pro Exam Preliminaries!
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
The "Igo Asia Cup in Okinawa" was held between March 22 and 23.
The Korean team scored an overwhelming victory.
Please say a few words to our young Go fans out there.
The manga Hikaru no Go is very interesting.
Learning Go is a lot of fun.
Children in Japan,
Go is easy to learn, so please learn it and have fun!
Thank you very much.
To be continued
Hikaru... are you nervous?
It doesn't matter who my opponent is!
I calmed down with those 30 minutes.
While you probably became upset.
Shindou can't do it...