Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
You won?
Yup! My first victory!
Touya...
Touya!
He came to see if I was here.
What are you talking about? He completely ignored you.
How are you guys rivals?
He said he'd never appear before me again... he's waiting for me.
He's waiting for me to rise up to him.
Look this way please.
Change of plans, I'll crush him.
Twenty-fourth match
Ouza Vs Akira
The depth of spiritual wonder
I envy them... They're going to go watch Touya's match...
We played Touya four times to the day.
Yeah, but we've never seen him play anyone else.
And his opponent is the Ouza!
Ahh! I wanna watch!
Hikaru! Hikaru! I'll play just this game for you.
I'll finish it in a blink of an eye!
Idiot.
Excuse me.
Oh! Waya! Isumi-san.
Mashiba-san...
Oh Isumi-kun, how are you doing?
Yes.
We'll place the game from move one for you.
I'll place white.
Touya Akira draws a lot of attention.
I wish you would pass the pro exams next year, Isumi-kun.
Oh, yes.
Isumi-san is stronger than I am. I just passed out of luck.
Tsk. Mashiba-san's gloating over how he passed.
Luck is apart of your skills.
Mashiba-kun might be the first person to defeat Touya Akira.
That would be great!
No offense, but none of you will be able to defeat Touya Akira.
Even Zama-sensei is struggling.
Look! Zama-sensei used a double-hane here!
It's not the way an Ouza would play against a mere new pro.
He is desperate.
A title holder should just connect here.
Zama-sensei intends to win no matter what.
Isumi-san, let's replay the game over there.
But Touya-kun's playing really well on the black.
Zama-sensei's probably biting the tip of his fan right now.
Oh! That habit Zama-sensei has when he's serious!
I'll go take a look.
There! End game!
How is it!
Hikaru you won by 2 and a half moku! Well done!
Great! I lost my focus half way through because of Touya's match, but...
20... 40... 50... 58!
Nope. I'm two and a half short. I lost.
Thank you for the games!
Hey. Right here, did I respond incorrectly? Shindou-kun, you seemed to move in really well.
Umm... ahh...
Come on! Come on! Let's go watch Touya's match! Come on! Come on!
Hmm... you played well there, but it can get difficult depending on how your opponent responds.
Are you!?
Going to discuss the game!?
Here...
Teacher, you don't go over the game with us every time! Why do you have to choose a time like this to!
Teacher! I'll... I'll make sure Hikaru reviews the game once we get home, so please make it short!
He tossed it in! That's really aggressive!
Zama can cut a point in Touya's formation at this point, so Touya should have connected there to play it safe. Instead Touya is threatening to capture the stones that are threatening him. It's a very risky move.
Touya tosses his stone in
Biting the fan!
Black's throw in is a strong move that won't let white relax at all.
Everything depends upon white's response to it.
If white cuts, the battle will be very complex. Black will be in danger, but white will be in danger too.
X
He captured instead of cutting!
White coward out!
The Ouza avoided a battle!
If white had cut, this, and this?
Yeah... both white and black are in danger but...
Zama-sensei probably avoided battle out of confidence.
No he didn't. He thought he shouldn't cross a faulty bridge against a mere new pro.
He's hesitating over Touya Akira's strength.
Zama-sensei must be really bitter over that. He didn't just pull back, he's coming into action in a lot of places.
But will he have a chance to come back?
Black's in the lead! Protect your territory and run towards the goal Akira-kun!
No, no. The Ouza won't let it end like this.
Not yet...
I won't defend just yet.
I'll move onward still!
A Kifu of this match will remain. Shindou will probably see it too.
I'll show you!
Each of my moves!
Keima!?
You're not defending the lower side!? You're going to keep fighting!?
But, he's going to leave a weakness in his own territory right?
Touya's well aware of that.
And he still attacks. Is Touya that type of guy?
Of course, Zama-sensei will attack him through that weakness.
Zama-sensei's thinking?
This is...
How's Touya doing?
Another observer?
Shindou! Over here.
Waya... Isumi-san.
Come over here, we'll replay the game for you.
Touya is black and the Ouza is white.
There's a handicap, not only does he go first black also gets 5.5 moku Komi.
Oh, there's a handicap?
It's between a top pro and a new first dan. Of course you'll need a handicap to make it a good match.
This is actually not enough for the new first dan, but the top pro doesn't play seriously, so it turns out to be a close match.
Then Touya's got an easy win?
But the Ouza is playing seriously today.
Using all his strength.
But Touya's winning.
Yeah! White responds by taking instead of cutting to blacks throw in.
The Ouza is playing carefully! Against a new first dan!
He's playing patiently, not rushing the game, protecting his weakness, and waiting for his opponent to make a mistake.
And take the win for himself in the end.
That's how Zama-sensei is playing today.
But, Touya played here, instead of protecting here.
He didn't protect!?
This is more interesting... but if white comes in here...
Ouza just went in there!
Black should be well aware that white will move into where black's control is weak.
How will you fight Touya Akira?
How will you fight Zama-Ouza?
Touya... you really are incredible.
You can win if you just protected... but you still attack... what's pushing Akira-kun like this?
I know... Touya...
you're telling me to come all this way right?
I'll walk forward, headed towards you.
Just you wait! I will... I'll definitely catch up to you!
It's snowing...
Even after a thousand years has passed, it is all still here...
snow... and the fierce wars on the board.
Each move speaks...
of the heart of the ones placing the stones.
Now, the sound of the stones is resounding through that stinging air.
Come after me with his skills?
Then, I'll move forward, to a place that he can never reach!
I won't let him come near me!
It doesn't matter who chases after me from behind.
What I see is the 500 pro players.
And just forward! I'll just move forward!
I won't even turn to you!
You're soft.
Did you think I'd respond here?
I won't.
You planned on coming here after that move right?
Too late.
If it's a young one studying under the Touya family, he probably would've responded there by impulse.
Hey! Who do you think is sitting before you right now?
Now it's even.
He was caught off guard...
That last move made the winner uncertain...
That's Zama sensei... I would've responded there on impulse...
It's already in the end game...
This is close.
Hikaru?
Will the match end with the victor uncertain?
It won't!
Touya won't let it end here, with the way he's been playing up to now!
If they enter the last round even, he'll try to go for a KO!
Black, that's too far. He'll get cut off!
Too far!?
You went in too deep Akira-kun! You haven't read through Ouza's responses!
He resigned....
Now for the post game discussion.
Though he was defeated, that was a very good game by Touya-kun.
Yes. He did well in chasing the Ouza back that far.
Shall we say to Zama-sensei "Good job"?
Isumi-san... wanna go?
They probably won't tell us to get out...
I'll go next year.
Yeah!
It's late, let's go home.
Shindou, let's go home.
I'll stay here a bit longer.
See ya. We're going now.
Touya got defeated trying to go for a KO...
so he loses to people other than Sai...
But I... won't forget his match today.
Yes. Touya's play today was worth watching.
It was exciting!
Wow! The snow is incredible!
Touya's going to keep moving forward right!?
Man he's really worth chasing!
But, Hikaru you've come along way too.
Yeah. It's all thanks to Touya.
If I keep chasing after Touya, maybe I'll be able to become Meijin or anything I want!
Touya Akira probably would have kept walking his own path without stopping if he hadn't met Hikaru.
He stops and turns back, and pulls Hikaru along.
As if...
The existence of Touya Akira...
was placed here by God...
to make Hikaru grow.
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Today, let's learn about geta (net).
There is a good move to capture this single white stone.
Where would that be?
Think about it, Yuki.
If I go here...
And if I go here...
Yes, good job!
Playing here to stop your
opponent's movement is called geta.
Mai, how about this one?
Here.
And if I go here...
I'll go here.
Yes, you succeeded in capturing them!
Geta occur often in games, so take this opportunity to learn it.
All right!
To be continued
I'll rise up to first class right away!
I want to go to the Wakajishisen!
No, I have to go!
Otherwise, I can't say "To defeat Touya Akira" anymore!
Hikaru you are afraid.
My moves that cut into you on the board.