Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
If I could...
could...
play like that!
Hikaru...
Fourth match
Kaga of the Shougi Club
Shougi is the Japanese equivalent of Chess. It's a much easier game than Go, and nowhere near as much fun.
Sai...
Did you...
Just...
Take over...
What?
Hey you!
Exactly what happened?
Should I not have forced him to come?
How is he?
There is no disturbance in the flow of his stones...
and no weaknesses to take advantage of...
a perfect example of pro play.
Then...
That's all I can say from a few opening moves.
I can't say anything about his strength.
Oh...
But...
But?
Nevermind...
That last move... was different...
It could be considered a bad move...
But...
You bastard!
You took over my body didn't you!?
How strange? What is he doing?
You didn't just enter my consciousness, but tried to take my body as well!
There's no way I could've played like that!
N-no!
I can't take over someone's body!
Then are you saying that I placed the stone like that?
Yes!
Lair!
Then try placing the stone over there the way you would a Go stone...
Position your hand like this.
Like this?
Yes.
Okay!
I can't do it!
But you did play that!
You didn't even play it in the place I told you to!
Yeah right!
You're plotting to take over my body when you get the chance aren't you!?
Whatever!
Delude yourself like that if you want!
But Hikaru...
that was your move.
You're starting to learn Go...
and you must've felt that you wanted to play the stone there.
Ah!
But, Touya-Meijin was so awesome!
Touya probably learned how to play Go from him.
I can't even pick up a stone properly.
Hikaru...
Come on...
Try once more.
Give it up...
I know I can't do it.
Hikaru!
Akari...
I just stopped by your house.
What were you doing all this time?
I was playing Go.
Go...
Again?
Hikaru, are you into Go right now?
I'm not into it or anything.
Oh...
This...
My sister's Junior High School is having an anniversary festival.
Let's go!
No way!
Why?
And I was going to buy you some takoyaki too...
Takoyaki is basically octopus cooked in a ball.
It's okay!
It's 2 o'clock this Sunday in front of Haze Junior High...
I said I'm not going.
Hikaru...
Well I guess I'll go home and have some noodles.
Two o'clock in front of the gate to Haze Junior High okay!?
Why don't you go with her?
No way!
Imagine what everyone will say if I go someplace like that with a girl.
Maybe she likes you Hikaru.
What!?
What did you just say!?
Haze Junior High School 12th Anniversary Festival
Welcome to Haze Junior High
Haze Junior High Anniversary Festival
That girl...
SHE'S NOT HERE!!!
Is this a festival of some sort?
A festival run by a shrine school?
Well... something like that.
But more importantly... I didn't bring any money!
Hey, I got some takoyaki.
Looks so good, I wanna have some too.
Hikaru, look over there!
TEA CEREMONY
Go
Look!
They're playing Go!
Let's go!
Come on, come on, come on!
Only for a little bit okay?
Here's a problem for a mid-kyu player.
Ranking in Go is determined with dan and kyu, the strongest player is 9-dan, then 8-dan, down to 1-dan, and under that is kyu, kyu starts at 1 kyu, and then down to 2 kyu, and onwards. A mid-kyu player would be about 5~12 kyu.
Please show the first 3 moves.
Well...
First black should tsuke,
Tsuke is a move in which a stone is placed immediately adjacent to a stone of the other side.
then white move...
here.
And what if white moves here?
Oh yeah!
This is quite hard.
Hikaru...
What's this book?
Assorted Tsumego from Touya Meijin's Matches...
Tsumego is a term for Go problems, usually life-death problems, but not necessarily so.
It's the prize for someone who gets a tsumego right.
Would you like to try?
Hikaru! I want it! I want it!
Fine! Fine!
Go on.
Thanks.
What grade are you in?
Grade school, grade 6.
Then let's start with an easy problem.
Here you go.
I think I can do this on my own...
Sai you keep quiet.
Okay.
Very good, very good... it's right.
Here's your prize.
Huh!? Kleenex?
Can you give me a harder one?
A harder one?
Are you sure?
Sai, I'm counting on you...
Okay.
Here's a problem for a low-dan players.
Even I would have trouble with this one.
Show me the first 3 moves.
That's right...
That was fast...
He answered in an instant...
Here's a can of orange juice.
Give me the toughest one that I can win tsumego book with.
The hardest?
Here...
If you get this, you're on the same level as Touya Akira.
Touya Akira?
I know him!
Is he really that strong?
He's probably good enough to pass the pro exam.
He tutors adults in Go.
Touya Akira may be able to get this problem...
Go on, the first move is the key.
Touya Akira would...
Okay...
Would you like to try on your own?
Hisha is a piece in Shougi, the Japanese equivalent of Chess, and is basically a rook.
Hisha
The first move... here right?
What do you think you're doing!?
Igo's so stupid.
What's so great about Touya Akira?
He's a loser that lost to me.
Shougi is a hundred times more fun than Go.
Touya lost?
He's as strong as a pro and he lost?
I'm strong that's all, moron.
He's Kaga.
He was in the same Igo class as Touya Akira.
He solved this difficult Tsumego in an instant.
This boy...
Who is he?
Tsutsui, how's your Go club going?
You were desperately searching for members, weren't you?
I can play for you guys if you want me to.
Go club?
Our school doesn't have a Go club.
If I can get 3 people to participate in a tournament...
the school will recognize us as a club.
You know how strong I am.
I'm a thousand times stronger than you are.
I won't accept help from someone who'd place gum on the board.
You sure talk big.
Who was it that came to me earlier begging me to enter the tournament?
Here's your prize.
Take it and leave.
Assorted Tsumego from Touya Meijin's Matches...?
I... HATE... GO... AND TOUYA AKIRA!
What!?
Tell me why you hate Touya Akira!
Tell you why?
You're telling me what to do?
Hey you, don't get too cocky.
You've got some guts.
Look carefully.
Which hand is it in?
If you get it right, I'll tell you.
But if you get it wrong, I'll beat you to a pulp.
What do you think you're doing Kaga!?
Hey you, go home already.
Ha! You talk big.
But you can't back up your words, is that it?
Hikaru...
You shouldn't.
I sense strength in him.
If you want to fight him, fight him in Go.
I can beat him at Go.
There's no guarantee at all that you'll win.
He's strong.
Then what about...
what about me!?
Hikaru?
It's this one!
Hikaru!
I guess you do have some guts.
There are no stones!
Kaga... you!
You gullible of you to fall for that!
Hey, why don't you quit Go and come to Shougi?
I'll teach you everything.
Fuck off!
I'd rather never learn Shougi than to have you teach me!
What?
Stop it, both of you!
You won against Touya!?
You probably cheated like you just did.
Either that or Touya wasn't trying.
After all, you probably just ran away to Shougi because you couldn't handle Go.
Tsutsui let him go!
You think I'm a loser?
I'll show you how strong I am!
KING
If I lose, I'll bow to you as king or whatever.
But if you lose, go jump in an ice cold pool!
Okay!
Sai!
17-4, upper-right corner, komoku.
What's with the way you hold your stone!?
The way I hold my stone doesn't matter!
15-4
Shoot off your mouth like that AFTER you win.
How can a guy like this understand me?
A guy like this...
Go Classroom
Tetsou!
Why do you always lose to that boy?
Touya Akira.
Thanks to that, you're always #2, don't you feel ashamed, you're 2 whole years older than him.
Of course I want to win...
but Touya Akira is...
Beat him today! I won't let you in the house until you beat him!
There's nothing I can do. Strong guys are just strong.
There's no doubt about it, you play go at a totally different level.
You're the undisputed top, but one day I'll surpass you and become #1.
Get ready for it.
Okay, let's begin.
Do you want me to lose?
Want... me... to lose?
Bastard...
I...
I thought of him as a rival.
But he didn't even care about me.
It didn't matter to him whether he won against me or lost against me!
At the end of the game, I won by one and a half moku with komi...
that bastard...
Once my dad knew that I couldn't be the best so long as he was there, he gave up immediately.
That bastard...
But... this guy...
He's pretty good...
Wow...
This kid is pretty good.
Hey, you've gotta be kidding.
He's messing around with me on the board.
11-15
14-16
How entertaining!
This boy is no where near as strong as Touya Akira...
but he returns my moves with very entertaining moves.
There's no problem in winning...
but I want to keep having fun...
Black looks to be in danger, but I think he can make it...
which means...
It's even...
No, black's ahead.
9-19
Oh really?
His face was all red, and he shouted "Stop messing with me!"
Akari!
Finally she shows up.
Hurry up and move!
Oh, sorry.
Hikaru! That's not it!
W-Wait!
Wait?
You've gotta be kidding.
Oh no, it died...
There is no choice...
12-15
That last move killed you.
What!?
That many!?
Time to resign perhaps?
An ice cold pool awaits you...
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
What are these?
They're just plastic bottle caps, aren't they?
Today, we'll be playing on this.
It's so small...
This is a 6x6 Go board. It is more than big enough at the start.
The first player to capture three stones is the winner.
Okay...
Okay, let's play.
Onegaishimasu!
Make a 6x6 board by drawing lines on stiff poster board
What will you do now?
Make Go pieces using plastic bottle caps
That's a great move!
Okay!
Mai is the winner! Congratulations!
Then you thank your opponent.
Thank you very much!
To be continued
Sai you told me it would be okay!
Tsutsui, we have a team for the Go tournament.
I think I understand now...
Why I was drawn to Hikaru.
Once you place a stone, you cannot move it.
That is the weight of a move.