この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
This atmosphere...
It feels familiar.
Yes! This atmosphere...
This feeling of pressure...
I've felt it before.
This is...
It's the old Shindou...
that I see in Sai!
I... finally understand.
God has...
given me a thousand years...
just to show Hikaru this match.
Fifty-seventh match
Let Me Play Sai!
Hikaru...
Father...
Sai...
It's Sai...
Ah! The wind feels great!
Say,
Sai.
You told me before...
that only the people playing the game can see some things.
Well, being where I was during that game it felt as if...
I could see what you were thinking,
and I could see what Master Touya was thinking.
I felt as if I was in the very middle of that match today.
Master Touya must be really disappointed, losing to Sai!
If I lose this match, I will retire.
Did he really mean that!?
Ah, that was close.
Well...
I came here first thing in the morning, but...
He can't really be serious, can he?
I mean, it's crazy!
Someone with five titles can't just retire... right?
Y-yes...
What? Were you thinking about something else?
Ahh! Why am I always the one that has to worry?
Let's go, Sai.
Touya Kouyou-sama
Akira-san?
G-Good morning.
I'm sorry, who were you again?
Touya's mom!
Ummm... I...
He's Shindou-kun, he just became a pro this year.
Remember? We played once.
Ah, yes! I remember seeing you in weekly Go.
You're the same age as Akira-san, right?
Akiko... I'm sorry, but could you leave the room for a minute?
Okay, okay.
Umm...
Master, you resigned yesterday, but...
you won't retire... right?
You said that you'd retire if you lost to Sai on impulse, right?
Right?
I just wanted to make sure...
Are you...
Sai...
No! No! It's not me! Why do you think I'm Sai!?
He reminded me of you during the game...
of the feeling I got when we played in the Room of Deep Contemplation.
Sorry.
I won't pursue it.
I don't care who Sai is.
Shindou-kun...
Let me...
Let me play Sai again!
I don't care if it's on the net.
I won't ask him to tell me who he is anymore.
Again?
Oh yeah...
We could do that if he plans to continue to play on the net.
Yeah.
Master Touya would probably keep it a secret from anyone else.
I can probably let Sai play from time to time.
He would probably like that a lot.
It's too late...
I probably don't...
have enough time for that.
I can feel it...
Inside me...
The sands of time that were frozen within me...
are mercilessly and without doubt... starting to flow once more.
Master...
Then... if I let you play him again, will you take back what you said about retiring?
I won't take back what I said.
I intend to retire after the upcoming fifth game of the Jyudan match.
But I just asked you not to do anything crazy like that!
Retiring is not a great concern for me.
In fact, it might be for the better.
I'll be freed from th constraints and responsibilities that come from being a pro.
I won't have to accept any boring interviews.
It's not that I won't be able to play Go.
I have this existence.
The happiness of existing...
I can play an all absorbing game of Go outside of the title matches.
The match I played yesterday proves it!
I can play a game at that high of a level with someone I've never met before!
Let me play Sai again, Shindou-kun!
I have no idea who Sai is.
But...
There is someone connected to Sai nearby.
Is it Shindou...
or is it one of the other people that visited him?
Anyway, the person who heard that the Meijin plays go on the Internet,
and arranged the match...
Who is it?
Master Touya should know.
This voice...
Is it Shindou!?
I can't hear what they're saying.
That maybe okay for you, Master,
but not for me! I can't have that. It'll all be my fault.
You want to play Sai again don't you, Master?
Sai feels the same way! So please give up on that idea!
Hikaru!
Oga...
Sai...
you said!?
So you do know who Sai is!
No! No! No! I don't know him! I have no idea!
Ogata-kun!
Liar!
You just said...
Bye!
Wait!
Shindou!
Did you arrange the match between Sai and the Master!?
No! It wasn't me!
If you know who Sai is...
Let me play him, too!
Mr. Ogata...
M-Mr. Ogata...
You know Sai, don't you!?
If you know him then let me play him, too!
I-I don't know him! I don't know him!
I just... happened to be watching the game...
between Sai and Master Touya on the internet...
Shindou!
Touya...
Ogata-san!
Ogata-san...
What happened?
Shindou was visiting the Master in his room.
He ran away when I went in.
I heard some of what they were talking about.
Chances are, Shindou and Sai know each other.
He was denying it, but...
all we have to do is ask the Master.
They know each other...
No!
Shindou and Sai are...
Master.
Ogata-kun.
Akira...
It was Shindou, wasn't it, who arranged your match against Sai.
No.
Master!
He has nothing to do with it.
Sai challenged me to a game on the internet first thing in the morning yesterday.
That's all.
Seems like you both watched the match yesterday.
It was a game deserving of my name, wasn't it?
Well?
But... Sai went above me.
Akira-kun, ask him!
Don't you want to find out who Sai is as well?
If Father says that he doesn't know who Sai is...
there's no point in asking him about it any further.
Ogata-san thinks that Sai and Shindou are different people.
I don't have the answer for it yet.
But the one thing I know for certain is...
that Shindou holds the answer to all these mysteries.
There's nothing I can do if both Shindou and the Master deny it.
So this is it...
Oh! Akira-san.
Ogata-san, too?
Hello.
Did Shindou-kun leave?
Shindou-kun was just here.
Phew, that was close.
Seems like Mr. Ogata heard me talking about Sai.
And then Touya came in, too, to top it off.
I wonder if he still thinks that I'm Sai.
Well, I'm sure Master Touya won't tell them anything.
But I think I can let you play the Meijin again, Sai.
Sai?
What's wrong, you look sad.
I said that I can let you play him again some time.
Don't worry about it!
I'm sure that Master Touya won't tell anyone about me.
I can let you play from time to time.
From time to time?
How distant that sounds to me right now.
Hey! I just let you play yesterday!
Tsk. You're always asking for more. Let's go home.
Ahh! Dammit.
Well, I don't think we'll be able to play him for a bit,
because there will be a commotion over his retiring...
Don't be impatient, we've got plenty of time.
There is...
no time...
Hikaru may have it but...
I... don't...
Waya, is this it?
The game that Kouyou played on the internet?
Yes! I was watching this game from the start to end.
It's an awesome match! It really is.
Is Black Master Touya?
Yes.
But really... I can't see him using computers.
I thought that computers weren't for either of us...
Hello.
Hey, Shindou-kun.
Hey, Shindou.
It's Sai!
Sai came back to the Internet!
We're going over a game he played against Touya Meijin right now.
You saw it too, Waya?
I saw it too.
What!? You saw it too?
So the opponent, playing White, is Sai?
Yes. I told you about him before, Master.
I told you there was someone really strong on the Internet.
This is him!
And then Sai... White went here.
What an astounding move.
And then, it went like this...
and Black resigned here.
Game over.
Resigned!? Here!?
It's half a moku match...
White's winning? Isn't there anything Black can do?
What if he doesn't respond here?
No, that's definitely Sente.
White can't lose any more territory...
I'm starting to get a headache.
Well, the thing is...
What?
Black would've gained territory if he played in the corner instead of connecting here.
I see...
Oh!
You're right!
See? Black is ahead by a bit this way.
He'll need to move there once all the outside liberties are gone.
He can't move back there at this point either...
But you always miss stuff like this, Shindou!
Waya, stop making light of it!
This move decided the match.
Shindou-kun, have you calculated it out?
Oh! You noticed it because you usually don't calculate stuff out!
What did you say!?
Everyone is starting to notice the strength Hikaru has...
I can see it...
The brilliant future that is...
shinning about Hikaru... the future that I lack.
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Hey, Mai-chan, do you remember what Komi is?
Yup!
Well, Komi just changed from five and a half moku to six and a half moku.
Why?
It's because Black's win rate has been
significantly higher in the last five years.
Komi recently became seven and a half moku in China.
Since komi became six and a half moku in Korea,
Japan has decided to follow in thier footsteps and change komi to six and a half moku.
Note from translator: As stupid as this joke is, I have no choice but to explain it. 'Gomoku Gohan' is a type of food dish, and it sounds like 'Gomoku han' which is 5.5 moku.
I thought it was because people mistook it for Gomoku Gohan.
That's not quite it...
Komi didn't even exist in Shuusaku's time,
what a big difference that is from six and a half moku.
The rules of Go change with the time.
To be continued...
Okay! I'll see exactly how far I can go
playing against Kurata-san!
Huh?
They're both white...
Oh well, let's play like this.
It's one color Go.
One color Go?
It's just starting to get interesting.