この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Your name!?
Your name! I said I'd remember it.
My name is Shindou Hikaru!
Shindou... Hikaru...
Shindou-kun.
I'll carve it into my mind too...
The name Shindou Hikaru!
Thirty-seventh match
The Pro Exam Begins
Sai... it's finally time...
Yes.
I have to become pro... to catch up to Touya!
Pro Exam Finals
First Match
Shindou!
Waya!
Calm down, Hikaru.
I know.
You okay? You're all stiff.
No I'm not!
Though we're all just as nervous...
Morning!
We can put the drinks we bought into this fridge right?
Hey, do you think I can put bread in there?
Probably.
Shindou!
Isumi-san!
Hey! Long time no see!
Tsubaki!
You can't call someone older than you directly!
Tsubaki... san...
Good!
Is that the guy Shindou was scared of?
Probably.
Aren't you glad you made it to the finals?
What is it?
Now that I look at it, you're cuter than Kawai-san is.
Huh? Kawai-san?
He's someone that always does this to me.
What are you doing!? Do it to that Kawai-san guy!
I can't do it to Kawai-san. He's too scary.
But Tsubaki-san's a lot better at Go than Kawai-san.
Of course I am.
I'm looking forward to playing you. I have to take another win from ya.
I won't let you this time!
Hikaru...
Oh! You're talking back?
Shindou's changed since the preliminaries...
Okay. If you're going to order a lunch, please place your order here.
I wonder what they have.
Please place your order by 10.
What about you?
My mom packed me a lunch!
Hikaru! You don't seem scared of the bearded man anymore.
Hehe, actually I used him to calm down.
That's a huge improvement!
Let's go to the match hall early.
Okay.
The finals is a round robin tournament that meets three times a week on Sundays, Tuesdays, and Saturdays for two months.
There are 28 participants this year.
Are we deciding today's opponent by lottery again?
Yeah. Only the top three pass.
Three...
It's the guy I lost to during the preliminaries.
Hikaru's attitude has changed significantly from before.
Hikaru, you're trembling with excitement.
Your confidence in being able to bring out all of your strength,
the way you did against Su-Young is making you yearn for battle.
In a wish to test your own strength.
Shindou.
Iijima-san.
I hear you passed the preliminaries with a win by default.
That was close.
Even if I just barely passed. Passing is passing. It's no different.
It's time, so please gather in the match hall.
Okay, we'll begin drawing lots now.
Please come up here once you've been called.
Nakamura-kun.
Hayashi-kun.
Sasaki-san.
I'm number four.
Nakamura-kun's number four.
Please hold onto your sheet.
Shindou-kun.
Here.
You only draw lots on the first day. The tournament chart's already been filled.
I'm number 7.
Once your number has been decided. Your opponents for the entire exam are decided.
I'm playing Iijima-san on the first day.
Shindou...
Set your game clocks to three hours each. Clock count is a minute per move. Komi is set to 5.5 moku.
Please begin then.
Good luck.
Oh yes, I should place the order for the lunch.
Hmm? Not even five minutes passed yet.
Yes. Calm down first.
Him too?
This doesn't happen in any normal match.
The pro exam really is...
What's the matter?
It's the first day, there's so much tension in the air, I can't bear to stay here.
I'll be in the lounge on the second floor until lunch.
Yeah.
My goal isn't to just pass. It's to pass in first place.
It's begun. The long long pro exam...
Only three people will pass.
I can't panic.
This year I'll...
He's calm.
Is it because he's playing me?
Or is it because he's used to the exam?
He's very different than he was at the preliminaries.
I don't want to lose on the first day!
The pro exam only happens once a year!
It's time, so please halt your clocks.
Time for lunch! Lunch!
Yup! Lunch! Lunch!
Huh? You're full of confidence.
They look more like best friends than anything else.
I guess it's because we went to the Go salons.
Go salons?
Isumi-san and I took him around.
He said that he had never played at a Go salon before.
Why the fuck did you do that? Why did you make your rival stronger!?
Mr. Morishita always says that people who will become strong will become strong no matter what.
But you didn't have to help him right before the pro exams!
Are you stupid!?
I'm not stupid.
My teacher even says that I've become much stronger since Shindou started coming to the study sessions.
Yeah. It seems like taking care of Shindou's made you stronger too.
Really?
I'm doing really well right now. I can tell myself.
I'm going to pass this year!
Let's look at the pairings.
Pro Exam Pairings
I'm playing Shindou at...
Wow it's towards the end. The day before the last.
Isumi-san, I'll be playing you on the thirteenth match.
I've got them right in a row. Shindou on the twelfth match, you on the thirteenth match.
"You made your rival stronger... Are you stupid..."
If Shindou passes and we fail, we may just be stupid.
Please begin now.
I resign.
There are 27 matches total, I can't be getting excited over one win.
Hikaru... it seems you've taken another step.
Second Match of the Pro Exam Finals
I resign.
Second quarter began in school before I realized it.
Third Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Win by 6.5 moku.
I resign.
So far, the only undefeated people are Isumi-san, and me, and Waya, and...  Shindou too?
Oh well, it doesn't matter.
My goal is to pass with no losses.
Sixth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
I resign.
Four people with six straight wins?
Isumi-san, and Ochi, and Waya, and Shindou.
Waya's doing well. Even you lost right Honda-kun? Well, I lost too but...
I can understand Isumi-san and Ochi's six straight wins, but Shindou too?
It's just started. Even if you've lost six straight games, you can pass if you win all the rest.
Besides, all wins isn't all good. You might lose one game and collapse.
Okay I'm going to close up.
All wins isn't good? Of course it's all good.
I'm heading for all wins.
What's up with him!? It's just starting!
You're right. I doubt Shindou will continue winning for too long.
Iijima-kun, you played Shindou on the first game right?
How was it?
He played a calm game, I got nervous so I lost.
He's changed.
You'll find out when you play him.
Maybe he'll pass.
Over here, it's tougher on white if you simply go to the kosumi instead of attacking him with a keima.
Okay.
I'll be going now then.
Thank you for coming.
Yasoki 7-dan is easy to understand.
Yesterday's Kigirai 8-dan was horrible at teaching.
That's no good.
But I wonder when it was that you learned Go.
I was the one paying pros to come and play tutoring games.
But you learned Go by watching me play, and you passed me quickly.
Right now, calling pros is all for you.
It's me, can you bring me a whiskey and water?
I'm happy that my grandson's aiming to become a pro.
Your father was no good. He didn't even touch the stones.
We'll get you practice at Go salons. I'll even have the pros come teach you everything.
I don't care how much it's costs.
How are the pro exams? Do you think you can pass with the top score?
I plan on doing so.
I passed Isumi-san and was first place on the last Insei rankings before the pro exams too.
Hmm, all the pros coming here have been set for this entire week.
But maybe we should get Touya 2-dan come sometime next week.
Touya 2-dan!?
He's passed with the top score last year.
Your pro exam will go on, so he can probably give you some advice.
But it's probably better to listen to a young person about stuff like that, rather than some old people.
Do you not want it?
No, that's okay.
I haven't played Touya 2-dan yet.
It's a great opportunity. I wanted to play him.
Once I become pro, we'll both be lower dan players. He's a rival that I may be playing immediately.
Pro Examination Scores
7 Shindou Hikaru
Six straight wins!?
Shindou... Shindou has six straight wins...
Even if he has six straight wins, the pro exams are long, six wins isn't very much.
But it's true that only four people are undefeated so far. Shindou is one of those four...
Tell me... tell me exactly how strong he is right now!
Akira-san, it's a phone call for you from the Go institute.
Okay. Going to someone's house to tutor them?
That's... no. It's not that I'm busy.
But could you turn them down?
I'd like to focus on my own studies.
Yes. I'm sorry.
Insei!? I'll be tutoring an Insei!?
Someone taking the exam right now?
I'll go! I'll go!
Yes please set it up.
Shindou...
I'm going to take a look at how strong you are right now.
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Today, we'll be explaining Go terminology again!
That's right.
When you play right next to your opponent's stone, it's called an attachment, tsuke.
When you play diagonally from an attachment, it's called a hane.
Against a hane, if you play right next to your stone, it's called extending, nobi.
Protecting against the cutting point between these two stones....
is called connecting, tsugi.
If Black doesn't connect and White separates these two stones,
this is called a cross-cut, kiri.
If you learn Go terminology, you'll know what Sai is talking about
and understand the explanations,
and that will make Go even more fun.
To be continued
I want to find out how strong Shindou is.
You don't think I can beat Shindou?
Shindou will trip along the way.
Sorry but I'm going to beat you again.
He lost!? To who!?