この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
This is the last Insei study session.
The pro exams will begin as soon as we enter.
Good luck!
I'm looking forward to seeing you during the first match of the actual pro exam.
Shindou was laughing...
Does he understand that we're all rivals?
Thirty-first match
The Preliminary Starts
The pro exam preliminaries start today and go for five days. One match a day.
Those with three wins get to advance to the finals a month from now right?
Yeah.
But, I'm just going to play Go as usual, in the place that I normally play at.
Isumi-san, Waya, and the other top eight aren't in the preliminary, so that's good.
But the other Inseis are all coming.
Play normally...
that can be quite difficult.
Hikaru, will you be able to play as you normally do?
I'll be fine! I'll play the way I usually...
Is he... taking the test too!?
H-He's an old man!
Ahhhh! Summer is so incredibly hot!
Wow, what a beard that guy has!
What is it? You taking the pro exam too?
You too?
Yeah...
Me too, nice to meet you.
That beard guy is taking the pro exam too?
Shindou, why are you just standing there?
Adults are here.
Of course. Outsiders take the exam too.
Outsiders?
You can qualify to take the test until you're thirty.
Former Inseis and people who...
did amateur tournaments come too.
Did you get any sleep last night?
Yeah.
Oh.
You fell asleep when we were learning Tsumego right?
Shut up.
What is it with your attitude!?
I'm talking to you! Why don't you respond instead of just ignoring me!?
HEY!
You idiot!
Huh?
Could you be quiet? You're a nuisance to everyone.
All I did was ask where he came from!
The exams are about to start. He doesn't want to talk.
Oh, so it's my fault!?
Is that what you're trying to say?
How can someone so impolite become a pro! Idiot!
Who's causing all the ruckus?
He's taking the exam?
Man, he's loud.
Hikaru! Let's put your bag away!
Huh? Yeah.
Let's...
Shindou-kun!
Fuku...
Morning!
What's wrong?
Yeah...
Umm...
There's a weird outsider here, and he's scared.
I'm not scared!
20 minutes left...
I played Touya-kun last year on the first day.
Touya?
Oh yeah...
As strong as he is, since he's not an Insei, he has to go through the preliminaries as an outsider.
That day during lunch, Touya-kun tried to talk to Waya-kun.
But Waya-kun just told him to shut up.
It's so weird.
Isn't it weird?
I'm walking the same path as Touya...
I'm a year behind but...
Yes... The same path.
If you go straight down this path, you will find Touya.
Yea, him.
It's almost time.
Well, we'll be drawing the pairings, so please come up as you are called.
Katagiri-kun.
Here!
Please draw your number here.
Murayama-kun!
Here!
Tsubaki-kun!
Here, here, here!
He's been talking so loudly! Is he trying to scare everyone?
Man, he annoys me. He'd better not cause a commotion during the matches.
Shindou-kun.
Shindou-kun!
Hikaru!
Here!
Hagino-kun, number 14.
Okay.
Hikaru... are you nervous?
Shindou-kun, number 21.
Please get seated.
Number 1 is to be seated on the far side, and continues with 2 and 3...
Huh?
Sup.
Worst possible opponent.
Be careful, he might start screaming like a monster during the match.
Shindou, you're rather unlucky.
Don't say that!
Please set your match clocks to 2 hours and byouyomi 1 minute.
Byouyomi is what happens when you run out of time. You get a set amount of time for a set number of moves. For example, if byouyomi is 10/25, you get 10 minutes for 25 moves.
You know who's black and who's white right?
It doesn't matter who my opponent is!
Then please start!
Good luck.
Okay.
Excuse me for a bit.
Hey... hey... what's going on!?
It's been more than half an hour. What exactly is he doing?
He returned and the game has resumed but...
Hikaru has lost his presence of mind.
It is time for lunch, so please halt your clocks.
Hey! Let's eat together!
Me?
You're an Insei right? Where do you usually eat? Show me around!
Hikaru! You can't go with him!
B-But!
Shindou-kun...
Hamburgers!? You've gotta be kidding!
Soba store
Let's eat at that Soba store! Okay? Soba!
Don't worry, it's on me. I won't make a kid pay.
No, it's not that...
Then what is it?
What's your name?
Shindou...
I'm called Tsubaki! As in the bud of a flower, isn't that cool?
Tsubaki means flower bud in Japanese.
There used to be a really strong Samurai called Tsubaki Sanjurou.
Hard to believe...
What's with that face?
Umm... mister. Where did you go during the first half hour of the match?
I circled around the block on my bike, to calm down a little.
Everyone here is nervous to a varying degree. I'm nervous too.
If you calm your emotions and play normally, you'd win.
If you play with stirred emotions, you'd lose.
I calmed down with those 30 minutes.
While you probably became upset.
We have two whole hours. It's up to me how I use the time.
Oh... You can use your time like that...
How much time do you Inseis play with?
First class has 60 minutes, second class has 30 minutes.
So you've never played with two hours time?
No.
Then this is your first time halting the game for lunch.
Yeah.
So that's why... you gave me the turn so quickly.
Huh?
The morning ended right after you played. What happens then is...
I can spend the entire lunch time thinking.
How would this move go? Or would this be better? How would he respond?
See, isn't it great?
You don't know how I'll play so you can't think. You'll just be spacing out the entire time.
And it seems like you're scared of my beard!
I'm not scared! I'm not!
You haven't played adults very much have you?
You won't ever be an adult unless you can come into a Soba store like this alone.
Eat already, the noodle's going to go bad.
I don't really like Soba.
He's completely been overwhelmed. There's no way he can win like this.
This is the end game.
You won?
I win by four and a half moku!
Thanks for the game.
Thanks for the game...
What's wrong? Don't get depressed over just one loss!
Though I understand how you feel.
But seems like I've gotten on rhythm thanks to you. Thanks a lot.
Well then!
What's with him!
Shindou-kun...
Shindou, you lost?
I didn't think about the turn before the lunch break at all...
Turn before the lunch break?
You're so stupid. That doesn't matter!
Really?
It's better to not think about anything during lunch!
You need to let loose!
I'd rather go into the lunch break on my opponent's turn.
I don't really care.
I'd like to go in on my own turn, just like that bearded guy said.
And then, I'd think about my next move during all of lunch.
You'll make a mistake if you think too much.
Don't worry, there's no gain or loss over whose turn it is going into lunch break.
We don't even seal the move.
Seal the move?
Sealing a move is sealing a move. You don't know what it is?
A match challenging a title is played over two days right?
So in that situation, they mark the last move if the day down on paper instead of actually playing it,
and unseal it on the next day when they resume the game.
It's fair that way.
Two days!? There are games that last two days!?
You didn't even know that?
Yes there are. There are games that you spend two days on.
Though the only people who play it are a few select individuals from the top ranks of the pro.
Our priority is the pro exam!
Listen, don't think about the match during the lunch break.
And, even if we do have two hours, leaving for the first half hour is obviously a plot to upset you!
A plot!
Shindou, you can't let something like that bother you!
We have three hours of time in the actual pro exams!
What are you upset over?
I'm playing that bearded guy tomorrow!
I'm not going to lose.
This is where I board the train. See ya.
Bye-bye.
Shindou...
He doesn't know much about the title matches does he?
No, he doesn't...
And he was scared of that bearded guy.
That bearded guy's an exception!
He's horrible!
Shindou's never even gotten molded by adults in a Go salon before...
People like us usually practice at Go salons right? Against high dan adult players.
Yeah, and then we follow a pro teacher.
But, Shindou learned from being in a Go club for a year.
And he doesn't even have much experience going to tournaments during that time.
He just went to some small tournament twice.
What are you trying to say?
A guy like that is already knocking on the gate to become pro.
He's a genius?
What I'm trying to say is that he seems unstable.
What goes up, must come down.
Though I'm just rambling.
Hikaru, your father and I are going out tomorrow, so can you watch the house?
I have the pro exams tomorrow too, so I can't.
What? What exam?
An exam to become a pro Go player.
Who's taking that?
Me.
What are you taking Hikaru?
Like I said, the pro exam!
Hikaru... you're taking... an exam to... become a pro Go player?
Yup.
What!? What are you thinking!? You're just a child.
What are you saying.
Huh? There are kids my age who are already pro!
But... I mean what is a pro Go player? You're going to become a pro?
You've never mentioned that to me.
Really?
Tomorrow? What is it? What are you doing Hikaru?
What is it all of a sudden?
You're the one that's suddenly bringing things up. I don't know anything about pro Go players.
Mom, you don't have to know anything.
See here, I don't think it's a bad thing that you're concentrating on Go.
But your semester finals were horrible!
If your grades were just a little higher, I wouldn't complain about you doing what you want.
Semester finals? If I pass the pro exams, that won't matter anymore.
I totally understand why Waya wants to become pro already.
I'm irritated right now because I lost today. So be quiet already.
Hey Hikaru!
Call me when dinner's ready.
Huh? What? Umm... pro? What? He's what?
Second day of Pro Exam Preliminaries.
That bearded guy's here already.
It doesn't matter. He's not my opponent anymore. I won't let him push me around anymore.
I just need to avoid him.
Words probably won't do any good right now. Hikaru...
He's not here...
Morning!
Mor...
Sup!
Good luck today. Don't worry about one loss.
I just have to win three games during the five days. Just win three.
Well, it's all over if you lose three times.
What's your problem! I've only lost one so far!
Shindou can't do it...
Please begin.
Good luck.
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Today, we will study tesuji.
It is White's turn in this shape.
White's stones are in jeopardy of being captured,
but they can be saved by capturing Black's stones.
What should White do?
What would you do, Mai?
They connected...
It was a good attempt, but you couldn't save them.
There should be a better move.
Oh? What?
He took it!
I got them!
Allowing your stones to be captured, then attacking was the best strategy.
To be continued
Shut up! I'm trying to think right now!
Play normally... that becomes harder as you become more desperate.
We might play each other tomorrow.
I resign...