Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
About time to resign?
An ice cold pool awaits you.
Fifth match
Prediction of an Awakening
I told you to wait!
Hikaru...
Once you place a stone, you cannot move it.
That is the weight of a move.
But!
Calm down Hikaru.
It's okay, there's still a chance we can win.
Now let's single-mindedly work towards defeating him.
Hey, did you just hear Hikaru's voice?
Huh? Shindou-kun?
Oh, I know!
You said you asked someone before us.
That was Shindou-kun right!
Oh!! Here!
What!?
Don't get mad.
Hey this takoyaki tastes great!
Let's go get another one.
Where did we get it again?
The other side of the school grounds.
This is delicious.
You've got something on your face.
Fortune Teller
Wasn't that show hilarious?
Yup
But the punchline was a little inappropriate.
Hey isn't that Shindou-kun?
Oh... he did come after all.
Well, we'll be going now.
Right!
But!
Say hi to Shindou-kun for me!
Come on!
Hikaru you came after all?
I came with Sayaka because you said you weren't coming.
What are you doing?
Go?
Again?
With the komi included, white 68.5 moku...
Black 68 moku...
We lost by half a moku...
We were a step short.
Dammit!
Sai, you told me it would be okay!
I did my best!
You moron! It's all your fault!
Nooo... an ice cold pool!
He caught up to half a moku from that condition...
U-Unbelievable...
this incredible chase...
after that stupid mess up that even Tsutsui wouldn't have made...
What do you mean by that!
Tsutsui...
take off your uniform.
Why!? Isn't he the one going into the pool.
Just take it off!
AHHH! An ice cold pool!
W-why did you do that?
Tsutsui, we have a team for the Go tournament.
Myself, you, and this kid!
Try out a tsumego
We can't do that!
You lost the game...
So just do what I tell you.
... when is that tournament?
This Sunday from 2PM.
Where is it?
Kaiou Junior High.
Kaiou Private Junior High School
To Third Annual North District Junior High
Winter Go Tournament Participants.
Wow!
So this is Kaiou Junior High school.
The Third Annual North District Junior High Winter Go Tournament Participants.
Let's see...
change into indoor shoes at the entrance...
and it's the second meeting room on the fourth floor of the main building...
I think I'll get lost...
Oh well, I'd never be able to come to one of the top Junior High Schools in the nation without something like this.
Wow, they're practicing even though it's Sunday.
Igo
Tournament
held here
Oh.
Here it is.
Junior High Winter
I guess I got here a little early.
I don't see Tsutsui-san at all.
Listen up, don't think that you can play better than you usually do.
If you meet up with an opponent who's better than you, it's only expected that you lose.
Let's play a bit then.
Imai you play Okata. Takeshita, you play me.
Iwana Junior High
vs
Ayu Junior High
Seems that Kaiou Junior High is exceptional again this year.
But I wonder who'll come in second.
What kind of a tournament are we in today?
It's a team tournament for Junior Highs.
Oh!
3 people per team, and the team with 2 wins are the winners.
... | Hamachi | Tai | Iawana | Ayu | Sawara | Haze | Kawahagi
Junior High
8 male teams and 6 female teams.
not too many.
Where's Haze...
Oh, there it is.
How exciting. Oh, I want to play now...
My heart's pounding.
Sai, you don't have to do anything today.
I'll be playing.
Hikaru!
B-But!
I've learned a little already...
and I really want to play... on my own.
But, last night!
You said "Oh there's a tournament tomorrow" and made me do your history homework.
But I said nothing about letting you play.
Hikaru! You're being mean!
You're going to lose so quickly!
It doesn't matter if I lose.
I'm just an extra.
See, there's quite a few people here.
Eh?
That's Takada's older brother!
Oh, no.
Why don't we play for a bit too?
Yeah.
But Kaiou's Go club's awesome.
I hear they use this hall for their club room.
They're just on a different scale.
I hear they've got 50 some people in their club.
I hear our Go club's the best.
Probably good to watch.
I guess I'll just sit around here.
Have you looked at the pairings?
Yeah, we won't go up against Kaiou until the final match.
If we do well, we can come in second.
Ah.
Sorry, sorry.
What are you doing!
Umm...
It was like this right?
No that's not it!
What are you talking about!
It was like this!
No it wasn't there.
Want me to do it?
Eh?
What are you doing?
Hikaru?
You came here...
and then... here.
then... here and...
Umm... after this it was...
Ah! Here!
And then...
and the part just now went...
like this and...
Umm...
and this is where you are.
What about that?
We know that already!
Anyone can just recreate the game from the first move, if they're any good.
Go away!
S-Sorry.
Dammit, if the stones was moved a little, I would've been winning.
Come on, let's continue. Whose turn was it?
Hey...
Can you really do this?
Dammit...
Which Junior High is he from?
What!?
There's someone here that you know?
So we can't stand out.
Yeah!
If they find out, we'll deal with it when it happens.
True...
If you can play the game, then recreating the game is easy.
But...
Hikaru just started a few days ago.
I can count the number of times he's touched the stones...
I think I understand now...
why I was drawn to Hikaru.
It's time.
We're starting the first match now.
Umm...
Women's first match...
Kaiou Junior High against Iwana Junior High is on seat A.
Ayu Junior High against Iwana Junior High is on seat B.
Tournament Pairings
For the men's division...
Kaiou Junior High against Hamachi Junior High is on seat C.
Seat D is Tai Junior High against Iwana Junior High.
And... Haze Junior High against Kawahagi Junior High is on seat F.
Is everyone in their seats?
Oh yeah, I can't stand out.
Huh?
W-What are you doing?
The game hasn't started yet.
You can't do that.
The match clock starts ticking if you hit it.
Match clock?
45 minutes per person.
Press this after you make a move...
Understood?
Hey, weren't we supposed to NOT stand out?
Sai!
Why didn't you say anything!?
You could've told me about the clock.
Things like that didn't exist in Shuusaku's Age.
And isn't it a little strange to be depending on me after bragging about how you were going to play today?
You jerk...
Fine!
You can just stay back today.
You do what you want Hikaru.
KING
Are you from the Shougi Club?
Why is someone from the Shougi Club here?
You didn't have enough members?
You didn't even have 3 people?
Shut up and just nigiri.
Nigiri? are you sure you don't want to use a furigoma?
Furigoma is a dice that they use to determine who goes first in Shougi.
You're lucky we're playing Go.
Shougi is the Japanese equivalent of Chess.
With Shougi, your King would've died in 5 minutes,
But with Go, it'll take me 10 minutes.
You get to live an extra 5 minutes.
Damn it.
How can you say stuff like that without knowing how strong I am!
You can tell the difference between a loser and a real man easily.
Someone who nags and bitches is obviously a loser.
Hey over there, hurry up and start.
2...
4...
6...
8...
9...
I'm white.
White...
then I'm black,
and Shindou-kun's white.
White.
Now, please start.
Good luck.
Improving your Go series
How to place your Joseki correctly
100 Joseki that you should know
Tsutsui! What are you doing!?
Are you a moron?
You're playing while reading a book!?
It's not against the rules...
You're weak because you depend on crap like that!
Joseki are set patterns of moves that result in local benefits for both players. Like openings in chess, although it benefits both players, it can benefit one player over another globally.
If the opponent move out of joseki, then that book's useless, don't you understand that!?
I'm more than aware of that, but I just lose confidence if I don't have this open...
You there, quiet!
Please! Don't stand out!
Whatever!
Idiots.
Hey, you forgot to hit your clock.
I'm nice aren't I?
Hmm...
What a terrible club.
A guy that doesn't know what a Match Clock is...
And an idiot that has a joseki book open.
And a guy from the Shougi club to fill the void.
The first match will be an easy win.
It's so cool.
I wanna play too...
I wanna play too Hikaru! Hikaru!
I can't hear you!
I resign.
Okay! 10 minutes!
Don't get distracted.
Teacher...
Its all right. The side with two winners win.
You two can win.
I feel sorry for Moriyama, but his opponent was just too strong.
Well...
Let's take a look at how strong this guy is.
What is this!? This is terrible!
Yeah...
This is just too sorry a sight...
Was the mad chase after me a fluke!?
That was me! Me!
Hey you! Are you trying at all!?
Yup.
I'm trying.
This isn't your real strength!
Or are you just playing around?
I am playing.
What!?
Because...
Look...
There are 9 stars on the Go board.
This is the universe!
And I'm placing stones one by one on that.
Like I'm increasing the number of stars one by one...
I'm making the universe!
It's like I'm a God...
I'm going to become a God!
On this Go board!
Hey are we still playing?
Well I want to keep playing..
Is that okay?
Well, the win-loss has been pretty much decided.
There's no point in playing.
Was it only a fluke that Hikaru recreated that game earlier?
And I thought I saw a glimpse of genius of the level of Touya Akira, in Hikaru.
Now it's one win one loss...
Tsutsui's our only hope.
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
We have two important rules to learn today.
An illegal move and its exception
When the stones are in this shape, it is against the rules for White to play here.
A stone cannot be played where it would be captured
It would only be captured, anyway.
There is, however, an exception.
Rule no. 2: The exception
A stone can be played if it completes a capture
When the stones are in this shape,
and White can surround Black by playing here,
White can play this spot.
Give it a try!
Yuki, you're getting better!
It's tied at one... Who will win?
We have a ko !
What happened, Sensei?
To be continued
Mister, why don't you try doing the mokusan?
His resignation is correct.
You're angry aren't you Hikaru?
That you can't win on your own strength?
I realize now that I won't reach the hand of god if I don't surpass you.
Hikaru...
You have Awakened.