この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Hikaru will...
start walking the path to the divine move.
It won't be me...
but Hikaru.
Is there no way that I can escape this fate...
that god has in store for me?
Sixtieth match
Farewell Hikaru
Huh?
Is it just me?
It looks like the stain has faded since the last time I was here.
Just as I thought...
There is no way for me to escape fate...
I guess it was always like that.
I guess it was just me.
Say, Hikaru.
What?
Are you free tomorrow?
Grandma and I are going to see a play.
Why don't you come with us?
A play!?
I-I have an overnight job tomorrow.
Two days and one night at a hotel.
I think there are supposed to be around 150 customers.
I'm going to play tutoring games and stuff there.
Wow, you?
It's not just me.
A few other pros are going to be there, too.
Say, you came all this way, you'll want to play, right?
Grandpa, I'll give you a thousand yen if you beat me.
Why, you little brat.
Hikaru!
Let's go home... and play a game.
You can play Grandpa any time!
What are you talking about?
We can play any time we want.
I hardly ever see Grandpa, I should play him when I do.
Let's go, Sai!
Hikaru, I...
Hikaru!
I'm going to disappear soon!
You and your stupid worries again?
That's ridiculous. You've been here for a millennium already, how can you disappear?
You'd better not be trying to make me feel sorry for you so that you can have your way.
You've been acting really selfish lately.
Why don't you just watch me play grandpa?
What are you waiting for, Sai!?
Hikaru can...
WELCOME
Japanese Go Institute
Go Seminar
Participants
Registration
Good morning.
Oh, Shindou-kun!
Here's the schedule.
Your room is 303, You're with Nagai-kun and Yokoi-kun.
Master Ogata is here, too!?
I should stay away from him.
I wouldn't want him giving me trouble about Sai.
Master Ogata is a solid player who plays all kinds of styles,
but his opponent Haruko-san is a forceful player.
What? Master Ogata played here?
In my opinion, this is a rather questionable move.
But who knows what Master Ogata will say to me later if I deride it.
Ashiwara!
See?
So, this Sagari isn't too useful right now, but...
you have other plans with it.
You can escape if you really want to,
but that's not enough.
Oh! I see.
Shindou!
You're still playing Go?
It's getting pretty late.
Ah! M-Master Ogata!
Hey, you don't have to be so scared.
Were you out drinking with Master Ogata?
Yup, on me.
We celebrated his Jyudan title.
Wow, he looks drunk.
Hey, Shindou!
Let me play Sai!
M-Master Ogata! I told you already!
I don't know Sai.
Hikaru.
Let's play.
Stop being selfish!
It will be alright he's this drunk.
It won't amount to anything.
Drunk?
Oh yeah. It doesn't look like he'd be able to play very well.
But are you alright with that?
I probably won't have any opportunities to play a real game against him.
No matter what kind of a game it is,
I will be if it will let me respond to the determination he showed at the hospital.
Let me play him, too!
Yeah. You're right.
I'll let him play you for a bit to congratulate him on his Jyudan title.
Hey, Shindou.
Let me...
Master Ogata!
Play me, right now.
Right now?
There's no point in playing him when he's this drunk.
Well, I guess I'll settle for you.
Will he really be able to play Go when he's this drunk?
Maybe he'll sober up a bit after playing you.
Why do you look so down?
Respond to me at least!
I'll let you play today for Master Ogata's sake,
but you've been really disagreeable lately.
Why?
Why is it not me, but Hikaru?
God...
Why is Hikaru...
Why is it only Hikaru...
I'm going to disappear! But Hikaru is going to...
I can't contain my jealousy towards Hikaru for having an existence.
That's not it...
I don't...
want to leave Hikaru.
I didn't want to leave Torajirou either.
Torajirou...
said to me, while on the brink of death from the plague...
'Sorry... Sai...'
I didn't want to leave him.
I didn't...
want to leave him...
I'm sorry, Hikaru...
I'll be going soon.
You were sleeping?
Sorry for turning on the lights.
I don't really care.
We can play without the lights on by the window.
Sit down.
You're drinking more?
I'm drunk either way, it won't matter.
Sorry, but I may not be able to play very well.
So it won't be strange at all if I crush you.
Hey, you can't challenge me when I'm this drunk.
Challenge me in an official match.
I have high expectations of you.
The day of your new first dan series match...
Master Kuwabara and I made a bet that day on who would win.
I bet Master Touya because Master Kuwabara bet on you.
But the truth is I wanted to bet on you, too.
Like I can trust what a drunk tells me.
You little punk.
You're right, I am drunk for a change today.
Seems like I'm finally starting to feel the joy of at last having become Jyudan.
We did have quite a ruckus with Master Touya's retirement...
I did become Jyudan...
but the world won't recognize me,
until I successfully defend the title next year.
Just you wait, I'm going to run all the way to the top.
Well Shindou, like I said earlier.
Let me play Sai!
Settle for playing me.
Alright, I guess.
Sixteen... you're going first.
Good luck.
I win.
This is over.
W-wait!
You messed up on an easy life or death problem.
Master Ogata, you must be really drunk.
Forget about my mistake...
More importantly...
You played in such a strange place on the top right...
and threatened a large cluster of my stones...
But...
I ended up playing poorly,
and my game fell apart.
I guess you had a little too much to drink.
I guess letting him play Sai didn't pay off...
But then again, it would have been troublesome if he had realized that Sai was playing.
Well, I guess there's little chance of that happening if he's this drunk.
Good night.
But...
I feel kind of sorry for him.
Such a solid play...
Yes...
It was as if...
I was playing Sai...
Ridiculous!
I must be really drunk.
I guess he was somewhat satisfied.
I'll go home first thing tomorrow, so I won't see him again.
Sai?
In the actual game, White played here to destroy Black's eye shape.
but first White should have connected to the center like this,
and waited for black to play here...
Oh! Good morning Master Ogata.
Have you seen Shindou?
He went home first thing this morning.
He said he doesn't have any more work to do here.
I slept on the bullet train, but I'm still tired.
I'm exhausted.
Hikaru, let's play a game.
But I'm about to collapse.
Man, I wish you'd worry about my health a little.
I'm going to sleep after one game, okay?
Sit down.
Come on.
A hundred forty years ago...
Torajirou lent his body to me.
If Torajirou existed for my sake...
then I existed for Hikaru's sake.
Then...
Hikaru exists for someone else as well.
And that someone will, too...
be there for another person.
A millennium becomes two,
built up slowly person by person.
The long path leading to the divine move...
My part in it...
is over...
Oh! Yes...
Hikaru...
Hikaru?
Hey, Hikaru?
Huh?
Can you hear my voice?
Hikaru...
I was fu...
Hey!
It's your turn.
I said it's your turn.
Sai!
Sai?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Today we have a problem based on a situation you might see quite often in your games.
Black has a really good move when White moves here.
Mai-chan, what would you do?
Here!
It's Atari, so I'll capture it.
That's Atari, so I'll connect.
Here.
Yup! That's right!
Now there four White stones can't get away.
You were able to hurt White's territory a lot.
But had you connected here...
White would have responded here, and his territory would have been very large.
The correct move for White would have been to move here at this point.
Let's make sure not to miss opportunities like this.
To be continued...
Sai!?
Are you there? Sai?
He wasn't in the shed where we met...
So I guess it's not a place where he has memories with me...
I'll find him no matter what!
I can't just let him disappear all of a sudden!
I won't let it happen, Sai!