この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Sit down. I'll play a tutoring game with you.
I don't need a tutoring game!
I can't let my guard down from any of his moves.
He's stronger than I thought.
But I can't afford to lose here.
You!
If I lose to you, I'll remember your name!
Yeah, I'll make you remember!
Thirty-sixth match
My Name Is...
What's going on?
Is there something special today?
Oh Yun-san, a Korean Kenkyuusei and a Japanese Insei are playing.
A Japanese Insei?
He's... Haze Jr. High's...
Do you know him?
Yes... Insei?
He's an Insei?
That's what he said.
His opponent is Ryu-san's nephew, and he's a Korean Kenkyuusei.
He's an Insei? Him?
It can't be...
He... said he was Shindou-kun?
The first time I saw him, his incredible skill surprised me.
Well played.
Yes.
But... the next time, he disappointed me greatly.
It wasn't just me... his opponent Touya Akira couldn't even hide his disappointment.
Thanks for the game.
Thanks for the game...
Though a little more than a year has passed since then.
He's gained that much strength since then!?
I won't...
I won't lose to him!
Damn! I can't...
I can't lose to a guy like him!
Though it started from a quibble.
This match...
This match touches me in the heart.
They both play well devised moves,
and return moves that are just as well thought out.
They don't hesitate to make the difficult moves because this is a match that they have to win.
Yes... it's as if the stones they hold in their hand are clearing a path for themselves.
How radiant both of their growth is!
But there can only be one winner.
This match... who will win it in the end?
How surprising... though the Korean child is at a slight advantage, could this really be Shindou-kun?
They both play sensationally powerful moves...
but Shindou is at a slight disadvantage.
Shindou...
The move Shindou-kun played right now... What was he thinking?
The move he just made was a mistake.
What are you doing? Shindou, that's not a good move.
Why? A careless mistake? Or is this his skill?
Shindou...
Did he read that last move wrong?
Too bad then. I guess this was all you had after all.
No one has realized what Hikaru's aim is.
Hikaru is reading deeper than anyone else here.
That bad move from earlier! It's in the perfect position right now!
That move Shindou made that we thought was bad....
he made it in preparation for the conflict on the top left!
So he didn't mind the fact that white would lose out in that area....
Shindou-kun surprised everyone and gained the advantage with white.
He read this far when he made that move!?
But the game is still close... Now I'll...
You're coming for this stone!?
I didn't think about that...
I can't get intimidated...
Su-Young isn't letting white gain an advantage.
Shindou's lost a little with those last few moves.
This is...
Shindou... wins by one and a half moku.
What a wonderful game! Both of them were going all out!
I couldn't take my focus off the game at all!
I'm sure the loser can be happy over a game like this.
White's attack in the mid-game was incredible!
Su-Young.
I lost...
I haven't had a game this mortifying lately.
I kept playing empty games of Go...
and I dropped a class...
and I gave up on it over just that...
He angered me, and I became serious...
and he played me evenly even when I was trying!
We're even! I'm no worse than he is!
I'll come to Japan again! To play you! As a pro this time!
Your name!?
Your name! I said I'd remember it.
Shindou Hikaru!
My name is Shindou Hikaru!
Shindou... Hikaru...
Hong-kun...
He's so disappointed he can't hold his tears back.
This is good.
Dropping down a class was a shock to him because he kept going up.
He wanted to cower away from that shame.
He ran from dealing with his disappointment.
But it's okay now...
He'll be going back to Korea tomorrow...
But Su-Young will grow a lot more.
Shindou-kun.
Who is he?
Hikaru. It's him!
From the Go club tournaments!
I'm Yun, I run the Kaiou Jr. High Go club, though you probably don't remember.
The teacher from Kaiou Jr. High!
I've met you three times so far.
The first time, you played Go that astounded everyone. When you were in grade school.
That's the one I played.
The second time was the tournament last year.
Where you betrayed the hopes we had in you.
But you've changed your mind about Hikaru just now, haven't you?
And today for the third time... I'm astounded!
See see see!
I was shown the strength of those who aim to become pro by the two of you.
The flow of stones that you showed on the board was incredible.
Did you hear that Hikaru!?
He's complimenting me...
Me! Not Sai!
Shindou-kun, do you remember? That incredible game you played that gave Haze Jr. High the win?
I played that game.
I couldn't believe that it was a grade school student playing that game.
Of course not.
Your game today was just as incredible as that one!
Like I keep saying, you're wrong, that was me...
Now I can believe it! That wondrous match you played then, was your true strength!
I'll carve it into my mind too...
the name Shindou Hikaru!
Let's go home.
It was an incredible game you played today.
The pro exam finals begin next week.
The next time we meet, will be in the exam hall.
Yeah.
The exam isn't at the Go Institute.
It's at the Go Research Center.
Okay.
Later.
Later!
Okay, let's go home Sai!
I feel great today!
The teacher from Kaiou thinks highly enough of me now to mistake that match you played for one I played!
That teacher is looking at me!
Sai doesn't exist in him any more!
Doesn't exist?
One day I'll erase the Sai in Touya too!
Erase?
My name is...
Shindou Hikaru!
I feel insecure...
What... What is this?
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Today, let's learn some Go terminology that Sai often uses.
This is called the 3-4 point, komoku, or small eye. We've covered it before.
This move is called the knight's move, keima.
From this stone, the move is called "the knight's approach."
And this is...?
Kosumi!
Yes, very good!
A move on the diagonal from another stone is called kosumi.
It's a move Sai likes very much.
A move horizontally away from your own stone is called an extension, hiraki.
Here, there are two spaces, so it is called a "two-point extension." Two-space hiraki.
Then, what about here?
You've moved two spaces toward the center, so it is a "two-point jump." Two-space tobi.
Let's continue with Go terminology again next week!
It's begun.
The long... long pro exam.
I have to become a pro if I want to catch up to Touya.
I'm looking forward to playing you.
I'm going to get a win again.