Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Is Touya going to quit the Go club after today?
Sai...
you play...
Is that okay?
You said you wanted to.
You play...
Tsutsui-san is just as motivated too.
First and second boards really should be like that.
Fourteenth match
The Third Match
The Fourth Annual North District
Summer Junior High Go Tournament Hall
Are you okay?
I'm fine, let's do it Tsutsui-san.
Let's Nigiri.
2... 4... 6...
I'm black.
I'm white, Shindou-kun's black.
Good luck
Good luck.
Good lu...
Finally...
Finally, I can play against you...
Good luck.
Hikaru, let's go.
Upper-right corner, komoku.
That was fast!
He must have already decided where to go.
That's probably the case.
He must have gone over many matches against me in his mind.
15-4 hiraki
5-7 moku-hazushi
Moku-hazushi is the third most popular opening move. It moves one spot outwards from the komoku. It is the most aggressive of the three most popular opening moves, but it doesn't secure very much of the corner for you.
They're the eyes from before.
The eyes he had when he challenged Sai.
I came all this way pulled by your eyes...
You're my far away objective.
Sai?
Thinking? Here? I'd go to 11-8 without hesitation.
What are you thinking about, Sai?
Dammit, I don't get it.
What's wrong with 11-8?
Have I improved a little?
You really don't need to improve anymore.
You've changed as well.
You hold your stone correctly now.
Hold my stone?
Of course I hold it correctly now.
I played Tsutsui-san everyday, and I played Mitani too.
I've gotten a lot stronger, really.
Touya...
I...
How much closer am I too you now?
You've realized already right?
That I'm not just a weak freshman.
Thinking?
Moron. You understand me, right?
I'm not just any Jr. High kid.
Yeah, you are better than me,
but by confusing you through overly aggressive moves and unexpected moves,
and dragging you into my pace,
I might stand a chance.
What is it?
What is he thinking about?
Go ahead and think about it.
In order to make this match befitting of the first board.
You're to aggressive. You should relent a little.
Talking in the middle of a match?
So you're still underestimating me.
Watch this, I'll make this match befitting of the first board.
This guys really cautious.
Last year, I was able to use my opponent's mistake to win.
but this second board plays solidly.
He's really strong.
I want to play!
Touya, just like you're chasing after Sai,
I'm chasing you,
I'll catch you some day.
13-4
I'll play at 11-8, and then...
Hikaru? 13-...
I want to try it.
Sai, sorry.
I can't see it unless I play myself.
I want to know,
the gap between him and I.
11-8!?
I'm going to play.
Hikaru...
This is...
it surprised me for a second but... this is...
or is there something else?
It's interesting.
11-8 is interesting.
It's too bad that Hikaru doesn't have the strength to follow up on that idea,
But, I can feel his will to keep playing with each move he makes.
Hikaru...
I will simply watch over you for now...
Stop messing around!
T-Touya...
Touya!
I'm not messing around!
Yes! We're very serious!
Touya's too busy chasing after me,
and can't see Hikaru's strength.
He can't hear Hikaru approaching him step by step.
Touya...
Play to the end. Either that or resign.
I told you, you'd know once you played him.
Damn it!
Is he an idiot?
Getting so fired up over Shindou.
You over estimate him too much.
I know exactly how strong he is.
Tsutsui-san can't do it either.
I'm our only hope.
What is it!?
He's fighting over a stone like this!?
I'm fighting back but...
Is there that much meaning behind this stone?
He's... why is he this stubborn!?
A stone like this... I should just give it to him.
You pulled back.
As I see it, you play a game based on strength, from yourself training.
In that case, you can't pull back.
Even if there's no real meaning behind this stone, you can't pull back.
With people like you, once you pull back, you've lost emotionally.
You'll only fall apart from now on.
So your plan is to make me worry by saying that.
Go ahead and play!
I resign...
Touya!
Thanks for the game.
I thought...
I thought I saw the hand of god in you...
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
To be honest, I didn't think you were this strong.
It was fun.
It's not...
over yet!
Oh?
You intend to play to the end?
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
Kaiou against Haze, Kaiou wins with a score of 3-0
Haze vs Kaiou 0-3
Iwana vs Haze 0-3 | Sawara vs Kaiou 0-3
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Let's do nigiri, which is how we determine which color to play.
Mai, since you are older than Yuki,
please choose for color with the white stones.
Grab some stones and conceal them in your hand over the board.
Yuki, if you think she has an even number of stones,
say "Even first", and take out two stones.
If you think she has an off number of stones,
say "Odd first", while taking out one stone.
Odd first.
It's an odd number.
Yuki guessed correctly, so that means Yuki is Black and plays first.
To be continued
You can play against people from all over the world here.
Hikaru, what are you trying to do?
I thought I'd let you play all the Go you want.
Gotta get a nickname first.
The name will be... Sai!
All I want? Really?
Well, let's go.