Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Zelda...
He's Japanese, he might be a child.
Child?
Who is this!?
Well Sai, how is he?
He's strong. Stronger than anyone we've played so far.
Master, is he a pro?
Probably not! A pro wouldn't play amateurs constantly like this.
So he's not a pro...
If he's not a pro, who is he!?
Maybe he is the God of Go.
The International Amateur Go Tournament is coming up. If I go to Japan...
If I go to Japan...
I might find out something about Sai.
Could he be?
A child!?
He's strong...
but he's not Sai.
Seventeenth match
The Match of Revelation
The 20th International Amateur Go Tournament
Sponsored by The Japanese Institute of Go
I resign.
Do you play Go over the internet?
Are you talking about Sai?
Are you Sai!?
Sai...
Is Sai here?
Did someone say Sai?
You're Sai aren't you?
No.
Another player asked me this morning if I was Sai.
Then...
I'm not. Who is this Sai?
We don't know who he is.
Who are you?
You played Sai?
Yes.
He was very strong.
I sent him a message asking him who he was, but I was ignored.
I was hoping that he would be here.
I played him a month ago too.
But given my skill, I didn't stand a chance.
I've never played Sai, but I've seen his games. I watch his games constantly.
I played Sai. About 10 days ago.
He suddenly appeared this summer.
He's so strong that his rumor spread like wildfire.
He gets challenged by everyone across the world.
Everyone asks the same question "Sai wa nanimono ka?"
Sai? It has to be. They're all talking about Sai.
Please quiet, there are still people in the middle of a match.
Exactly who is he!?
He's no ordinary player.
People!
What's wrong?
They're muttering something about the internet.
Internet? Oh yes, Waya said something about that too.
Did something happen?
Mr. Ogata!
Long time no see Mr. Ogata.
Oh you know Shimano?
Yes, he used to come to the Meijin's study sessions often.
I came to pay my respects today.
Akira-kun will be here momentarily.
But it seems rather chaotic in here.
Yes, something about someone really strong on the internet.
Strong?
He calls himself Sai.
Nice to meet you, I am Li Lishin from China.
I played Sai and resigned.
Then is he a pro?
I doubt it, Sai appears often, and doesn't choose his opponent.
A pro wouldn't waste time like that.
Sai...
I'm Kim, from Korea. I haven't met Sai directly.
But before I came here, I was contacted by my friend Yun 7-dan.
"I just played Sai. Please find out who Sai is when you go to Japan,"
"because Sai is definitely their top pro."
No, he can't be a pro.
Then, exactly who did he lose to!?
Who within any of our nations did he lose to!?
Excuse me... umm...
Hey! What do you think you're doing Waya!
But you're talking about Sai.
I can't keep out of it.
Oh? You've played him too?
I just told you! Someone who's really strong, but isn't a pro.
That's him! Sai.
Oh yeah...
Who is he?
He's Morishita-san's student.
What kind of player is he?
What kind of player...
I played him a month ago... but with his playing style...
He reminded me off Shuusaku.
Shuusaku!?
Honinbou Shuusaku!?
I replay Shuusaku's games a lot, so I thought they were kinda similar.
He seems that strong and...
I watched his games a couple of times after that...
Really, over and over...
He's always there... and I thought he was incredible...
and he gets stronger every time I watch him...
his style is changing...
As if Shuusaku learned modern Joseki.
Shuusaku!? Learn modern Joseki!?
This is fun Sai.
Only I can see you...
Is he a God?
But within this box, you exist.
Fujiwarano Sai exists!
Or a demon?
Honinbou Shuusaku exists!
A Honinbou Shuusaku that lurks among the nets...
I'd like to play him once...
Is something the matter?
Touya-kun.
The tournament hall seems...
It doesn't concern you!
You're...
Akira-kun, have you ever played Go over the internet?
I've played a pro from Kansai...
But...
It seems that there's someone really strong on the net.
He's an amateur, but even a Korean pro lost to him.
Someone strong on the net?
Like I said it doesn't concern you.
Waya! Why you being so contentious!
No reason.
I hear his nickname is Sai.
Sai...
Teacher, I thought, Sai might be a child.
A child?
Impossible, what makes you think that?
Why?
Because, he appeared in early July, and he's been around since.
I think that's because it's summer vacation.
And he sent me a message saying "I'm strong aren't I?"
That's really childish.
What!? You've talked with Sai!?
What did you talk about!?
Ahh! One at a time!
A child...
Do you have any ideas?
No I don't.
If you're thinking of him, you're mistaken.
And I thought I saw the hand of god in you...
Everyone.
You can access the net through this.
We can see Sai?
Akira-kun.
Sai may be there.
I'd like you to check.
He's there.
Another resignation! We win again!
Sai, it feels great with you playing, cause you win them all.
That last one wasn't very strong,
but there are some very hard opponents in this box.
Yeah seems like it.
Huh? Akira?
Damn, why do I get so many challenges?
Let's reject this, and...
back to the screen.
Akira...
Is it Touya?
Probably not.
Argh! Not another guy!
Gimme a break!
Not again! I just rejected one!
One after another!
Why don't you take a breather.
Ah, this?
Service.
Arigatou! Mitani's Sister!
Hikaru, we're back to that picture again.
Let's try it.
Sai...
sent a challenge...
He accepted the challenge...
Wouldn't it be great if it was Touya?
He wanted to play you...
I want to let him play...
even if he doesn't know that it's me, I can grant his wish...
Wanna test him?
Whether he is Touya or not.
What are you going to do?
Take black please.
I took it.
Then let's do it.
First move 17-4.
17... 4...
White played to the star on the top left.
16-17
White played to 4-17.
We'll go to 15-3.
Huh? White's not moving.
Is he thinking?
He's attacking the lower right, Sai next move.
He's made the same moves as last time, so far.
Last time?
Sai this is...
Yes... the second match against him when I cut him in two.
It's the match from then.
Okay, next is 15-16 kosumi.
He's not moving...
Maybe he's not moving because it is Touya.
Perhaps his hand has stopped because he recalls that game.
It can't be...
That means Touya's realized it's me! That's bad!
He played Shuusaku's kosumi against you...
Akira-kun?
It can't be...
What's wrong? Why isn't he moving?
Look!
He went to the same place as last time!
Sai! This is bad! If he finds out that it's me playing were in trouble!
What should we do!?
Is his opponent right now that strong?
Excuse me!
Yeah.
Come on Sai, make moves different from last time from here on out.
Then lets try 4-14. Two space high kakari.
I wonder if we fooled him...
Probably.
I wonder if he really is Touya.
Huh? He's thinking.
He resigned!?
Akira-kun! Why did you resign?
If we continue playing, it'll disrupt the tournament.
I'll request a rematch on a different day.
Why you...
Huh!? A rematch on another day!?
Mitani's sister!
What's wrong?
Will you be here tomorrow?
Sorry. I'm going to go on a trip with a few friends tomorrow.
The next time I'll be here is Sunday.
Then, can you type in "This Sunday at 10AM" to this guy?
Why don't you learn to do it yourself?
akira> May I have a rematch on another day?
sai> This Sunday at 10AM...
This Sunday...
It's unfortunate, we will have returned by then.
akira> May I have a rematch on another day?
sai> This Sunday at 10AM...
akira> I will accept those conditions.
You'll accept it!?
Please excuse me for today.
Shimano-san...
Who is that child?
He is the son of Japan's top players, Touya-Meijin.
But, why did Sai challenge him to a game?
Yeah, Sai rarely sends challenges to other people...
A rematch on Sunday? He accepted it without hesitation?
It's the first day of the pro exams!
Are you trying to say that you don't care if you lose a match!?
So some mysterious player is more interesting!?
Damn...
Oh well, so we still don't know anything about who Sai is.
If you find out anything about Sai, please contact me.
Me too.
Touya-Meijin's sons is taking the exam this year.
Yeah, makes it so much tougher for us.
How many times have you taken it now?
Don't mention that. If I don't become pro this year, I should probably give it up...
Japanese Center of the Study of Go
He's not coming...
It doesn't matter if he loses the first match.
Man that guy pisses me off.
Touya Akira...
He hasn't arrived yet...
Everyone's working hard for the pro exams.
He doesn't know how hard it is to come here!
Damn him!
Well, please begin your match then.
Good luck.
Good morning Shindou-kun! It sure is raining hard today.
Sorry, I've gotta hurry.
Okay let's go!
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Today, we continue our discussion on eyes.
One of these three shapes ensures that no black stones will be captured.
Which one is it?
- This.
- This one.
This one that Mai selected has two solid eyes, so Black cannot be captured.
Now how about this one?
These look like eyes, but a stone can be captured, which leaves only one eye.
Now let's look at the one Yuki selected.
They look like eyes, but these stones can be captured, leaving only a single eye.
Shapes that look like eyes but are really not are "false eyes".
False eyes are extremely important, so learn them well.
To be continued
Okay!
There's a strong player, his name is Sai.
People are raising a ruckus as to who Sai is.
I feel a wall higher than when Shindou defeated me.
I'll force white to reveal his eyes structure with the move.
Come, tell me...
Who are you!?