Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Thinking again?
I resign.
One win!
The stones easily flow.
The teacher complimented me on my three board match, so maybe I'm better at fast Go.
I won by half a moku! Yes two straight wins!
I lost!
Oh, sorry.
I resign.
You won...
I won... three straight games...
Just when I thought "I'm gonna have all wins from now on!"
I started getting straight losses,
and I started to doubt whether I was getting stronger at all.
He did get over the hurdle in front of him, so congratulations is right.
Doesn't matter to me.
And? When is the Wakajishisen? Touya will be there, right?
Is Touya Akira the only thing in your head?
Next month and the month after. It's on the Saturday's when we don't have Insei matches.
It takes more than a day. It's a tournament between 16 Insei and 16 new pros.
The first match is all between Insei and pro. It's an even game of course.
But you won against pros! Wow!
What are you talking about?
You won't pass the pro exams unless you can win against pros.
Wakajishisen is a good testing ground.
Twenty-eighth match
The Wakajishisen
The Ninth Annual Wakajishisen
What other Insei isn't here yet?
Let's see...  Nozaki and Shindou and...
Oh! Shindou's here!
You're late!
Waya! We're finally here! I'm so excited.
Aren't you a tad too excited?
Where's everyone else?
Huh? Why is there people under 16 and from the second class here too?
We're not allowed to watch!?
Not helping you ever again.
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry! Sorry!
Where are the pros?
They're over there.
They're the pros!? They don't look it.
Not many of them wear neckties.
The Wakajishisen is like a festival of sorts, so they're relaxed.
Sup guys, been awhile.
Oh, it's just Mashiba-san.
Are you all doing well?
Who is this?
He's one of the Insei that became pro last year.
Isumi-san, good luck today. Please take it easy on me.
Isumi-san's playing...
Yup. Mashiba-san in the first round.
Hey Isumi-san, please come over to this side already.
Once you become pro, you can play freely, without that stuffy feeling you have when you're an Insei.
It really is great, though you have to become pro to understand it.
It's great being pro.
Well then, later.
He's so annoying.
What is with him?
He's gotten so irritating ever since he became pro.
He pisses me off.
Second Floor
Wakajishisen
Public Game Room
Today's Program
I definitely have to win my first round now!
Waya! Shindou!
Saeki-san.
Aren't you glad we're not playing each other in the first round?
Fighting each other within the Morishita school, that would've been bad.
Good luck to you too, Shindou-kun, with beating Touya.
Yeah!
Later.
Where's Touya?
Oh, he's not here yet...
Good morning.
Morning.
It seems that you're not the only one focused on Touya.
Doesn't look like they give a damn about the Insei.
That especially has to be the case with Murakami-san.
Once he beats Shindou in the first round, he has to play Touya in the second.
Who's my opponent Murakami 2-dan?
Which one is it?
He's over there.
He has his hair parted down the middle, with glasses.
Hey!
I said Hey!
Aren't you a little too nervous? With those fists?
Sweating already? Take it easy. No one's expecting you to win, sixteenth.
Everyone please quiet down.
Well then, we'll begin The Ninth Annual Wakajishisen now.
It's almost time to start the matches, so everyone please take your seats.
They're even matches, but the Insei will take black.
It's time now, so please begin.
Good luck.
This many Insei's are going to be watching?
I'm getting nervous.
I mean, Isumi-san is an Insei, and I'm a pro.
It'll look bad if I get defeated really quickly.
Good luck.
The focus of this year's Wakajishisen is probably Touya Akira.
He's had straight wins since his debut in April. I wonder how long he'll last here.
Huh?
That's Ogata 9-dan.
Why is he at the Wakajishisen?
Maybe since he studies under Touya-Meijin, he has to watch out for Touya Akira...
You think?
I mean, Touya Akira's had straight wins since his debut.
What is there to worry about against Inseis?
That's?
Murakami 2-dan.
No, the Insei.
He's... oh yeah, during the new first dan series...
Touya!
Another spectator?
Will the match end with the victor uncertain?
It won't!
Touya won't let it end here, with the way he's been playing up to now!
If they enter the last round even, he'll try to go for a KO!
But, why would Ogata 9-dan watch his game?
Is he special?
Hello? Touya Akira is over here.
Just kidding.
You seem to be interested in Hikaru.
Yes, you watched the move Hikaru talked about at the Children's Go tournament didn't you?
Close! It's one above that!
Calm down.
Mr. Ogata...
You saw Hikaru play a few moves against Touya-Meijin too, didn't you?
Sai...
You!
Those... were both me.
I only play Hikaru these days.
That's fun in it's own way.
But you are a Go player as well. I wish I could play you someday too.
What kind of a game will you play?
I've played many types of games against many different players in the past.
As Fujiwarano Sai and as Honinbou Shuusaku.
Those memories are coming back...
those dozens... those hundreds... those thousands of games...
I still remember them all.
Even the cold feeling of the Go stones.
There is a free board.
Come! Let us play as well!
I wish I had a body.
No... I have to be thankful that I met Hikaru. I can't ask for more.
How is Hikaru?
You should keep a close watch on him.
Someday... he will become a rival to everyone here, including yourself.
His opponent is a pro... but he isn't that much stronger than the Insei.
But, I don't know how far Hikaru can go, the way he is now.
But that's... NOW.
Just you wait. In the near future...
he? AHHH!
Hikaru! That was a bad move!
So like I said he still has much to learn. You just happened to be watching this one game.
I play Hikaru everyday, so I know.
He sees more of the board everyday, and his play gets more solid everyday.
His growth is very apparent.
Of course, he'll still makes bad moves, just like earlier.
But... but...
It... it was a bad move... but he fooled his opponent well and turned his bad move into a good one!
Hikaru...
Okay!
See? You rushed too much here.
Ohh! I see...
Don't follow your opponent's moves too much.
It's important to play fast, but it's also important to use your time.
Oh, looks like you won Tajima-kun. You're being very nice.
Really?
Well then, I guess I'll go watch Touya.
Huh? Ogata 9-dan is here.
I wonder what it is. I doubt the people there are very interesting.
Oh well, gotta watch Touya.
Umm... I... I'll go watch Isumi-san.
How is it?
I lost.
Not you! Isumi-kun!
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
Waya you've gotten better. I hope you pass the pro exams this year.
Of course I've gotten better. Nakayama-san was Insei two years ago.
I even expected to win today.
Let's see Touya... oh! His game's still going on. Later.
I couldn't win... but I did well!
I'm not too far from becoming pro! This year I'll...
I wonder how Isumi-san's game is going.
It's!
Isumi-kun's advantage is plain as day.
Mashiba tried to come back earlier. But Isumi-san took care of it, and that's that.
Go Isumi-san!
In your face, Mashiba!
No... I can't do anything even if I keep playing.
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
Huh? That's it?
Yeah, seemed as if he was only half concentrating on the game.
Maybe he's saving his strength for the next match.
Man, I don't even know how strong Touya is because the Insei sucked too much.
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
Yes!
Isumi-san dominated the game from the start to end.
Yeah totally.
I thought Mashiba-san would put up more of a fight.
Yeah can't tell who's the pro.
Huh! It's meaningless to beat me at a place like this!
Just like it's meaningless to be first amongst the Insei for 2-3 years in a row.
It's all meaningless unless you pass the pro exams.
Isumi-san you beat me in the pro exams last year, but you didn't make it.
The way you're going, you're going to fail...
Waya!
Why you!
What's going on!?
Mashiba! Waya!
Mashiba! You bastard!
Stop it!
Isumi-san! Waya!
Just because you...
Screw you.
Waya.
Touya Akira is watching.
But... you were a little too late.
But he saw Hikaru's wonderful play from earlier.
Can Touya see from this board, from these unusual patterns of stones?
Can he see the moves that occurred?
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Yuki, you always start at the tengen point.
But Hikaru and Sai start at the corners. Why is that?
There's a reason for that.
I've made equal territories at the corner, side and center.
Let's count how many moves it takes to create each territory.
In the center?
Eight moves.
Along the side?
Six moves.
And in the corner?
Four moves.
You see? The corner territory required the fewest moves.
Common locations are the corner star points,
and the place above it, called komoku.
Okay, let's begin.
Onegaishimasu.
To be continued
I want to become stronger...
I want to play more...
Has Shindou gained that much strength compared to the pros!?
And I would like to be the one here to greet them,
as a title holder.
Kuwabara Honinbou?