Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Oh, he's not here yet...
Hikaru! That was a bad move!
It... it was a bad move... but he fooled his opponent well and turned his bad move into a good one!
Hikaru...
Twenty-ninth match
Kuwabara Honinbou
Oh yeah. What happened to Shindou?
Touya... and Mr. Ogata too.
Six and a half moku.
There's quite a gap.
Six and a half moku...
Pros are strong...
Thanks for the game.
Shindou...
Waya.
Sorry.
But I did well.
I see.
What about Touya!?
He won, awhile ago.
Oh...
I wanted to play him...
Watching...
He was watching your game.
Very intently.
Tropical Fish
How did you know I was here?
Ogata-san you come here occasionally, so I thought you might be here...
You don't look happy considering that you're doing well in the Wakajishisen.
You look as if you're worried about something, and don't have time to be caring about anything else.
Shindou right?
You left immediately afterwards yesterday.
There was something I wanted to ask you.
Of course.
I thought you'd come sooner.
The usual fish food, but more of it than usual please.
Ogata-san.
I have to play Kuwabara-san for his title, so I'll be out of the house for awhile.
Sure is a hassle to get a title.
But, if I dilly dally around, Touya Akira might come up and take the title before me.
I'll give you a ride home, or did you want to stop somewhere for sushi?
Ogata-san!
Tell me.
Shindou's game from yesterday, something, something happened right!?
Something?
What I saw was Shindou getting crushed by Murakami 2-dan's strong end game.
Just that.
And the end result was six and a half moku gap, just as you saw.
Six and a half moku after he lost sente over and over again in the end game.
That means it was even going in to it!
Has Shindou gained that much strength compared to the pros!?
It's just as you saw.
Ogata-san, what I want to know is...
That awkward stone formation. I can't imagine what order the moves went in to form that shape.
Something must have happened!? Exactly what did Shindou do!?
Haha, get in.
You should ask the opponent Murakami-kun about the match.
I asked him...
What did Shindou do? Why are you concerned about the loser!?
I was the one who won! The 16th ranked Insei didn't stand a chance!
I'm the one who's playing you in your next match! Why don't you worry about that for a bit?
And, he got crushed by you in the second round after saying all that. Poor guy.
Ogata-san, tell me about Shindou!
I thought you didn't care about Shindou.
It was spectacular. His moves...
His bad move from earlier turned into a good one.
What a guy...
It was a bad move at that point, but he fooled his opponent well and turned his bad move into a good one.
Don't be so impatient.
The answer will come to you soon.
The pro exams...
Yes. He's now walking the path that you went through a year ago.
NcDonald's
Just another run of the mill Insei Study day.
I can hardly believe that the Wakajishisen was just yesterday.
It's so quiet...
So only Isumi-san and Ochi and Adachi-san managed to win the first round...
Ochi won the second round too.
But he probably can't make it through the third round.
That's rather depressing...
But Waya, you were close in the first round.
You played well.
Yup, the teacher was complimenting you too.
But Ochi is incredible.
I've been losing to him straight lately.
What about you Isumi-san?
Half and half...
I'm half and half with him too. I'm strong against Ochi.
Oh yeah did you hear? Ochi tends to lock himself in the bathroom when he loses.
The bathroom!?
I just noticed recently, but whenever he loses, he goes to the bathroom and he doesn't come out.
And?
And you can hear the sound of a finger tapping against the wall along with some kind of mumbling.
I'm sure he'll be doing that after the Wakajishisen too.
Tap... tap... tap...
What is he doing?
That's so weird.
Even his opponent was a pro, I'm sure he'll be really angry about losing.
And tappy tap.
My opponent in the afternoon is Ochi...
Good luck Shindou! Lock Ochi in the bathroom!
You're probably still too weak. You lost by 6 and a half moku in the Wakajishisen after all.
Too bad you couldn't play Touya.
But I became stronger yesterday.
I want to become stronger...
I want to play more...
Games like the one yesterday... I want to play more of it...
You...
I can become stronger! I can!
Sorry!
Were Ogata 9-dan and Touya looking at Shindou?
Thank you come again!
Looks like Shindou might give us some fierce competition. Can't let our guards down in the summer everyone.
Summer?
The pro exams.
Pro exams?
Huh? You forgot? The greatest goal for all of us Inseis.
If you make it to the pro exams, you'll get to play all the fierce games you want.
Dozens of them.
When that comes around, all of us here...
will be crushing each other's futures.
But anyways, good luck on your match against Ochi.
Waya-kun you're with me.
I can't keep losing to you...
I'm looking forward to it.
Why you...
What? You're still losing to Fuku?
I just can't seem to win.
Komiya said something about being weak against Fuku too...
Not really for me...
Isumi-san you're...
Shindou, let's go!
Why were you spacing out in front of the elevator?
Something the matter with Master Kuwabara?
Master Kuwabara?
You don't know him!?
Geez you're stupid.
He's Honinbou!
Kuwabara Honinbou!
Kuwabara Honinbou?
Is something the matter Master Kuwabara?
I felt something peculiar...
Oh did you see a ghost or something?
No, that kid.
He's an Insei...
I'll remember him.
Honinbou is a name that Go players have passed down for generations.
So at the beginning of the Showa period, a tournament for the Honinbou title was made.
And the winner started taking the name "Honinbou".
Right now there's many titles, like the Kisei or Meijin.
But Honinbou is the oldest.
That old guy is Honinbou they say.
I don't like it.
Mr. Ogata is challenging Master Kuwabara right now.
Mr. Ogata is?
Seven game match. Though they don't play it all in one day.
Mr. Ogata won the first game a few days ago, and the second game is this week.
They spend around two years on the preliminaries for all the titles,
and the winner there gets to challenge the title holder.
Two years!?
You really don't know anything do you?
Why don't you study the Go world a bit?
I'll study it once I become pro.
You're something alright...
I want to play more...
I can become stronger...
I can!
Hikaru, you should play an Oogeima there, not a Kogeima.
Oogeima? I don't think a Kogeima is bad...
If the Oogeima were to be 100 points in strength, the Kogeima is 99.
I let you play Kogeima up till now.
With the Kogeima it's easier to read ahead and harder to make mistakes.
While the Oogeima becomes complex and easy to make mistakes on.
Oh...
But Hikaru, you have to surpass that now.
Yeah!
What is it?
Have I gotten stronger?
Yes! Another level stronger ever since the Wakajishisen.
Why?
Touya... he's playing in that same room I play in right?
We play on Sundays and every other Saturday but...
He plays on Wednesdays or Thursdays since he's a pro...
We won't ever meet... but when I think that I'm playing in the same room as him... I feel something.
I have to work harder too, to prepare for the pro exams in the summer.
Yes! Summer will be here soon!
Yeah! And Touya too!
Hokkaido...
Today's Events
Piano Recital
Eve of the Honinbou Match
36th graduating class Akino Jr. High Reunion
Bridalfair Flower Festival
Hello Ogata-kun!
Did you just arrive?
Yes, but Hokkaido sure is close.
How about it? Let's ditch the ceremonies and go out for a night in town.
That's okay, I'm not interested.
You're no fun!
H-Hey isn't that Kuwabara!? The pro player!
Who?
Hey! Do you have any paper and pen?
You're not a child anymore.
You sure are energetic. We're going to be playing for two straight days starting tomorrow.
You might be a little too nervous about it.
Umm, excuse me, you're Kuwabara Honinbou right?
Why yes, I am Kuwabara.
Sorry to disturb you when you're busy, but could I get an autograph?
I'm a huge fan of yours master.
The Go world must be really depressing if an old man like myself is this popular.
Right Ogata-kun?
Ogata?
Immobility
Kuwabara Honinbou
Here how's this?
Thank you very much!
Thank you.
Ogata-kun, you beat me on the first match, but I won't lose this time.
Just try to take the title of Honinbou from this old man.
Master Kuwabara.
A new wave is coming upon the Go world.
A new wave?
It's just my intuition.
But it's almost coming.
A new wave of young players.
Oh really?
And I would like to be the one here to greet them,
as a title holder.
Masters, the preparations for the ceremony is done, so please come with me to the stage.
I failed to escape from here because you were dilly dallying.
Morning!
Sup. Did you hear?
Touya's risen to 2-dan.
What? Really!?
Touya...
Touya Two Dan
Almost... I will catch up to you... Touya!
Okay! Resignation! Great.
Shindou really has gotten strong since the Wakajishisen.
I can't let my guard down...
Kadowaki!?
Waya are you sure?
Isn't Kadowaki the guy that got the three titles Student Meijin, Student Honinbou, and student Jyukketsu?
I can't believe you know that Isumi-san.
There was quite a commotion over him.
So Kadowaki is...
I saw it on the net. That Kadowaki is taking the pro exams...
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
The popular "Hikaru no Go" beginners Go class
is being held again on a nationwide scale.
I am here at one of those locations, Okinawa.
I'm with Women's Kisei, Kaori Chinen.
I'd like you all to enjoy Go the way Hikaru does.
Working with the children of Okinawa today,
I learned just how far Go has spread throughout Japan.
To be continued
Kadowaki, gotta watch out for him.
Might as well warm up a bit for the pro exams.
People do make mistakes.
I have no intentions of listening to an old man's ramblings.
Leave it to me.