Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Oh, the Insei exams are going on today?
Who's taking it right now?
A guy, probably a little younger than me.
He'll...
probably pass.
Good luck.
Twenty-second match
The Insei Examination
Hikaru...
That was...
He won't respond to that expansion. The Tsuke you played earlier was a mistake as well.
The three stone advantage Hikaru started with has already been spent.
Hikaru is aware of that as well.
That's why his game is getting rushed and he's making mistakes.
Against someone as strong as this person... he's...
Hikaru! You will lose at this rate.
Hikaru! If you wish, once again I will... Hikaru!
Hikaru?
He can't hear me.
It's too bad that he doesn't have the strength to go along with his concentration.
I... I can't do it. I can't win.
If I go in too far, he'll crush me.
But the gap will just keep on widening like this...
Touya...
Touya!
Hey! Hey!
Don't get so nervous.
You don't have to win to pass. I'm just seeing how strong you are.
Oh!
Couldn't you have said that earlier mister?
M-Mister!?
Hikaru, mister is a little too rude.
T-Teacher.
What is with that posture!?
I-I'm sorry!
M-My legs are asleep... I can't hang on....
Just say "excuse me" and break your form in that case~
Couldn't you have said that earlier as well?
Oh, you look like you lost.
This is my third straight loss to Fuku.
I'm strong against Waya-kun.
I'm terrible against Fuku.
It's not good to think so negatively.
You're terrible against Touya-kun too, Waya-kun.
No one's good against Touya.
Hmm... let's stop here.
O-Okay.
You should have simply pulled back here, that would've troubled white.
This formation is, a little difficult for black.
And? What is it? Did I pass? Or...
He's a little too weak, but it says here he's only been playing for a year.
That's some incredible growth, reminiscent of Kurata 5-dan.
But, even Kurata-kun, who had a lot of talent got a pro teacher right after he started playing.
He doesn't even have that.
If he became this strong just from playing in a Jr. High club, he may have incredible potential.
Is it true that you don't have a teacher?
Umm... ahh... no...
Well, I kinda do... a totally useless one.
What! A totally what one, Hikaru!?
But these three matches are...
you didn't read very deeply, and your play is very careless.
Oh? They're all the same day?
I played it simultaneously.
It was the first time I played three games simultaneously, it was horrible!
Th...
Three games!? And it was his first time!? He played this well on his first try!?
Okay. Come here starting next month. Go get your mother.
Yeah! Yay!
Hikaru!
This is the central room. Looks like most of the matches are over.
What about a Furikawari here?
That might work.
Mark me down too.
This is your fourth straight win, Matsura!
Oh, there are kids younger than Hikaru. No wonder he passed.
There's a pairings sheet over there.
Okay, okay.
Oh! Hikaru! Let's look over there.
What?
What would you do if he played here?
This is bad for black.
What about a tsuke?
I'll just pull back.
That might be too soft...
Did you pass?
Yeah...
You came to take the Insei exam?
Waya do you know him?
Oh, I heard him say "To surpass Touya Akira" in the hall.
I used to say that too when I first joined.
You got a problem with that?
I played Touya twice during the pro exam, but I don't like him.
You played Touya?
What about you? Have you played him before?
Yeah, during a team match for my Go club.
He was in the Kaiou Jr. High Go club and...
Go club? Touya!? Really?
I remember hearing Mr. Kuwabara laugh about it with Mr. Nishio a while ago.
About the Meijin's son was participating in a tournament with his Jr. High Go club.
Oh so it's for real?
What? What are you talking about?
What an incredible first board match for a Go club match.
Between a soon-to-be Insei and Touya Akira.
Nope. It was a third board match.
Third board!?
I wasn't strong enough to play first board back then.
That may have been the case with you, but Touya? Third board? Impossible.
He forced the teacher to make him third board because he wanted to play against me.
Forced?
Like I said, that's the kind of guy he is.
The reason he joined the Go club was just to play against me...
Hikaru!
Hikaru, let's go home.
He'll start coming here starting next month. Nice to meet all of you.
Oh crap...
Touya Akira's what!?
Rival.
Rival?
Morning, what are you talking about?
Oh yeah, the guy coming today he might be really strong.
Touya Akira supposedly went to a Go club tournament pursuing him.
And he...
M-Morning.
Mo-rning.
Sai? Isn't everyone glaring at me?
They probably think a horrible strong enemy's arrived.
It's all because you talked about Touya, Hikaru.
But...
Did you hear? The guy coming today. Yeah! I heard my parents talking about it.
Touya Akira views him as a rival!
He's in the seventh grade.
I'm playing him for my first match today.
He's probably really strong...
Tsk... they were talking about me.
Umm... who's Uchida?
That's me.
We're playing here.
A girl!?
I got a pairing chart, but it only has last names.
She's fifth in the second class. I'm 25th. I'm starting at the very bottom.
Is this room just for the second class? Are there first class people here too?
They're all here, That half is the first class.
You can rise up to first class if you're strong enough?
Yeah.
So second class isn't good enough for you.
I-I don't feel that way at all!
It's not that second class isn't good enough for me...
But Touya is above first class, which is above second class.
I passed the Insei exam! I'm not like I was in the Go club anymore!
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
I totally read that part wrong! I'm such an idiot!
Oh yeah, I wonder if his game is wrong.
You can't get any eyes with this shape.
In this situation, if you cut them... you can get this area better.
This made black lose.
Looks like he lost.
How'd it go?
Uchida won.
The Second Match
I resign.
And he's Touya's...
Rival?
Moving into here, I think that was a little unreasonable.
Really?
Yeah, this happened, right? Even if you moved here...
Yeah, you'd get crushed.
It would be bad if it went like this.
There's nothing you can do.
Two straight losses...
Nothing to fear from here it seems.
Maybe he's just nervous since it's his first day?
Then wanna watch over him a little longer?
Waya, wanna go get lunch?
What are you doing for lunch?
I'm buying it too.
Obento: Launch box
Onigiri: Rice ball
Obento Onigiri
Thank you. Come again.
What's your relationship with Touya?
Were you his classmate in elementary school?
You said you played him in a match in a Go tournament for your club.
But why a school tournament?
Touya pursue you? That's strange.
You're not strong at all. Are you really rivals?
Really! I'm his, and he's my rival!
There's too much of a gap!
I'll catch up eventually!
What's the reason for Touya thinking of you as a rival?
He saw my incredible potential at Go, and that's why he views me as a rival!
Your potential at Go?
Hikaru, that was cool.
But... that's a lie.
That doesn't matter, I'll make it come true.
What? Something else you want to ask?
How was the match against Kaiou?
3-0 loss.
Touya is special, but everyone else in Kaiou is also strong.
I heard Kaiou's Go club is strong, but wow.
Kaiou's president's really strong.
I tried playing against him in a Go salon another day, but I totally lost.
That's not because he's strong, that's because you suck.
Waaahhh! I hit the wrong button!
Isumi-san! A coffee came out! You drink it Isumi-san!
Hey!
Drink it? But it's black!
I am the oldest... but black is...
Waya...
Don't want it.
I guess I'll give it to the teacher.
Oh! Black coffee, that reminds me.
Remember that guy that used to drink black coffee? In the seventh grade!
Yeah! He used to come here. What was his name?
What's a "black coffee" Hikaru?
It's really bitter.
What kind of a guy would drink black coffee in the seventh grade? Was he good at Go?
Not at all! He was here for a year, and then quit.
Was he always second class?
Nope. He rose up to first once. I remember playing him.
Oh yeah, I played him too. He wasn't any good.
I beat him too.
You've both been in the first class since back then?
Being in first class for a long time isn't something to be proud of.
When are we finally going to pass the pro exam, Waya?
I wonder what that guy that got pummeled in first class was doing now.
He was really smart!
Oh yeah, he went to Kaiou Jr. High. What was his name?
He was tall and wore glasses...
He should be in the ninth grade right now...
Now I remember! It's Kishimoto! Kishimoto!
Back then it was...
He didn't look like a Jr. High student.
Yeah, yeah, and...
And those glasses...
He's no good...
It was total domination.
Really?
But he doesn't look like a Jr. High student.
Well, let's get going.
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah, that strong first board from Kaiou you were talking about. What's his name?
Hey!
Kaiou's first board was... Kishimoto was... always second class...
I... I... will I ever be able to make it to first class?
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Sagamihara Kamimizo-South Municipal Middle School
Today, we're at Hamimizo-South Middle School in Sagamihara City.
Yukari Sensei begins playing against five students at once.
I also played against someone on a 9x9 board.
Have I become stronger than before?
Sensei offered advice after the game were over.
Most of the children have been playing less than a year,
but they surprised me because they were so strong.
There might be a second or even a third Hikaru!
I hope you'll all continue to enjoy playing Go!
Thank you to everyone in the Kamimizo-South Middle School Go and Shougi club!
To be continued
He came to see if I was here.
He said he'll never appear before me again...
He's waiting for me...
To chase after me with his skills?
That's funny.
Then, I'll move forward far beyond him, so that he'll never reach me.