この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Touya says he's going to recognize me as a rival, if I beat you in the last match today.
Then if I beat you, Touya will recognize me as a rival, right!?
Isn't that right, Touya?
I won't lose.
I won't lose!
Touya is standing behind me!
Is there anyone standing behind you, Shindou?
If I win this match today, I'll become a pro!
I'm going to stand before you...
Touya...
Stand before you...
I'm going to keep attacking until I crush you!
There!
Forty-sixth match
The Last Day of the Pro Exam Finals
We're from the Japanese Go Institute's publishing division!
Hello.
We came to interview and take pictures of those who passed.
Those who passed?
One person has already passed, but the other two spots may or may not be filled today.
I saw that.
I've looked at the win loss record up to now.
You might have a three-way playoff, right?
Well, it will be a while still, so come on in and have some tea.
Thanks.
There!
I'll...
I'll attack...
Wait!
N-No!
When did Shindou's stones...!?
Hikaru didn't miss the slight weakness...
that Ochi failed to notice.
Hikaru made his stones in the lower right live.
He has gained back the lead that Ochi had.
The game is completely even now.
Touya...
This is Hikaru's strength right now.
The Hikaru you played two years ago,
that was me.
You are looking at both of us inside Hikaru.
You must want to ask the question...
'Exactly who are you?'
I am Sai.
Sai of the Fujiwara.
But it is Hikaru who will answer your question.
Hikaru, who keeps growing stronger by absorbing me.
Touya, the person you will eventually meet.
is not me, but Hikaru.
Wow, I still have a lot to learn.
Not at all, your play was very good.
Thanks for the game.
Oh yes, about your father's successful defense of the Meijin title...
Congratulations!
I hope you do just as well as your father. I will be cheering you on.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you very much for the game today.
Oh, Touya-kun!
The reporter...
It's Amano. Do you have some time? I'd like to do an interview.
You're still on your winning streak, right?
Is it around twenty, as of right now?
The greatest winning streaks so far have been,
Kurata-kun's twenty-five win streak, and master Kuwabara's twenty-seven win streak.
It would be incredible if a new player were to break that record!
Have you ever thought about it?
No.
Do you have any ambitions, like to surpass your father?
Or to become the top player in the world?
Touya-kun.
The thing is, we're thinking about picking you up for the monthly magazine.
The plan was to do it with you and Touya Meijin, a father and son thing.
But we thought you could do it on your own.
Well, there are a few who think it's still too early.
But it would be kind of like, 'the player of the 21st century.'
I'd like to hear some motivating stories, that would help the rest of your generation along.
Do you have time for dinner after your tutoring games tonight?
I have somewhere to go to after this so...
I'll be done here at 7:40.
I won't get to Ochi's house until late...
Well, umm, another time maybe.
Sorry for bothering you during your break.
Oh, It's okay.
Oh wow, it's this late already?
I guess I'll call the Research Center.
The results from the Pro Exam might be in.
W-Wait! Please!
U-Umm, may I hear the results too!?
Two matches left...
And what important matches they are.
Two boys at three losses each...
I wonder how that boy who's still at four losses feels,
waiting for their results.
His chances of passing or not, depends on the results of these matches.
Rain?
Waya won.
Waya is the second one to pass.
Those that win will rise.
That is something everyone in the Go world knows.
We all laughed and worked together knowing that.
Only three can become pros.
Only Shindou's game against Ochi is left.
If Shindou loses, he'll have a playoff match against me, at four losses.
It's over.
Who won!?
No one...
is coming...
If...
If Shindou has lost... he'll have a playoff match against me.
Wouldn't someone come tell me...
That there's going to be a playoff?
Shindou... must have won.
Kousuke! How long are you going to be like this.
I can understand that you're upset about losing to that Shindou boy today.
But, it doesn't change the fact that you passed with the top score.
You can get even with Shindou-kun when you play him as a pro.
More importantly, about the celebration for your passing...
You don't have to get that.
It's probably Touya.
No, it's okay. I'll get it.
Yes?
It's Touya.
Oh, hello. I believe yesterday was the last day you were supposed to be tutoring.
Did you come to find out how Kousuke did today?
No. I heard the results at the institute.
Then why are you here?
I'm sorry for not coming earlier.
But, I came to ask you to show me that match.
He says he doesn't want to show you a game he lost.
Oh.
I see. I will be going then.
Really. You can be so difficult sometimes.
One and a half moku...
This one and a half moku is big.
It shows Shindou-kun's determination.
I can see why Ochi-kun made beating Shindou-kun his goal.
Ochi-kun played well too, but...
Shindou is coming.
He will appear before me soon.
With the answer to,
the mystery behind you.
I will just have to see for myself.
Come, Shindou!
I am right here...
In the world of the pros!
Student Guidance Office
Congratulations!
I heard about it from Shindou-kun this morning.
Thank you.
I hear he found out that he passed on Saturday.
But to be honest, I'm really surprised.
I can't believe that Shindou-kun is going to become a pro Go player.
Though I probably shouldn't say that, since I'm his homeroom teacher.
My husband and I feel the same way.
We have no idea what's going on.
It's just... we've suddenly become really worried.
He's going to miss a lot more days of school right?
I'm not sure.
He's going to make some money too, right?
Pardon me for asking, but how much?
I still have no idea about that.
We're just worried that his schooling and social life may be effected.
We're really worried about him.
I see.
And there is the matter about high school.
There's a boy named Waya-kun who passed with him.
He's a year older than Hikaru and in the 9th grade.
And he says he's not going to high school.
Is Shindou-kun not going to go to high school?
He hasn't said anything about it yet.
He says it's still a whole year away.
He's allowed to go, right?
Well...
I suppose he has made it out into the world.
Though it might not be the normal world.
You're absolutely right.
Anyways, I'd like to meet Waya-kun's parents.
and talk to them about all of this.
I see.
When I asked Hikaru, he yelled at me, saying,
'Mind your own business'. But he is my business.
Yes, yes.
He doesn't know that I came to meet you either.
Well, but...
He won't become a pro until later... not until Spring, right?
Please feel free to come talk to me again when you find out more.
Yes I will. Thank you.
I hear...
that you're a pro now.
Yeah...
Well, good luck with that.
I wonder if the Go club is meeting today.
I'm sure they are.
It's Akari-chan!
It's still going on...
The Go club that Tsutsui-san made.
Well, let's start.
I hear Shindou-kun passed the pro exam?
Yup! Hikaru said that he passed when I asked him.
Shindou is the old Go club member who became an Insei, right?
Wow!
Hikaru should have dropped by.
All of us would have celebrated it with him.
Hikaru...
It's okay...
But, I don't really understand exactly how incredible that is.
Me neither!
Maybe I'll get him a gift,
to celebrate his passing.
Hello!
I'm here again!
Kaneko-san! You came again!? That's great!
What about the volleyball team?
It's fine. I'll be coming to the Go club for awhile.
We lost in the first round that last time we went to a team tournament.
I want to make it to the second round for the winter tournament.
Yay! Kaneko-san is getting serious about Go!
We'll all have to work all the harder now!
I wonder if Mitani-kun will come today.
Senpai, I want to go to a tournament too.
Why didn't you just write Mitani-kun's name down when signing up for the tournament?
We can't do that!
He said he didn't want to.
I'm sure it'll turn out okay.
Natsume-kun, you're the club president, so you have to be more forceful about it.
She's right, senpai.
You too, Koike-kun?
What's all the fuss about?
M-Mitani senpai!
N-Nothing!
There you are, first board.
First board?
First board for the guys' team tournament.
W-What are you talking about!? What do you mean, 'first board'!?
Calm down.
Hey, Kaneko.
Let's play a game!
What?
Don't decide things for me!
Did I bring Mitani-kun's notebook today? We need his notebook.
Shindou!
I heard from someone in your class,
that you're becoming a pro Go player?
Yeah.
Then our Go club must be really good!
You can win any tournament you go to, right?
I can't go, even if I wanted to!
Oh... Really?
Aww man, being a pro sure sucks.
I've finally made it there.
Hey!
Touya has been there since last year.
I've finally made it to Touya's world.
Touya! To your world!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Let's do another problem today!
Okay!
You can still play something in this white territory.
It's black's turn.
Mai-chan, try it.
Here.
I connect because it's atari.
Here!
If I play here?
It doesn't work.
You can't take anything.
Try it Yuuki-kun.
I connect because it's atari.
I connect agajn because it's atari.
Yup. White can't get away from this.
Yes!
Good job! That's right.
There can be problems even if it looks like territory,
so learn to tell them apart.
To be continued...
Okay!
We're in the same world now!
He'll be playing me some day!
'Me'...
I am connected!
To Touya, and to Touya's dad...
Hikaru... I...
Is Hukaru not going to let me play any more?