Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Seventh match
I Won't Play Against You
Public Haze Junior High School
Spring came, and I entered Haze Jr. High.
Hey have you decided on a club to join?
Nope, not yet.
There were a lot of posters from clubs on the bulletin board in the hall.
Let's go and take a look at it later.
Men's
Volleyball
Club
Come to
Baseball Club!
...League
Drama Club
new students
welcome
...recruiting
club
Orchestr...
Which one are you going to join?
Women's
Volleyball
Club
Go Club Recruiting Members!
Contact Tsutsui in 3-2
Men's
Volleyball
Club
Recruiting new members!
club
Come to the Tea Ceremony Club!
...recruiting
Hmm... I dunno...
Let's put ours up here.
Yeah, the board near the main entrance is the best.
Yup
What is this?
Go club Recruiting Members!
Contact Tsutsui in 3-2
Go club?
Did we have something like that?
They took up so much space!
Take it off, take it off.
What do you think you're doing you bastards!?
What?
What did you do to the Go club poster!
Take this!
Keep away!
Stop it! Isn't that the mop for the bathroom!?
Take this! and this! and this!
Hikaru!
Shindou-kun!
What happened Shindou-kun?
These guys ripped our poster!
Men's Basketball
...tournament
...champion!
No one's gonna join your Go club.
And you haven't even been recognized as a club yet!
Don't take up space on the bulletin boards!
With great power comes greater privilege.
Our basketball teams strong so it only makes sense.
Kaga...
Seems like the Go clubs having a tough time...
Compared to that the Shougi clubs great.
Well, if you ever get tired of the Go club, you can join the Shougi club anytime.
So anyways...
Good luck establishing your Go club!
Man I'm angry.
It's only a poster.
We can make another one.
But Tsutsui-san... no one'll see it if we put it up here.
Oh well... but I have good news too.
Ms. Tamako, the chemistry teacher gave a Go board and some stones.
And if it's available after school, we can use the chemistry lab too.
Then we're like a real club now!
We've got to get new members.
We have to get the school to recognize us as a real club this time.
Okay. What do you want me to do then Tsutsui-san?
Putting up posters? Handing out flyers? Or drag someone into the club?
AH! Sounds like fun! I'm gonna go too!
Why are you going to go?
'Cause it sounds like fun!
What about Kaga? He's not gonna do anything with the club anymore?
Yeah... he's gonna stick with Shougi.
He's not gonna come here...
Oh...
Shinagawa 50
Sa 41-41
Thanks Ichikawa-san.
Anything for you Akira-kun.
But what do you need to do at Haze Junior High?
If you're going to be done in a few minutes, I'll wait for you.
That's okay. I'll go home by bus.
Oh? Okay...
Huh? That's a uniform from Kaiou.
Why's he here?
Umm...
I'm searching for someone called Shindou Hikaru in the first year.
I was told that he joined the Go club.
Could you possibly tell me where the Go club is?
Go club? I've never heard of a Go club...
I think I saw something about it on the bulletin board.
Really?
I think I saw it there...
Thank you.
Go club? We have a Shougi club.
You know about it?
Nope.
Oh...
Do you know about it?
Nope.
Umm... excuse me.
Yes?
Oh, a student from Kaiou? What are you looking for?
I'm looking for the Go club... but I'm having trouble finding it.
Do you really have one?
Go club? Oh! them!
They should be playing in the chemistry lab right now.
Using a Go board that once belonged to my father. It doesn't have any ashi left, and the stones are a little beat up.
Ashi are legs on a Go board. In Japan Go boards have legs. Although Ashi literally means "legs" they are also a type of flower. Their presence on the Go board is there to remind the spectators to be as silent as the Ashi flower during the game.
Chem... lab?
If you go around there, you'll be able to see the chemistry lab windows, so you can look in on them.
If you want to go in, there's an entrance on the right...
...aci
Metha...
Salt...
Manganese
Dioxide
We were disqualified from that last tournament... but that last word that the head steward said was great wasn't it?
Stewards are the tournament officials present at chess tournaments to decide upon certain issues. Therefore, I decided to use steward instead of referee.
Yeah.
I'm looking forward to Haze's entry next year.
Are you talking about the one where Hikaru entered pretending to be a Junior High student?
Is Hikaru really that strong?
Be quiet.
Well... I'm not sure about that either.
When he's in a bind, he brings out incredible strength but...
If we're playing normally, he still loses to me.
Oh, so he isn't that good after all.
Look he lost again!
Akari go home already!
I messed up because you kept talking right next to me!
What!? Are you blaming me for your loss!
Well it is your fault!
Shindou!
Touya...
Why are you here?
Shindou... why is someone like you in the school Go club?
Are you not coming to the Go salon anymore?
I'm usually there.
No matter who I play with, I'm constantly thinking about you...
How you would respond to each of my moves.
I've become stronger since then so that I won't be embarrassed by you again.
I'm waiting for you.
I came to say that.
I'm not gonna play against you.
Wait!? Why!?
I'm gonna work with Tsutsui-san in the Go club. Right Tsutsui-san?
And we're entering the tournament again.
You won't play with me...
Shindou!
Hikaru...
I'll make him wait... until I catch up to him.
Why? Why won't you play me?
There's no way you could fear me. I should be the one fearing you.
I'm gonna work in the Go club, and we're entering the tournament again.
Shindou Hikaru, if that is your intention, I'll...
Did you here?
Yup. Touya Akira's gonna enter our club.
Really?
Isn't he as strong as a pro? Why enter a school club?
This sucks.
He's definitely gonna take a tournament spot.
What about team matches? Touya's gonna be the captain?
No way!
What about the president Kishimoto-san?
The third year student won't keep quiet about this.
Yeah. I heard the president said to Touya. "If you enter the club, it'll motivate everyone in the club."
You've got to be kidding.
Don't think too long. Thinking longer is useless when you're just bad.
Okay.
Yamada, answer tsumego instantly! Don't spend more than 10 seconds on any one!
Yes, sorry.
The atmosphere today sucks... everyone's so tense...
Shh! Quiet!
That guys still not here?
He doesn't think high enough of us.
You there, quiet!
S-Sorry.
Stop it Nakai, it's embarrassing, as if we were actually bothered by this.
I know.
Touya...
I'm sorry I'm late. I had some things to do in class.
That's okay, I heard from your teacher.
Seems everyone's here now.
Everyone, please pause your games for a second, I'll introduce all the new members this year.
New students please come to the front.
How is it? Is it okay? It's not crooked right?
Yeah looks okay.
Who asked you?
But I helped you color it in!
Move into your youth!
Go is the universe!
Join us new members
People who wish to join us
should contact Tsutsui in 3-2
I'll draw a lot more attention than before now, right Tsutsui-san?
Yeah.
See!
Let's go back to the chemistry lab now and play a few games Shindou-kun.
Yeah.
Me too!
We have 17 new members this year.
Let's all work hard together towards the tournament in June.
Good luck everyone.
Nice to meet you.
Please return to your seats now and continue your games.
Yes.
I'm having all the new members play each other to see how strong they are. Let's see, you can play...
Teacher, I'll play him.
Miwa... yeah...
Wait, I'll play.
Touya this way.
Oh well.
What happened?
The teacher wanted me to avoid an embarrassment.
It's not good when a 3rd year student is easily defeated by a freshman.
I'll take white.
Yes, please.
You're Touya-Meijin's son?
Yes.
I'm looking forward to seeing how strong you are.
Hikaru! You can place the stones properly now!
Still no new members.
I wonder if we can get enough people by the time of the tournament in June...
I'll try asking a bunch of smart people.
How smart they are doesn't matter.
But it seems like stupid people can't learn how to play Go.
Yup, yup.
Then why does Shindou-kun know how to play?
Oh yeah!
Why are you agreeing with him!?
Damn it.
But Kaiou Junior High is an elite school, and there Go club's strong too isn't it?
But there are pros who had really bad grades in school.
Like all D's and F's.
Really?
Then maybe Hikaru can become pro someday too!
Hey!
But now I feel like I can do it too.
No! No! You can't do it!
Come on Hikaru, teach her!
But...
If you can do it, so can I!
Right, Tsutsui-san?
Yes.
Fujiwaki-san why don't you join, I would not mind at all.
So just teach me a little, Hikaru.
Oh man...
Look you're white.
If black moves here, then this white stone is captured.
Okay, I took back that move.
It's your turn, what should you do to prevent the white stone from getting captured?
I'd run away like this!
Are you messing with me!?
You can't do that! It's impossible!
What!? Who are you to talk!
Calm down Shindou-kun!
I taught children in Korea how to play Go, while teaching at school.
I was lucky enough to come to Japan, and I decided to teach Go over here as well.
When I first came here, I was really disappointed...
The children in Japan aren't very good at Go.
Go is really popular in Korea compared to here.
Yes.
In Korea, there are Go schools the way there are cram schools over here, and everyone learns well.
But last year, when I transferred here, I changed my mind.
The children here are just as strong as those in Korea.
But... there are always those who are stronger.
Um... ahhh...
Shindou Hikaru from Haze Junior High...
He appeared in the winter tournament this year as a member for Haze Junior High.
Our team from then has all graduated already, but I still remember.
I was there as well.
Shindou Hikaru!
I'm gonna work hard in the Go club, I'm going to the tournament.
But... you may be able to defeat him.
That is my intention.
Let's stop here. I know your strength now.
This clubs centered around inter-league matches, divided by strength, but there are those who look at kifu and try to solve tsumego.
I give a lecture every now and then, Fridays we discuss "the next move".
You're free to participate or not.
If you're going to participate in the league matches you'll probably be in division A,  but you're free to join whichever division you want.
Umm, teacher...
We'd like Akira-kun to play us in a game of tutoring Go.
You guys, Touya is...
I don't mind.
Hold on a second!
You guys can't ask him for tutoring before any 3rd year students have a chance.
Senpai...
I'll play you some other time Senpai.
They asked first today.
Yes!
The sakura hasn't changed at all in the last thousand years...
how peaceful...
I'll be waiting... Touya!
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Let's play a game of capturing stones.
You go first, Yuki.
Yuki captures a stone!!
But... Mai...
I don't have a move!
You're right... That is a problem.
And Yuki?
Yuki is... also unable to make a move.
I can't move anywhere.
You can't, can you?
When both players have created areas...
where neither can capture stones or be captured,
we call these areas "territory".
In a real game of Go, the size of the territory determines which player wins.
The size of Black's territory,
the size of White's territory,
and the number of capture stones are very important.
We'll continue next week
That guy's replaying games alone.
I guess it's a waste of his time to play against us.
After all he is the son of Touya Meijin, the holder of 4 titles.
What are you plotting?
A way to win against Touya Akira.
Anyways... no matter what we do... we'll win against Touya Akira...