Fujiwarano Sai, the Go player who lived during the Heian period,
has revisited this world through Shindou Hikaru.
He returned to this world to make the move of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
What? He lost?
Akira-kun lost, did you say?
Second match
The Weakpoint Revealed!!
Hello.
Hi, Akari-chan.
Is Hikaru-kun at home?
Well, he's started to go to Go class.
Go?
Yeah, I don't know why he suddenly started it.
Hikaru is playing Go?
Okay, let's start with this problem right here.
In this situation, black should place a stone underneath this one.
Then, even if white holds the two black stones,
black tries to capture these two stones, forcing white to capture his stones.
Then breaking the eye on the left would kill the white formation.
I don't get any of what they're talking about!
Well, that's because you are a beginner.
Now, let's see what happens if we go to break the eye first.
19-16!
That's right.
If we place white here, then the white formation would live.
Do you know how strong the person who's teaching is?
I know that he's a pro.
Pro?
That means he makes his living playing Go.
Let's cut the lecture off around here and get to playing the game.
Good luck.
Um...
So, you are Shindou-kun, right?
Uh, yes.
Is it your first time?
I've played once before, but that doesn't count because I was sort of watching the game.
Why don't we start with "capture" game then.
Oh, I know this!
If white goes here, black gets taken, right?
Yes, that's right.
When you only need one more move to capture a stone, we call it atari.
Ok, what about the next one?
Atari. Ok, Shindou-kun, try playing it black.
Um...
See, atari again.
Atari.
Atari again.
Ok, thanks for the meal!
Oh, hey!
This shape is called shichou, it's one of the shapes that you can't get away from.
You will see this quite often when you are playing,
so why don't you watch others while keeping this in mind.
Oh no...
Hikaru, are you going home already?
I need a break.
Oh!
What is this?
It's a vending machine. You can get drinks by putting money into it.
Hmm... oh...
Oh no, I'm running late again.
Oh, Hikaru-kun...
Did you start playing Go, too?
Well, yeah, kind of.
I have a friend who plays Go.
I play with him sometime, but see, I don't know anything about Go...
So I came here to try to learn some of the basics, but I still don't understand it!
And you're hanging around here.
Oh, hey, this is the TV broadcast of the Tengen-match.
Hikaru, what is that? There are people playing Go in the box?
Hmm... he's pausing to think...
What would he be thinking right here...
Um... what would that be?
Well, with Touya Meijin,
he's constantly thinking of ways to improve the status-quo even during the opening game.
Some way that we can't see.
Yeah, that's right.
He's said to be the closest to obtaining the hand of god!
Hand of god?
I'm kind of his fan.
This man... is not an ordinary player.
He's also like me, trying to make 'God's move'.
Oh, and it's known that Touya Meijin has a son who is also trying to become a pro.
Yes, I heard that he's pretty good.
Oba-san, don't you need to go to the class?
Oh, yeah that's right!
Shirakawa-sensei is also cute!
Welcome.
Is Akira-sensei here?
I was wondering if I could play a match with him.
Well, he's here, but...
he hasn't played anyone since last week.
He's been looking over at the game he lost last week over and over.
Oh, you mean the game where he lost to another boy his age by 2 moku?
I'm going home.
Um... ok. Be careful on the way.
Hey, Akira-kun, you were still here?
You better go home before it's late... your mother will worry...
What's wrong with him?
Well, he's a little...
That move, and that move...
it was a tutoring match.
If that's his real talent...
No, it can't be.
There can't possibly be a child like that.
I don't understand it...
Who the hell is he?
Ok, class is over.
Don't forget to do your homework!
Good bye.
Be careful on your way home, everyone.
Oh, Shindou-kun.
You've been phasing out a lot,
but your social studies grades have been very good.
Have you hired a tutor or something?
Well, something like that...
but he's a little annoying sometimes.
Well, keep it up!
Yeah, I will, bye.
Be careful on the way home.
I will!
Hikaru!
Hikaru, what's wrong with you these days?
You aren't doing well in PE class,
and you actually do your correction for the social studies test.
Is there anything wrong with my doing the corrections?
I don't mean that, but...
Hey do you want to go out tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
Well, I need to do something for a friend.
You mean Go class?
What, you know?
Y..yeah.
Do you wanna come, too?
Well... I'm a little...
Go class
Nice to meet you.
Sorry, she said she really wanted to come and watch.
Oh, that's fine with me...
It's nice to know people are getting interested in Go.
Recently it's been popular to place the first move on the star point, but komoku is probably still the safest.
Komoku is an opening move in Go where you place your stone under a star point, it captures less territory, but is a great deal safer.
If you follow it up with a keima, then it's like you've captured an entire corner already.
A keima is a move in Go similar to a knight's move in chess. Where you go 2 units in one direction, and another unit in a different direction.
Hikaru, do you get what he's talking about?
No way.
But in an actual game, it won't always turn out the way you want it to.
Ok, now, let's say white places his next move here.
What should black do?
Oh, I know!
Shindou-kun?
Tell me where would you put black?
16-5.
16-5. Underneath the star point.
16-5. You mean right here?
I thought you were a beginner?
Oh, was I wrong? Sorry.
No...
It's a very good move!
Whoa?
Nowadays we don't see this as much, but in the past it was quite popular to make this move.
Oh, ok.
Oh, you can sit down.
Yes.
Am... why isn't that move seen anymore?
It's because of the komi rule.
Komi?
Since black makes the first move, he's got the advantage, so white gets 5 and a half moku to start with.
In other words, if white has 50 moku on the board, black has to have 56 moku all together to win.
I see... 5 and a half moku.
What do you mean "I see". Didn't you know?
There was no such rule during Shuusaku's time.
Didn't you think that black seemed to have the advantage every time?
I've never lost before when I've taken black.
Hmm... this guy...
I see...
Komi rule, with 5 and a half extra points...
After this rule was introduced, some people said that this move was not as good...
so that's why not many people make this move anymore.
But we cannot deny that it is a very good move.
If you think Shindou-kun has an odd number of stones, then put one stone on the board,
but if you think he has an even number of stones, then put two stones on the board.
Ok, how many have you got, Shindou-kun?
2, 4, 6, 8, 9, it's an odd number.
I got it right.
Ok, then you are black.
If you are playing against a person at about the same level, we use this method to decide who goes first.
Um...
There is a game played by pros in this book.
Why don't you recreate their game and kinda get the hang of the game.
I'll be back later.
Hmm...
Hey, Hikaru, do you understand it?
I guess all we need to do is to put stones on the board, following the numbers.
See, Akari, the first move is this one.
Where?
Here, this one.
Okay! There's six more stones I've captured!
I guess you like getting all your stones taken or something!
Akoda-san is bullying those who can't play well again!
How annoying!
Oh my, why do you make such stupid moves?
People who enjoy losing are rather rare you know.
A wig?
I can't stand him anymore! Hikaru, play against him instead of that man!
That guy hasn't made a single correct move!
Sai...
Every move he's made is there to confuse the weaker player! I can't stand it!
I will play instead of that man who can't even fight back.
I will make him swallow the grief that comes from making futile moves,
and say to him at the end of the game...
Oh, I'm sorry.
What do you think you're doing, you little brat?
You've ruined the whole game!
Sorry, my hands slipped.
Don't worry I'll take it off now!
What?
No, stop, stop it!
Shindou-kun, you may go home, now!
I came with you and THIS is what you do!?
I didn't ask you to!
Go to hell!
You've made the teacher angry, now we can't play Go!!
19th National Children's Go Tournament
Oh yeah, there's a tournament next week...
I will take you to this. Is that ok?
Hikaru~~~~~
Japanese National Institute of Go
What's with this atmosphere?
Some of these kids are younger then me.
Are they parents and family?
Sai, it's amazing, isn't it?
Yes. It's amazing!
There are lots of kids.
Their passion towards the game is the same as my passion from 1000 years ago.
They show me...
that it is the same even after 1000 years.
Oh, maybe that guy is here.
Akira-kun, Mr. Hirose is here to ask you whether you can play a tutoring match with him.
I'm sorry, but...
Are you waiting for him?
It's difficult to find him with this crowd.
The battle on the upper-left corner...
You mean this?
Black is going to lose, if he doesn't make the right move.
Hm...
1-2 is the key point.
Oh, close! You should've gone above it!
What?
Ooops!!!
You!
What do you think you're doing?
You're disturbing the game!
I..I'm sorry.
No need to yell.
Mr. Ogata. Well, I will take him to the back.
Ok.
Here, come with me.
Ok, everyone, continue the game.
And... could you tell me what happened?
I put it at 1-3 and he said "you should have put it one above it."
That...
Oh yeah, that's right!
I gave him the pamphlet on the National Children's Go Tournament.
Oh, is it at the Kiin today?
Yes. He didn't seem too interested, but he might be...
Akira-kun.
If he comes here, could you hold him until I come back?
He's changed...
Well... he didn't have any rivals.
See, what you did was serious. You can't just say "my tongue slipped."
Y..yes.
And what happened?
Well, we decided to cancel the match and have them replay.
Oh well, I guess that's the only way.
You can go home now.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
Well... well... and what did the game look like?
Umm... your change!
I shouldn't have said anything... huh?
I feel sorry for them.
Be careful.
This man...
the one we saw last time on TV, the one who's closest to the hand of god.
I heard that there was trouble.
Oh, Mr. Touya.
Well, please look at this.
A mere child commented on this situation...
a situation that even us pros would take a moment to think about.
I see.
He found the key point for black to live...
I didn't know a child other than my son could do this.
And you didn't even ask for his name?
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
If he's really that strong, sooner or later he will come before us.
Anyways, it's all your fault, Sai!
What you wanna fight? If you act like that I won't play Go anymore!
Shindou!
Touya...
I found you...
I finally found you...
Shindou Hikaru.
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
What will Yokari sensei teach us today?
Let's start by playing a game of capturing stones.
The rule in Go is:
you can take an opponent's stone if you surround them.
Yuki, you try to surround Mai's stones, and Mai, you try to surround Yuki's stones.
Yes, you've both surrounded each other's stones.
But this is correct.
Even without these stones here, you can surround this stone.
You only need to place your stones where there is a "liberty".
You can now capture this stone.
Now let's see who can capture the other's stones first.
You first, Yuki.
To be continued
Oh...
so you were the one that beat Akira...
Place three stones,
that's what I play Akira at.
Me? Pro?
I've never even thought about anything like that.
Someone who plays Go can't possibly say something that insulting!