この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
I'm sure I want to play him in an even game.
Yes.
I wonder if I can make it happen...
'I wonder'!?
But Hikaru!
I'll make it happen someday. Be patient.
When is this 'someday'?
'Someday' is 'someday'.
Besides, it was an important match for me, too!
And I couldn't play it because of your selfishness, don't you get that?
Umm...
I'm sorry...
Man, it was your fault for coming to me.
Torajirou...
He was very clever...
and truly kind person.
So what you're saying is that I'm stupid and unkind.
Hikaru...
Fiftieth match
Sai of the Fujiwara
Why did god...
revive me in Hikaru's mind?
It's true
Hikaru is growing very quickly,
and it brings me both pride and joy in teaching him...
But,
what about...
What about my Go?
I hate this existence.
The chance to play him finally came...
The game against him when I was supposed to master the divine move...
But...
I couldn't do it.
In a game that I couldn't play as myself,
I couldn't head for that divine height with him.
If I cannot master the divine move...
Why am I here?
How long am I supposed to wait?
A thousand years ago...
Everything began from there.
Every day...
I played Go within the palace.
But...
When I played the other tutor that His Majesty had,
In a match to decide who would become the only tutor for His Majesty...
He placed a white stone that was hidden among his stones,
In his Agehama during a moment when everyone was distracted.
When I tried to raise my voice...
You...
just...
Hey!
You! You just placed a black stone from your Goke into your Agehama!
W-What?
That is what you just did!
What a stupid excuse that is.
You just placed a black stone that was hidden in your Goke into your Agehama when everyone's attention was on the board!
You are the one making excuses!
Stop it. Quiet.
I do not wish to even consider that such a dishonest act has occurred before me.
Continue.
I lost.
I could not contain my anger.
I was charged with cheating during the game
and driven out of the capital.
I no longer had a reason to live.
Two days after the match...
I drowned myself.
But...
I wanted to play Go a lot more.
My soul, unable to find peace,
possessed a Go board,
and after a long period of time
heard a voice of a young boy
on Innoshima, within the Sea of Seto.
He was...
Torajirou.
Young boy,
If you can see the tears of grief that I shed,
let me dwell in a corner of your mind.
I was able to play Go as much as I wished, together with him.
He changed his name to Shuusaku, and became the successor to the Honinbou.
I believed that I would be able to master the divine move together with him.
But...
he could not defeat disease and...
Torajirou...
Honinbou Shuusaku...
I will never forget the time that I spent with him...
Never...
Sai...
So that's how you want to play it...
Yes...
and then you appeared before me.
This stain just won't come off.
There's no stain. It's clean.
This.
Where?
Here!
There's nothing. Where!?
Can you see it?
That's what I've been saying...
Can you hear a voice!?
You can hear my voice, can't you?
There's nothing...
Who are you!?
The gods before me...
I thank you.
Now I can...
I can...
I can return to the present world,
once more.
But...
I was concerned at first.
After all, Hikaru, you had never played Go before.
You like Go that much?
Yes!
You still want to play Go?
Too bad, I have no intentions of playing Go.
Hikaru!
Shindou-kun!
Say, can't you possess someone other than me?
Probably not...
Fine, I guess it would be okay to play once in a while.
And!? And!?
Where are we playing?
In a Go salon.
Wow, It's filled with old men.
Oh there's another kid.
Can I play him?
Umm, yeah... but he's...
Looking for someone to play?
This was how I met Touya Akira.
Yeah.
Okay, I'll play you.
I believed that this was the destiny that God gave me.
Yes...
The wheels of destiny began to turn.
Okay!
17-4, Komoku on the upper right-hand corner.
17 and...
one...
one... two...
one... two... three...
one... two... three... four...
He holds the stone like a beginner.
I think I played him around three times,
through Hikaru's body.
16-17, Komoku on the lower right-hand corner.
16-17... here it is.
3-16.
3-16...
8-5.
Let's see... 8... There it is!
This...
This isn't the best move...
nor is it the strongest move.
He made this move to see how I would respond.
He's testing to see how strong I am...
from far above me...
Touya Akira had great potential,
despite the fact that he was the same age as Hikaru.
So...
Go on.
Yeah...
Wow, he doesn't even notice the crowd.
That's why I...
He's waiting for my Kosumi, isn't he?
I suppose there's nothing wrong with that.
15-16
Kosumi!
Come, let's see what you have in mind!
I resign!
Sai...
He resigned.
He declared his own defeat.
He faced up to me despite his fear.
Our third match was a match over the 'internet'.
He's strong.
I feel a wall higher than when Shindou defeated me.
He's...
He's... not Shindou?
Could it be!?
The black in the center has...
no chance of living.
He resigned...
Sai, how was it? Was it Touya?
Without a doubt.
Oh.
And? What did you think?
Sai?
Yes...
he was very strong.
He had great instincts.
He thought during all the important moves.
And? Did Touya get any stronger?
I was the one that became stronger.
And Hikaru, you, too.
Me?
You watched dozens of my games, after all.
Yes.
Together with Hikaru,
I learned modern Go.
Through playing Touya Akira,
Touya Akira began to chase after me,
and Hikaru began to chase Touya.
Oh yes, I forgot about that match.
When I was playing Touya Akira during Hikaru's match in the Go tournament...
Touya...
how far...
have I caught up to you?
I want to play...
Touya...
Just like you're chasing after Sai, I'm chasing you.
I'll catch up to you some day.
13-4
I'll go to 11-8, and then...
Hikaru. 13...
I want to find out.
Sorry, Sai...
I can't tell without playing him myself.
I want to find out the gap between him and me.
11-8!?
I'm playing!
Now that I think about it,
that was when I first realized how interesting Hikaru's ideas were.
You must have been mortified then.
Stop messing around!
T-Touya...
I'm going to catch up to you someday, if you keep chasing after my illusion!
You?
Would you like to play now instead of 'someday'?
Ever since then, Hikaru has...
run straight towards Touya Akira.
He became an Insei to chase after Touya,
and he passed the pro exam.
He really has become strong.
Hikaru...
Your name!
Your name! I said I'd remember it.
Shindou Hikaru!
My name is...
But...
Now that I think about it,
that was around when I stopped playing Go against people other than Hikaru.
And to think, I have more opportunities to play stronger players now.
Hikaru...
Hikaru, do you not intend to let me play anymore?
Even though I'm closest to mastering the divine move?
Oh, God! Why did I come back in the mind of Hikaru!?
God...
So there is no answer after all...
Hikaru!
Wake up!
Hurry and wake up!
What is it? Why are you being so loud this early in the morning?
Wake up and play me!
I haven't even eaten breakfast yet,
I don't want to.
No 'I don't want to's.
We have to play to come closer to mastering the divine move.
Hikaru you're the only person I can play.
What's wrong Sai?
You're acting weird.
Not at all. It's just the conclusion I came to.
Come on, hurry! Hurry!
Let me sleep for just another half hour.
No!
Hikaru! Hey! Hikaru! Wake up!
Good night.
Let's play, Hikaru!
Hikaru!
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
We're continuing with Yose today.
When there are two Yose spots left, how would you play, Yuki-kun?
Here.
You got to play both spots.
If you play here first...
You can only get one of the spots.
You lost three moku compared to earlier.
We call places like this,
where white has to respond to black, Sente.
And, we call a place where your opponent doesn't have to respond to, Gote.
The key to "Yose" is to play the Sente spots first.
To be continued...
How dare you slander Torajurou's name with a fake signature!
You said all that, why don't you try?
It's impossible to turn a game around once you're at a disadvantage to a pro.
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
14-4, approach by one space.